Kenzo: her interest.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: You know? Maybe, uh- Another, another angle is to
Seeker: offer information in exchange for information.
Unknown: Well, what can we offer her? What do we think she wants?
Seeker: Well, we know some facts about Ra'ghemdros now
Seeker: that she might not know.
Kenzo: How old is Ra'ghemdros?
Kenzo: We don't know. The only thing we know about her is that she's a black acid dragon who's Shemut's daughter.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, presumably she's at least 250.
Unknown: Well, who allowed her to proclaim herself to be Shemut's daughter?
Kenzo: Okay. Actually, actually- Oh ...
Kenzo: oh, well here's, here's another thing too, um, that, uh, right, maybe she's not Shemut's daughter.
Kenzo: But- She is nominally, um, trying to...
Kenzo: She's protecting something. Right ...
Kenzo: and is potentially trapped, untrapped.
Kenzo: So if she knows something about Shemut's daughter, which she very well may- Yeah ...
Delwath: then... I, I think just straightforward, I mean- Yeah.
Delwath: Okay ... straightforward, here's what we're doing.
Delwath: We know that, we know that you have, uh, issues with Shemut.
Kenzo: But do we have anything to offer her other than her just telling, helping us?
Kenzo: Like, what can we offer her in exchange?
Wellby: We'll show her the head once we kill her and-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... chop it off.
Wellby: Satisfaction of seeing...
Kenzo: Can we throw things in, in the, in the thing?
Seeker: Grisly. I love it. No.
DM: Throw things in the...
Unknown: You can only...
DM: Has to be a living creature.
Delwath: Yeah. You have to be holding it, so like you have to go through.
Kenzo: You can't- I'm just saying like, like, you know, even if,
Kenzo: you know, 'cause right now the only thing is like, just help us because we're doing something that you might like.
Kenzo: Is there anything else that we could potentially offer her?
Delwath: I, I think see what she says, right?
Delwath: Like, she's either gonna be like, "My spite, I just not interested in helping you even against Shemut."
Kenzo: Yeah. But if she's kinda like, "Oh, like I'm interested, but what are you gonna do for me?"
Unknown: Like, what do we have? What would we offer?
Kenzo: That's what I'm saying. Ooh ... like, is what information or like could it be a promise that like, you know, after we kill Apollyon, and maybe this is true, we, maybe we let her out.
Delwath: Like we really- No, I don't think we should let her out ...
Seeker: She'll have a seat on the cabinet, you understand?
Kenzo: No, but seriously, like what, what... It's like are we, are just gonna pun- punishing her forever, just like trap her in here?
Kenzo: Or is there some like atonement, you know?
Kenzo: Can she be let out to the orcs and like, like through some like judicial process or whatever, you know?
Kenzo: I'm serious, you know.
Wellby: How long has she been trapped now?
Wellby: Since before the war.
Delwath: Like, like 500 years.
DM: No, like,
DM: like 250 years.
Kenzo: Like is that just? No, Apophis was 4...
DM: No, she was the granddaughter of...
Wellby: Yes.
Kenzo: Do we truly know, know?
DM: No, she was like half 1.
Wellby: Restorative justice.
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. You know, restorative justice/ like, like, you know, what the fuck, like And that's just another example of- Restorative justice for hobgoblins ...
Wellby: how the prison system doesn't rehabilitate people.
Kenzo: Why? W- are hobgoblins like innately evil or something?
Kenzo: Yeah. Are they? Yeah.
Delwath: They don't have souls.
Unknown: Really?
Seeker: Is that Delwath talking or me? [laughs]
Unknown: Delwath.
Kenzo: But no, but like seriously, are, are like just, just in Tal- like are hobgoblins just like a...
Kenzo: 'Cause, you know, like the orcs, they like can farm and do shit.
Kenzo: Like can't hobgoblins also like- Most of the orcs can't.
Unknown: They have to break free from their god first.
Delwath: But, but some of them do, you know? I know, but if they don't, there's no redemption.
Kenzo: Well, this is like, I'm just saying, you know, it's like is there something that can be...
Kenzo: Like is there some-
Wellby: Could we put her in the city cut off from the gods?
Wellby: What, what happened to her-
Delwath: Like hobgoblins aren't related.
Delwath: They, the hob- the thing about hobgoblins is not...
Delwath: Orcs are possessed by the god of w- by their god.
Unknown: So h- what about Hobgoblins are soul...
Delwath: I mean, Delwath's opinion is they're soulless and don't have souls, and therefore are intrinsically sociopathic 'cause they don't have souls.
Unknown: So you're, you're like-
Wellby: Similarly, a chair or a rock is intrinsically sociopathic
Kenzo: ... yeah, exactly. You're, you're a Cartes- you're a Cartesian materialist.
Kenzo: You're just like, "Oh, like cats, like they don't have souls.
Kenzo: Like we can, we can just like beat them up."
Kenzo: No, cats totally have souls. Yeah, I know, but like hobgoblins also, like halflings and so...
Kenzo: [laughs] You're a fucking Cartesian materialist.
DM: You're just like whatever fucking wants to talk about. The metaphysics of hobgoblins in Talgar are not entirely clear, but...
Seeker: They're not associated with a singular god.
Wellby: But the sympathies of elves are unambiguous.
Unknown: The sympathies of elves are unambiguous.
Unknown: [laughs] That's certainly true.
DM: And also the, the, the...
Unknown: So
Unknown: most,
DM: almost anything that exists with a sentience in Talgar was created by some divine being.
Kenzo: And hobgoblins in some part-
DM: But hobgoblins were not.
Kenzo: How, how were they created? Do we know how they were created?
DM: They were created as sort of a trick by this like void mind that just wants existence to cease.
DM: Now whether that means...
DM: So they have no, like there's no divine...
DM: Hobgoblins cannot use divine magic.
DM: There's no
Unknown: hobgoblin
Delwath: See, they have no souls.
DM: Whether that means they're intrinsically evil is a different question.
Kenzo: But, but just, just another... Again, it's like the only reason that she's in the mirror is because she was resisting Shemut.
Kenzo: That was her crime.
Delwath: Wow.
Wellby: That was the crime for which she was imprisoned, but that was not her only crime.
Kenzo: What else do we know anything else about her?
DM: We know nothing else about her.
Kenzo: I soul sighted her, right? And she, uh-
Unknown: But I mean a hobgoblin can use, um-
Kenzo: I don't think she... Can I, can I soul sight her through the mirror?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: I'm with the elves on this one.
Unknown: That-
Seeker: Maybe the hobgoblins could be reframed to really portray the way they've been victimized historically.
Unknown: Ah, I'm, I'm-
Unknown: And oppressed
Kenzo: ... I'm feeling like, yeah, like I, I don't know.
Delwath: This is, this is not- They've been victimized by slaughtering any human or elf they encounter.
Seeker: [laughs] Well...
Kenzo: I mean, I think there's just a lot of like pro-elf propaganda on Talgar, just this very like, you know, elven supremacy, you know, situation going on here.
Seeker: Between that and the human supremacy and the elves are-
Wellby: The, the gods gave the elves this land.
Delwath: The gods did. [laughs] They literally created a giant forest for the elves.
Delwath: I know. But we gave it up out of our generosity to the humans.
Wellby: What about the people who were in the forest before the elves came along?
Delwath: There were no people.
Wellby: Oh, gee, of course an elf would say that.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: It was day one.
Unknown: Just the thing for an elf to say.
Unknown: It was the first day in the universe.
Kenzo: De-colonizers.
Delwath: The elves gave the swamps to the...
Delwath: I mean, the gods gave the swamps to the lizard folk, and the mountains to the dwarves-
Unknown: All right
Delwath: ... and the forests to the elves.
Kenzo: Let's fucking talk to the goblins or goblins.
Wellby: The whole world is the halflings.
Unknown: And the whole world's the halflings.
Kenzo: I'm, I'm gonna be, I'm gonna be an empathetic ear.
Unknown: Who are always welcome in the elven forests.
Wellby: Hmm.
Seeker: Okay. Are there, is there some taxonomic relationship between goblins and hobgoblins?
Seeker: Do goblins exist?
DM: Yeah. Goblins are a bit more sympathetic.
DM: They're basically the slaves of the hobgoblins.
Seeker: Oh. But
Seeker: anyway, okay
DM: There are all the goblin lords that are related.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: Um, I think we just straight-
Kenzo: Let's do it. Let's do it. Let's talk. Let's go.
Wellby: We can also... We could tell her the story of the Great War and Cha'mutte's destruction.
Unknown: That might be a satisfying thing.
Delwath: Let's wait to see... I mean, I think we wait.
Delwath: If she says, "Well, what am I gonna do for you?"
Delwath: We can offer her information.
Kenzo: Yeah. Maybe you don't not be the one leading this conversation.
Kenzo: The one that's like, "Just hobgoblins have no soul and should be killed."
Unknown: And yeah, maybe, you know-
Wellby: It's true because I'm also the only one good at talking to people
Kenzo: ... or do we do like, as a kind of like a cop bad cop, you know?
Seeker: I like the idea of telling her the history of the world that she missed, 'cause she's never left.
Delwath: See, I think actually Delwath's gonna approach it.
Delwath: I mean, Kenzo can jump in as good cop if it seems appropriate.
Delwath: I think-
Kenzo: Kenzo is definitely gonna, gonna-
Delwath: But, but-
Kenzo: ... gonna try to reign in Delwath's, uh-
Delwath: I mean, honorable... There's a little bit of an honorable enemy.
Delwath: I mean, there's a little bit of an enemy vibe, right?
Delwath: Like at least hobgoblins.
Delwath: I would anticip- I would approach it as like the, "Look, I know we generally mostly like fight and kill each other, but like,
Delwath: let's make a... Like we're going up against an enemy.
Delwath: What... That is also your enemy."
Wellby: She wouldn't expect subterfuge from an elf.
Delwath: Yeah. Let's, let's-
Delwath: There's something to that
Delwath: ... I'm putting my cards on the table and-
Kenzo: Let's fucking do it. Let's do it
Delwath: ... offering you an opportunity to help us kill Cha'mutte's daughter, if you're interested.
Kenzo: Let's do it. Mirror.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: She appears
Unknown: looking
DM: kind of the same as before, so like a hobgoblin,
DM: um, wearing clothes.
Delwath: What do hobgoblins look like?
DM: I don't actually know.
Delwath: Okay.
Unknown: I think the same.
Unknown: You don't have to think of it right now. Just imagine it [sighs] and decide it look.
DM: Yeah. Whatever the... I don't know what hobgoblins are supposed to look like in D&D.
Seeker: Like orcs without tusks?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Maybe.
DM: I don't know. They're always...
Unknown: Yeah, I don't know.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Dracula, come back.
Delwath: Come back. Yeah, no, I... If, uh...
Delwath: Don't, don't go on a tangent just if you had an idea in your head.
Delwath: Anyway, and so-
Kenzo: Does, does she say anything?
Delwath: Delwath will start with that, I mean, the spiel that I gave you basically is the vibe.
DM: Um, she kind of sort of blinks her eyes open and sort of says, "You again."
Delwath: And, and looks-
Delwath: Let's all start into it, right? Like...
DM: Okay. Um, oh, we do probably need a die.
Unknown: Can you go grab a D20?
Delwath: Yeah. [items rustling]
DM: This is Delwath's.
Kenzo: Delwath weirdly has a high charisma.
Kenzo: I don't understand it myself, but-
Wellby: He's persuasive.
Unknown: A 10.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: He's just... He has a lot of self-confidence.
Delwath: [laughs]
Wellby: People are attracted to that in elves.
Kenzo: Yeah. Just like saying stuff that they think is real and then whether it's real or not.
Unknown: Exactly.
Unknown: It's kind of real.
Delwath: Yeah. [die rolling] 22.
Delwath: [thudding] Um,
Delwath: [sighs] now Seeker has to give me inspiration, but it's probably not necessary.
Delwath: 22's a pretty good roll.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Disadvantage against hobgoblins.
Unknown: No. Um...
Unknown: Ah, come on. Stop.
Delwath: I'll te- I mean, I'll tell her that there's this dragon.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: I'll describe the dragon.
Delwath: I'll say she claims to be Cha'mutte's daughter.
Delwath: That's it.
Delwath: Tell her, her the name,
Delwath: and like, "We thought of you kind of."
Delwath: Um, [laughs] we thought of you.
Delwath: It just made us just...
Delwath: Just like, "We thought you might be interested in news of your enemy."
DM: And what are you... Like what are you trying to convince her to?
Delwath: I'm asking... I'm basically telling her we're planning on fighting this dragon, and does she know anything that would help us?
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Well, first-
Unknown: Well, which, which main-
Kenzo: Maybe, maybe, maybe first we just, we just say like, "Uh," and just, just, just see her reaction-
Delwath: Right
Kenzo: ... to the news about Cha'mutte's daughter, and does she like, does she like-
Delwath: That's true actually
Kenzo: ... does she like recoil or is she neutral?
Kenzo: Is she like, you know?
Delwath: Yeah. Watch her, watch her carefully, like insight, like-
Unknown: Yeah. Oh, yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... does-
DM: Yeah, go ahead and make an insight check.
Delwath: Does she like
Delwath: react like [die rolling]
Unknown: D20. Eight.
Unknown: 20.
Delwath: Does she like react like there is no, like, "Cha'mutte's daughter, I've never heard of this," or like doesn't seem to care or?
DM: She's... I mean, she doesn't seem particularly
DM: not... I mean, she's not like, "Oh, yes."
DM: Or, you know?
DM: She doesn't seem like... She, she's sort of listening carefully and kind of her attitude is kind of like, "And what do you want?
DM: Why are you bothering me? What do you want from me?
DM: Unless you're gonna... Unless you're planning on freeing me,
DM: what kind of help do you expect?"
Delwath: Uh,
Delwath: I'll... I mean, the first thing is I, I thought she would
Delwath: appreciate the information.
Delwath: But of course, if it's of no value to her, that's fine.
Delwath: And does she know anything about Cha'mutte's daughter?
Delwath: Did this creature exist in her time?
Delwath: Had she heard rumors?
Unknown: Maybe.
DM: My concern was always my
DM: domain.
DM: Cha'mutte barged in unwelcome,
DM: and I would be very happy to just go back to my life.
DM: I want nothing to do with dragons or
DM: great quests.
DM: She comes across as pretty parochial.
Delwath: Hmm.
Kenzo: [clears throat] So-
DM: I might be willing to help if you will
DM: restore me to my
DM: proper place.
Kenzo: [clears throat] Do you know how long you've been in there?
DM: Well, it sounds like hundreds of years.
Wellby: Other people live in your territory now
DM: It was always an out of the way place in the world.
Unknown: [clears throat] So
Unknown: look,
Unknown: uh,
Kenzo: personally,
Kenzo: and again, this is just me speaking here,
Unknown: um,
Kenzo: I don't much like the idea of like...
Kenzo: I, I don't know anything about your, your past, what's, what's been happening for you, but,
Unknown: um,
Kenzo: I think there's
Kenzo: a possibility that we could imagine a scenario where you could come out of that mirror.
Unknown: I think
Kenzo: the world is shifting. There's a lot of things happening right now, and, um, us figuring out how to
Kenzo: [clears throat] deal with, uh, Cha'mutte's daughter is of critical importance in this moment in history.
Unknown: And
Kenzo: yeah, I mean, this is just me speaking.
Kenzo: I think we can all talk a little bit about this more, but I could imagine a way in which if you were able to provide information that could be critical, of, of critical use for us in
Kenzo: this upcoming engagement, that we could potentially figure something out.
Delwath: Freedom, I'll say this in Dunmari, freedom would require
Unknown: fighting us, with us, no?
Delwath: We're not gonna let her go just for telling us things.
Wellby: We're not gonna put her on the battlefield with us either.
Unknown: No, I'm not saying right now.
Seeker: Then I don't see any way to let her go.
Unknown: Not now.
Delwath: Information's not worth it.
Wellby: I mean, if she's got teleport, as soon as she's out of that mirror, she's out of our control.
Delwath: That's why I don't think we should free her.
Kenzo: Yeah. Do you have any information that is helpful to us?
Wellby: Well, actually,
Wellby: do you wanna see Cha'mutte's daughter dead?
Wellby: 'Cause that's our plan for the day.
Wellby: And if you don't, and if it doesn't matter, we can call it a day.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: But if you do,
Wellby: let's talk.
Kenzo: And if you have anything that can help us, let's talk.
Delwath: I mean, didn't she sort of already say no, she did, but...
Unknown: If either of the-
Wellby: Just wanna be real direct. If our interests don't align-
Unknown: Yeah, then that's-
Wellby: ... we'll move on.
Kenzo: That, that's fine.
DM: How, how, so what did, wait, what did, uh, did you tell her the whole story about Dimitaur, where you were or where Cha'mutte was?
Kenzo: No. Just, just that we're, we're, we're gonna go, go, go kill Cha'mutte's daughter.
DM: I don't see why I would have a quarrel with Cha'mutte's daughter unless she was threatening my territory.
DM: Is she?
Unknown: [sighs]
DM: I would say no, as I currently have no territory.
Unknown: Hmm. All right.
Unknown: Well...
DM: Unless you're offering me territory.
Kenzo: But do you, do you have any information to help us?
Wellby: What-
Unknown: Either way?
Wellby: What if she was keeping some part of Cha'mutte alive?
Wellby: What if she was
Wellby: protecting something or planning?
Wellby: As it's been described, she's
Wellby: serving some purpose that she can't move from.
DM: That's fine by me.
DM: I'm not sure what quarrel you think I have with Cha'mutte other than
DM: all I want is my own kingdom to run as I see fit.
Wellby: You're the least vengeful hobgoblin I've ever met.
Kenzo: Listen, this is really simple.
Kenzo: Do you have any information at all that could be useful to us in this?
Unknown: And if not-
DM: I have lots of information
Kenzo: ... about Cha'mutte's daughter that'd be useful in a, in a battle?
DM: Mm.
Kenzo: Doesn't really seem like it.
Kenzo: I think we're probably done here.
Seeker: Did you, uh, did you know your grandfather?
DM: [scoffs] You know that, I'm not sure what that has to do with anything.
Seeker: Well, he was a
Seeker: powerful wizard as far as we know.
Unknown: How do we know that, by the way?
Seeker: Well, he created-
DM: He made the mirror.
Seeker: He created this mirror that you're, you yourself are trapped inside of, even now.
Seeker: It's been a very powerful tool for us.
Seeker: You too
Seeker: could have a legacy like that,
Seeker: but it takes intervening in the world.
DM: Keeping people imprisoned forever?
DM: I don't know if that is my desire.
DM: Well, yes, there are some people I keep imprisoned forever.
DM: That's certainly true.
Seeker: Our group has used this mirror created by your grandfather
Unknown: to,
Seeker: in the ways that we have access to, nudge the history of the whole world towards peace.
DM: Towards peace?
Unknown: We have.
DM: That seems like a rather
DM: small-minded use of such a tool.
Seeker: How would you use it?
DM: She's look, she looks kind of thoughtful.
Delwath: Here's where the lack of soul comes out.
Unknown: [laughing] Tell it.
DM: Well, it seems an easy way to gain territory.
DM: Just trap the ruler
DM: and move in.
Seeker: And that's how you'd use the mirror if you had it?
DM: I'm sure if I had time to think, I'd come up with other creative uses, yes.
Seeker: We've had a great deal of such time and made many creative uses.
DM: Interesting.
DM: And you too desire territory?
DM: Perhaps I could work with you. [gasps] Look in curiously at Seeker.
Seeker: [laughs] [clears throat] Surely there's a way our interests could align.
Kenzo: Can we, is this like, does she ha- I mean, it doesn't seem like you have any information to help us.
DM: I mean, Kenzo sense with your insight is, I mean, she's trying to string you along.
Kenzo: Yeah, exactly. Uh, this is... I think we're done here.
Kenzo: I don't think there's- Just telepathically.
Kenzo: Like, if our goal is to try to get information to help us with this battle, this is not the way.
Unknown: There's, this is a dead end.
Wellby: No, we don't have shared interests here.
Kenzo: This is a dead end.
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Yep, I agree.
Unknown: Well,
Kenzo: we'll see you soon.
DM: [laughs] She's like, "Wait."
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: I was thinking about the... I was thinking about...
Delwath: [coughs] All right, well that didn't pan out.
Kenzo: It's okay. They don't all do.
Delwath: Although it occurs to me,
Delwath: if we knew of a place where there was an expansionist hobgoblin leader
Delwath: who was trying to conquer a human kingdom or push and expand their territory,
Delwath: dropping her in
Unknown: might actually be useful.
Unknown: Why?
Delwath: Because she would try and conquer the hobgoblin territory from the other hobgoblin leader and cause a civil war.
Delwath: And she seems like the kind of person who, if she won, might be a lot more content, right?
Delwath: Like she strikes me a little bit as the kind of leader who, given a well-defended border and absolute control over her kingdom-
Kenzo: Would just stay there
Delwath: ... would just stay there.
Wellby: Maybe, but maybe the lesson from the last time she had a well-defended border and absolute control was that that wasn't enough.
Delwath: That's true also.
Wellby: And that you have to continually-
Kenzo: Well, and also why, why wouldn't she join forces with the, uh...
Kenzo: I mean
Delwath: 'Cause she wants to lead.
Kenzo: But in the short term-
Delwath: Mm
Delwath: ... that's a risk.
Wellby: I think we're not letting her out, are we?
Unknown: I don't think so. [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs]
Delwath: Thomas just looks at you like, "Yeah, yeah, okay.
Delwath: C- Maybe you should say the elf was right."
Kenzo: I, uh, so, so...
Delwath: [laughs]
Wellby: Well, you can still be wrong.
Kenzo: Both things... Exactly.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: And, and-
Kenzo: Both things can be true, yeah.
Kenzo: We're not letting her out, and the elf was wrong simultaneously.
Delwath: [laughs]
Kenzo: Yeah. The universe was not destroyed, see?
Unknown: So... [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs]
Wellby: All right.
Seeker: So, all right.
Unknown: Well-
Delwath: So
Kenzo: ... is there anything we can learn about
Kenzo: the dragon
Kenzo: other than just, you know, barging into the lair?
Kenzo: Can we sneak into the lair?
Delwath: Well-
Kenzo: Can you use your animal, uh, animal, animal, um-
Delwath: Animal shapes thing?
Kenzo: Yeah. Let's see if we could.
Delwath: Before...
Delwath: We should consider whether we want
Delwath: to work with her.
Unknown: Parley?
Delwath: Yeah.
Seeker: We can also validate the question of
Seeker: interdimensional portal or not using that wand.
Kenzo: We already know that she's not, she's not in there.
Kenzo: It's inter... We already know it's interdi- I, I can sense her
Delwath: Kenzo couldn't sense her.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Delwath: Yeah. She's either warded in some fashion or interdimensional.
Unknown: She... But is there any-
Delwath: And probably couldn't-
Kenzo: Is there anything that can ward...
DM: Yeah, so there's like... I mean, there's a 8th level spell called Mind Blank that makes you completely undetectable to any magic-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... or other sense that would detect creatures of your type.
Seeker: So we may as well use the wand and just-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... make sure we know exactly where it is.
Delwath: What does the wand do again?
Seeker: Detects the nearest-
DM: It detects the nearest portal.
Wellby: What's the range?
Seeker: I think it's any range.
Wellby: Oh, okay.
DM: Just the nearest portal.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: It's just, like, more useful if you're close to one.
Wellby: Oh. [laughs]
Seeker: As you move, it sort of changes direction a little bit.
Delwath: Yeah.
Delwath: Um...
DM: Right. It lasts for, like, 10 minutes or something, so you can sort of triangulate a little bit the distance.
Kenzo: Okay. I mean, there may be portals.
Kenzo: Like, we're right in the middle of the island right now.
Kenzo: It feels a pretty magical place.
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: There could be some...
Kenzo: Or just use it?
Seeker: It's an interesting question.
Kenzo: 'Cause it, it might tell us about a portal that's close to here that we-
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: That could be a good side quest.
Delwath: Like why not find out, right?
Delwath: Like can it...
Unknown: Sure.
Wellby: What can we do-
Kenzo: How many times can we use that, that wand?
Seeker: It's once a day, right?
DM: To do the portals, it's once a day 'cause it requires all, all the charges.
Seeker: I'm inclined to wait till we're closer to it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: I agree.
Wellby: I think in an ideal world, we wanna lure her out of the lair one way or another.
Kenzo: Yeah, we do. Yeah, we do. We can't fight...
Kenzo: Uh, fighting her in an acid lair sounds horrible.
Wellby: And it would be nice to fight her not with all of the
Wellby: hench-persons at the same time.
Unknown: Oh, there's-
Wellby: Like the sharks
Seeker: ... oh yeah, there's the chimeras and the
Seeker: dragonettes and-
Wellby: They, they can all fly though
Seeker: ... there's a fiend.
Delwath: How did we even find-
Wellby: Oh, the fiend
Seeker: ... how did we find out about the fiend?
Delwath: Kenzo sensed it.
Wellby: Kenzo sensed it.
Unknown: Oh, man. Yeah.
Delwath: But it implies the fiend is on this side of the portal.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Either that or she does in fact have the 8th level Mind Blank spell.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: Right?
Delwath: So
Delwath: the general luring plan would involve...
Kenzo: If we had something to trade
Delwath: ... offering a trade, letting it be known that we wanna offer a trade.
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: And then
Delwath: somehow refusing to...
Delwath: demanding that the trade happen-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... outside.
Wellby: That's right.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: So we won't deal with the dragonettes?
Kenzo: No, they would be outside and we would have to deal with them, yeah.
Seeker: No, I mean, we won't just use them as intermediate.
Seeker: We're not willing to use them as intermediates.
Delwath: I mean, the throne is an interesting trade good-
Wellby: Mm-hmm
Delwath: ... that has some plausible challenges getting-
Wellby: Right
Delwath: ... bringing into her space.
Unknown: That's true. [laughs]
Delwath: Right?
Kenzo: Yeah. She, she... I mean, we definitely can't tell her we have a portable hole, so.
Delwath: Right.
Kenzo: So it's just we have... We, we're able to get this throne.
Kenzo: Is there any way for us to communicate remotely with her?
Kenzo: There should be bunch. Sending messages-
Delwath: Well, we can-
Unknown: Links
Delwath: ... we can,
Delwath: we could, we could send a Drankharian message stone with a dragonette
Delwath: to her.
Wellby: We have message stones?
DM: You don't have a p- you don't have a complete pair.
Delwath: Ah, we don't have a complete pair.
Wellby: We have two halves.
Delwath: You have two halves.
Seeker: There's like a child in Jordan.
Wellby: One that goes to the little kid, yeah.
Delwath: And one that goes, one goes to a child-
Unknown: One that goes to Jordan
Delwath: ... and one that goes to-
Delwath: Or someone like that. Oh, that's too bad.
Delwath: Mm-hmm. Um, I mean,
Delwath: I can cast... Could I cast Dream?
Delwath: Do dragons sleep? I don't even know if dragons sleep.
Unknown: Arcana?
Delwath: So-
Seeker: Oh, do dragons sleep?
Delwath: Do dragons sleep?
Kenzo: That should be pretty obvious.
Delwath: Um...
Kenzo: Just roll, roll and add 20 to it or whatever.
Delwath: Yeah.
Seeker: That's a 26.
Delwath: Um-
DM: Dragons, as far...
DM: At least the i- oldest of dragons are like elves.
DM: They don't, they don't sleep, sleep.
DM: They're never fully unconscious.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: They're always at least partially aware of the world around them.
Kenzo: But can you communicate with Dream?
Delwath: Dream doesn't work on elves. It doesn't work on...
Delwath: You have to be, like, asleep, asleep.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: Got it.
Seeker: And it would be- So they're like dolphins.
DM: They're like- Yeah ... half, half sleeping They're like do- yeah.
DM: They're, they're not so much like... I mean, they don't like trance like elves, but they're always partially How...
Kenzo: Sh- this is important, though. How can we communicate with the dragon while it's in its lair?
Wellby: Hmm, why not send the dragonets as messengers?
Kenzo: We can. We have to do a bunch of back and forth.
Kenzo: You know, it'll be kind of a pain in the ass.
Wellby: Well, but the message can be, "We're only gonna negotiate directly with you out here."
Delwath: Now, and is the plan
Delwath: to set a trap and kill her when she comes out to negotiate, or are we gonna negotiate in good faith?
Unknown: Well, what else, what else-
Delwath: Are we gonna respond to her trap when she springs it, but not spring our own trap?
Unknown: I mean,
Kenzo: on the one hand,
Kenzo: it'd be nice to know that this island was cleansed.
Unknown: Haha.
Wellby: I mean, I think we're not gonna attack her when she comes out.
Unknown: Yeah. I th-
Wellby: 'Cause the first thing she's gonna do is run back into the lair,
Wellby: and we can't kill her before...
Wellby: And we can't stop her.
Wellby: And then she's waiting in the lair with all of her powers ready to kill us.
Wellby: I mean...
Delwath: I mean, there's a straightforward offer of Apollyon's throne for the piece of jade.
Kenzo: That's such a... The, the, I mean, the throne's not magic.
Kenzo: The jade's clearly magic.
Wellby: But the fact that we have Apollyon's throne also means that she can...
Wellby: She now has access to the west side of the island-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... unimpeded.
Wellby: Like, that's really...
Wellby: Like, that's a deeper offer underneath that.
Unknown: But is it, though? Yeah, but it, it...
Kenzo: That exists now. She can go there now.
Wellby: But she doesn't.
Delwath: She's afraid of it.
Wellby: Right.
Kenzo: But, but she...
Kenzo: If she, if she knows that we have the throne,
Kenzo: then we, then why can't she surmise that we've disarmed, which is actually true, 'cause now she can just literally go over there whenever the fuck she wants.
Seeker: So another-
Unknown: It would be-
Seeker: Another approach would be for her to find that out indirectly.
Seeker: So we don't tell her, but we make sure the dragonets tell her that she can go there.
Unknown: Ah, this-
Seeker: And then we ambush her there.
Kenzo: We tell her, we tell her that, um-
Wellby: Yeah
Kenzo: ... we know that there are, um,
Kenzo: um... The...
Kenzo: You, you make creative magic, but we've seen the greatest thing of all, which is the ability to create any magic, create any magic item.
Kenzo: We are, um...
Kenzo: Yeah, and let her know that we've got the abil- that we would trade with...
Kenzo: We, we tell her we would trade with her the ability to, um, the information and the materials so that she can make whatever she wants.
Delwath: I like Seeker's idea, though, of just spreading rumors and pouncing on her when she appears.
Wellby: I don't know if we have time for that, though.
Wellby: What if she's like, "Great, I'll go next month"?
Delwath: Well, I know. That's... Yeah.
Unknown: That's true.
Seeker: Right. How do dragons think about time?
Wellby: It's like- Yeah.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: That's right. They long lived. No, but I th- I thi- I think we could bargain with her that.
Kenzo: I mean, that's, that's the ultimate thing to bargain.
Unknown: I mean, what if we sh-
Seeker: 'Cause she doesn't- Oh, we could spread a rumor that- That we're going to loot it ...
Seeker: we also recently learned about Apollyon's tower and we're headed there.
Unknown: Correct.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: And so she has to get there first.
Delwath: What if we-
Unknown: Beats us to it
Delwath: ... what if we sent the dragonets out to start chattering amongst themselves that a group of-
Seeker: Dimitar could spread the rumor
Delwath: Yeah, Dimitar could spread the rumor that us, the four of us, a group of adventurers-
Kenzo: We could spread it ourselves. We just tell Gresh, Ghesh to go and tell-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly. Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah
Delwath: ... have, have just defeated Apollyon's traps and are heading, and have been retreated, recovered, and are now heading back
Delwath: to the tower to loot it.
Unknown: Totally.
Seeker: But she has an opportunity for a limited time.
Wellby: What's-
Unknown: But-
Wellby: What's the advantage of doing that as rumors rather than just talking with her directly?
Seeker: Like just- We reveal less about ourselves ...
Delwath: telling her that we're going straight to the...
Delwath: It, it... So I think the advantage of doing it as rumors is that we're hoping she bites at the bait and comes to investigate the tower with whatever group of...
Delwath: Now, the problem is she might bring 100 dragonets,
Delwath: or she might send 100 dragonets and not come herself.
Delwath: I mean, there's a lot of ways it can go wrong.
Seeker: Is that a good place for... Also, is that a good place for us to fight her?
Delwath: I mean- From ... I think anywhere ...
Unknown: anything's better than the lair I think is- Anything's better than the lair.
Seeker: Yeah, that's true.
Delwath: Um, I mean, the problem is if we're not fighting in her, her in her lair, there's always the chance that she is skittish, and as soon as she takes any meaningful damage,
Unknown: she runs.
Unknown: She runs.
Wellby: That's what the green dragon did.
Delwath: Right. And so then-
Unknown: Oh
Delwath: ... you get into the situation where- She knows about us ...
Delwath: how do we...
Delwath: Do we have any way of stopping her from getting her back, from getting back to the lair?
Kenzo: I mean, she can just teleport back to her lair whenever she wants probably, right?
Delwath: Maybe. Oh.
Delwath: Now, if we-
Seeker: We don't know what magical abilities she has
Delwath: ... if we, if we knew her lair, if we could see her lair...
Delwath: Oh, but it's extra dimensional, so we probably can't teleport to it.
Wellby: We don't know if it's extra dimensional.
Delwath: So if we could teleport to her...
Delwath: If we, if we could draw her out, and then when she starts to flee, we cast teleport, go to her lair, take the jade, and then flee before she gets back.
Seeker: There you go.
Kenzo: How do we do that, though?
Delwath: Well, I don't think we can, unfortunately.
Delwath: [laughs] But if we could, it would be a good plan.
Kenzo: Just, just as we're talking this all out, as we're talking this all out, it feels as though we're gonna have to kill her there no matter what.
Kenzo: 'Cause even if we draw her out, if she's got the ability to go back there however she wants, which feels pretty likely that she's got some ability to go back there, and if she's partially wounded or whatever the fuck.
Kenzo: Yeah. 'Cause the... Aren't the lairs like, uh, like...
Kenzo: Didn't we have the experience already?
Kenzo: Like, they... Like, we almost killed them and then they just, like, got all their hit points back and they're just like-
Delwath: No. With Grimbiskal, we killed him in human form
Delwath: We thought we had beaten him.
Delwath: We thought he was an elf.
Kenzo: Right. Right.
Delwath: And we had pretty much taken him down-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... after his charm backfired on Seeker.
Delwath: And then he was, like, only at a few hi- Well, actually, I think Delwath killed him.
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: But then he turned into a dragon.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But because he has a second set of hit points, 'cause polymorph gives him all of, gives him double hit points, right?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. But then-
Wellby: But the point still stands. It-
Delwath: He fled once...
Delwath: As soon as he became a dragon, he ran back to his lair
Wellby: Well, he sort of taunted you a little bit.
Delwath: He taunted us a little bit and then ran back.
Kenzo: But wait. But, but does the lair ha- I, I'm remembering some lair where we fought something where, like, it regenerated a whole bunch of stuff.
Kenzo: Like, who was... Was there-
DM: Um, the, I think the, the veta demon-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... had regenerating ability.
Unknown: Oh, okay. Okay, all right. Okay, all right.
Kenzo: So but I'm just saying, i- is there any scenario where we don't, where we're, we're not able to beat...
Kenzo: Like, I feel like we're gonna have to kill the thing in this lair.
DM: The, the dragonets, when you're talking to Gresh, described the lair as a nasty room full of-
Unknown: Right
Wellby: ... acidic geysers.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Awesome.
Unknown: Just sounds horrible.
Delwath: Right.
Wellby: The other path, though, is that we try to just do a deal and not fight at all.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, acidic geysers is cool.
Delwath: A legendary action to soak you with acid [laughs].
Kenzo: Yeah. Oh yeah, we're fucked.
Kenzo: It w- it's just, it's just gonna be-
DM: Well, I remember that Seeker is fucked
Kenzo: ... Yeah, but it's just gonna be, like, area effect.
Kenzo: Like, it's just, like, acid fireballs, like, everywhere, you know?
Delwath: Right. But I mean-
Kenzo: Like, every round just, like, taking, just, like, massive amounts of acid damage.
Unknown: I don't... You know, that's, like, how
Delwath: Well, you can deck save your way out of it almost certainly.
Delwath: The two of you will be okay. It's just Delwath will die.
Kenzo: Okay. Then that's not terrible.
Kenzo: [laughs] Kenza says quietly to himself.
Kenzo: And I look at him sideways. No, no, that would be terrible.
Unknown: But I take that back.
Delwath: Um-
Wellby: If we try to do a deal,
Wellby: like, I feel like we have good things to offer.
Wellby: Like, she doesn't know that we've already knocked down the tower.
Wellby: We could offer, "Hey, we'll go destroy the tower."
Unknown: Exactly.
Wellby: "Bring the throne back to you-"
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Wellby: ... so that you know that it's really happened.
Unknown: Exactly. Exactly.
Wellby: And then pretend to go do that if she keeps her word.
Unknown: Yeah. And, and, uh-
Wellby: But also, if she's Cha'mutte's daughter and she knows that the piece of jade is from Rai-
Unknown: Right
Wellby: ... she may not wanna give it up under any circumstances.
Delwath: But if she knows it's the key to killing Apollyon, she might.
Wellby: Right. Right, right, right, right, right, right, right, right.
Delwath: Right. So the, the bargaining stack theory would be something like we are enemies of Apollyon.
Delwath: We are coming here seeking Apollyon death.
Seeker: So we're gonna-
Wellby: Right
Seeker: ... shut down the tower for you.
Delwath: And, and we... Here's his throne and you can ward it o- Like,
Delwath: his, his throne could be a psychologically powerful bribe-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... if she ca- I mean, she might be like the hobgoblin and be like, "I'm Cha'mutte's daughter, but I don't care about Cha'mutte.
Delwath: Like, so what that he died?"
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Right?
Kenzo: Or, or so what, or so what about Apollyon?
Delwath: Or maybe even, "Hey, I'm happy he died," right?
Delwath: Like, maybe she likes that Cha'mutte died.
Seeker: Oh, yeah. Well, at what age is-
Delwath: We don't, we don't know that there's, like, a close bond, right?
Seeker: At what age is a dragon like a teenager?
Delwath: Right. Like, is she, like, a surly teenager who's like, "You killed my, my da- Apollyon killed my dad, that means he's my best friend"?
Wellby: But there, but there's a couple... There's, like, different levels of alignment of interest there, because even if she doesn't care about Apollyon being killed or Cha'mutte getting vengeance or any of that stuff, probably she still cares
Wellby: about getting access to Apollyon's tower, which we care about if we care about Apollyon getting killed.
Wellby: So, like-
Delwath: But-
Wellby: ... there's still alignment there
Delwath: ... I mean, it's a big cost to give up.
Delwath: I mean, she's gonna go take all of our ability to make cool magic items with the Divine Forge.
Kenzo: Yeah, I mean, it's not turning her into his-
Wellby: I mean, we're gonna come back and kill her.
Unknown: It's not, it's not-
Delwath: Ah, there you go. Come, come back after we kill Apollyon and-
Unknown: Yeah. It's-
Delwath: ... clean, clean
Kenzo: ... it's not... She's not, like, a lich dragon, but then if she's just artificing, like, you know, fucking cool dragon magic items for herself-
Wellby: Yeah
Kenzo: ... like, that feels-
Wellby: Bad
Kenzo: ... that feels not...
Wellby: Right
Kenzo: ... you know. She'll polymorph herself into some, like, fucking powerful wizard and go in that room and just, like, you know.
Seeker: Maybe it'll make her lazy and overconfident, and then she'll-
Delwath: Yeah
Seeker: ... make security mistakes.
Delwath: I-
Kenzo: But then, like, us, like, having to fight her later is gonna be way harder when she's got, like, fucking, you know.
Delwath: What, let's expe- Is there any way we could find out more...
Delwath: Is there something we could do that would, like, help us understand?
Delwath: Like, 'cause the key challenge here is we don't know how she's gonna respond, right?
Kenzo: We also don't know what else is going on inside the geyser or, like, the lair or, like...
Delwath: Like, should we start-
Delwath: Maybe we do like-
Delwath: ... by, like, spreading...
Delwath: I mean, we could start by just telling Dimitaur to go spread some rumors
Delwath: about our, about our-
DM: Well, remember Dimitaur doesn't live here.
Delwath: That's true.
Wellby: You would have to spread the rumor.
Delwath: We could go-
Wellby: But you could, Gresh or Megren
Unknown: ... We could, we could go back to Gresh-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, mm-hmm
Delwath: ... right, or Megren and say, "Hey, actually, could you spread some rumors amongst-"
Kenzo: We just tell them and then they spread it themselves.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah. But-
Kenzo: We don't have to be like, "Go spread rumors."
Delwath: Sure. But, but, but we told them to keep our secret, right?
Delwath: So we need to at least tell them.
Kenzo: What, what's the rumor? What's the rumor?
Delwath: That...
Delwath: I mean, that we...
Delwath: So-
Seeker: We're gonna be taking over the Apollyon's tower soon.
Delwath: She-
Unknown: The throne room
Delwath: ... Well, hold on, hold on. She has historically been willing to trade.
Delwath: In other words, the dragonets, her attitude hasn't been, "The dragonets have treasure, I'm gonna come burn them out of the sky and take it."
Delwath: Right.
Delwath: So we just, we spread rumor.
Delwath: We just say we've gone spread rumors that a group of heroes has come back from Apollyon's tower with treasure.
Kenzo: I mean, that'll make her likely to talk to us, but...
Kenzo: So yeah, we could... I mean, we can get an audience.
Wellby: If it's a conversation, yeah.
Delwath: So then-
Unknown: We can get an audience
Delwath: ... and then how does she respond to that? She, does she respond by sending a bunch of dragonets to demand that we turn it all over?
Delwath: Does she respond by offering us, by start opening a negotiation?
Delwath: Like, does she respond by just ordering our, us killed?
Delwath: That would, like,
Unknown: tell us something, right?
Seeker: And the dragonets as a group have only seen Kenza, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So far, yeah.
Seeker: So we may wanna keep things that way.
Delwath: Ah, we could just say the lone monk.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: There you go.
Kenzo: That's interesting.
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: That's interesting.
Delwath: Kenza goes back
Kenzo: That's really interesting. Yeah, and you know what?
Unknown: I bet-
Seeker: We wanna be underestimated.
Kenzo: Totally. And I bet that could draw her out if I'm like, "Hey, I went there.
Kenzo: I found some re- I found some things that you might be of, that might be of interest to you, think you'd be find very interesting, but I'm not gonna go talk to you in your acid lair, so you gotta come out and talk."
Delwath: Yeah.
Delwath: Like-
Kenzo: I, I, I, I'll, I'll tell you about what I found.
Delwath: Right.
Kenzo: 'Cause I know, and I, 'cause I learned a lot there, but I'm only gonna talk to you out here.
Delwath: But-
Unknown: You have to, y-
Delwath: Right, right, right, right. Well, and, and, and, um, have them say, like,
Delwath: acknowledge that the stuff is hers, right?
Delwath: Like, like,
Delwath: the rumor we want... Well, okay, think about it this way.
Delwath: We want the rumor that gets back to her to be-
Kenzo: No, why, why, why rumor? Why just, just go and tell Gresh that, "Hey, I'm here."
Delwath: Send a direct, send a message?
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah, just tell her I, I, I...
Kenzo: Like, "You, you, you met the monk yesterday.
Kenzo: I gave you this amulet." The mo- the monk sh- like, the, the dragonet will have, like, the cool fucking thing that I get.
Kenzo: And then, "I went to the tower.
Kenzo: I, I, I know what is there.
Kenzo: I wanna talk to you about it, 'cause I know, I know this is, you know, this is your domain.
Kenzo: I wanna talk to you about what I found at the tower, but I'm only gonna talk to you outside your lair.
Kenzo: I'm not going to your lair."
Kenzo: That'll... I, I think that'll be...
Kenzo: She would ha- She would be very curious about that.
Seeker: And if we just suggest in there that also it seems like this monk has somehow defeated the defenses of the tower.
Kenzo: I, I don't even think... Because, like, 'cause, like, if the...
Kenzo: If she thinks that the, the, the tower defenses are already defeated, then why talk to me?
Kenzo: Just go. She'll just go there herself. But if I, if I went there and I've lear-
Unknown: Mm. Mm.
Kenzo: And I, I went there and I came back and I've learned things and I have, I, I wanna talk to you about what I found there, and just leave it like that, that's like a, "What the fuck did he find there?"
Kenzo: You know? Like, that's a interesting-
Seeker: But then she'll wanna come and talk to us, you're saying?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: So we can get an audience.
Kenzo: We can get an audience.
Delwath: Yeah. I just wonder if we're gonna get more information if we leave her more options.
Delwath: Like, make it less direct, like, di- directly asking for an audience.
Kenzo: We wanna draw her out and talk to her.
Kenzo: Are we... And then in that conversation, we're gonna decide real time right then and there-
Wellby: Whether to negotiate or attack
Kenzo: ... whether, whether, whether we actually f- full on try to negotiate or like, "Fuck it, let's start the attack."
Kenzo: And then at some point she's gonna go escape, but at least we've done a whole bunch of, bunch of damage to her out here and then we go to go in the lair and-
Delwath: Right. So one hopefully-
Seeker: So if, if there's a scenario where that, this conversation, the first conversation turns into the battle, uh, we should prepare for there to be a battle immediately.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: Yes.
Seeker: So I should, um,
Seeker: animate the ladder and also...
Seeker: Unless there's some other-
Kenzo: Can we prevent, can we, like, close the entrance or whatever, so at least, like, if she's got some, you know...
Kenzo: Can we seal it off?
Seeker: Uh, uh, seal what off?
Delwath: Of her lair?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: We'd have to go there.
Seeker: What do you mean? Well, where do we want her to come and talk to us?
Delwath: What do you mean seal it, like...
Wellby: Like close the portal or the entrance.
Delwath: Oh, that's interesting.
DM: The thermal baths are the, that's above her lair.
DM: It's just open to the air.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: There's nothing you could seal off.
Kenzo: That's actually interesting is we have her, we ha- Like, I'll say that, "Come meet me, but come meet me at like the, the foot, foot, the footsteps of the Wanderer," or something like that, just, like, someplace far.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: That she's gotta, like, travel to.
Delwath: Yeah. I thought that was where... Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I assumed that's what we were doing.
Kenzo: Okay. Okay. No, no, I, I was thinking of just even getting her outside the lair.
Delwath: Right.
Kenzo: Like, at her lair, but yeah, that's even better.
Delwath: Well, hold on. Can we teleport to the...
Delwath: Seeker saw through clairvoyance the thermal baths.
DM: Yep.
Delwath: That's a pretty good-
Kenzo: So we could teleport there.
DM: I mean, it's not guaranteed.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
DM: But-
Delwath: But it's not ba-
DM: We could pre-
Delwath: I mean, it's a good shot.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: We could... We'll get there.
Unknown: So-
Seeker: Close enough. Yeah
Wellby: Alternately, and I mean, this goes in a different direction, what if we, if we think we're gonna end up fighting her in her lair anyways, maybe we just wanna be there to start with.
Wellby: Negotiate in the lair and if it goes bad, we're already there.
Wellby: We don't have to run any gauntlet to get in.
Wellby: We don't have to deal with her-
Unknown: That's true. That's true
Wellby: ... guards on the surface.
Kenzo: That's true. That's true.
Kenzo: That's very true.
Wellby: We lower her...
Wellby: Like, we raise her comfort level.
Unknown: That's true.
Wellby: Lower her suspicion 'cause she's in a place of power.
Kenzo: That's true.
Delwath: That's true.
DM: Keep in mind, you know she very rarely leaves her ra- lair.
DM: The odds of her meeting you at the, the foot of the Wanderer is-
Seeker: Low, yeah
DM: ... pretty low.
Delwath: But see, I-
DM: She might be willing to emerge from her lair, but, like...
Seeker: She's not gonna come far out.
Delwath: But see, this is where I think-
DM: And the whole vibe you've gotten is like she is, sees herself as the undisputed boss of the island.
DM: Like, is she really gonna be willing to
DM: follow the orders of some lowly monk?
Kenzo: It's not orders, it's, it's just, uh, you know, if she-
DM: Just keep it in mind.
Kenzo: Yeah. No, for sure. For sure.
Delwath: See, this is where I was wondering if rumors works better because then we can see what order she gives to us,
Delwath: right?
Delwath: Like, if we, if the dragonets just are bringing information.
Wellby: I feel like the order's gonna be, "Come to the,
Wellby: come to the lair."
Kenzo: Or just, "Give me, give me what you have or die."
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: You know?
Wellby: Like-
Kenzo: You're, you're, you're a fucking, like-
DM: Every time dragonet... Well, Gresh and Megren were both summoned to the lair.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: To hand over the treasure.
Kenzo: Right. You know, the more I think about it-
DM: Yes
Kenzo: ... the more I think, I think it's... 'Cause if we start a fight, even if we get her on the outside of the lair, like, she'll immediately retreat back inside and then to your point, we're gonna have to go through the gauntlet of the fiend and
Kenzo: the uh, uh, all the way to get in there.
Delwath: See, I think we're...
Delwath: I mean, if we're going to her lair,
Delwath: I think we're better just playing it
Delwath: straight.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: Wait, the rainbow bridge as far as we know does not work through the anti-magic field or do we have any idea?
DM: You have no idea.
Delwath: Okay.
DM: But it does work between planes.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: So it actually might be easier to use in her lair than outside of her lair.
Delwath: Oh, 'cause we're outside the anti-magic field.
Unknown: You know what? As always-
Wellby: Oh, that's fascinating
Seeker: ... this whole thing comes down to questions of hydrogeology.
Seeker: Is there a way that the rivers,
Seeker: like, going underneath the ground might form a connection to her, her lair that would make it easier for us to get in?
Unknown: That's an interesting entrance.
Wellby: A secret backdoor? Yeah.
Kenzo: That's interesting.
Seeker: Except for the interplanar portal part, but...
Delwath: I mean
DM: I mean, the water in the
DM: thermal bath has to come from somewhere
Unknown: That's what I'm saying
DM: But that would just get you to the, this-
Kenzo: Entrance of the portal To the entrance, yeah
Delwath: ... entrance of the portal
Seeker: Yeah. But at least we could get there undetected.
Unknown: That would be valuable.
Kenzo: Well, h- holding that thought for one second [laughs] Which I think is a very...
Unknown: Like, let's talk about-
Unknown: Possibility
Kenzo: ... let- let's come back to that for a second though.
Unknown: Like,
Kenzo: if we don't know anything about how to even get to the portal, if there's some fucking keyword you need to even get in there Right ...
Kenzo: whatever the fuck,
Kenzo: I kinda like what you're saying, which is like we go in, we let- we get, we get the audience, all of us are there, you know, and we're just a bunch of humans.
Kenzo: She doesn't... She, you know, it's like ma- she's really comfortable.
Kenzo: She's in her space.
Kenzo: We get through all the whatever wards and tricks.
Kenzo: Like, the two options are, if we have to get to the lair, either we're fighting our way through and not knowing what the fuck we're doing and getting in, or we get the escort, we're in there, and maybe we get one round of like,
Kenzo: you know, decent, like, you know-
Delwath: Do we- ... attacks off I mean, it's harder to-
Seeker: There'll be dragonet loyalists in there too
Delwath: ... prepare a little bit, but do we have any way of trap...
Delwath: We don't... Do we have any spells that would prevent her from escaping?
Kenzo: Like if we lured her out? Yeah.
Wellby: It's hard 'cause she's gonna have legendary resistance.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah. She's probably gonna have some kind of magic maybe.
Kenzo: She's definitely gotta have some kinda teleport or something I mean, legendary resistance makes it tough
Unknown: She might have weird actions in her territory
Seeker: So wait, but, but, are any of those binding stones spells?
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: No
Delwath: What about binding? But everything's gonna work.
Delwath: The, I mean, guess it's tricky 'cause everything's gonna be a save.
Delwath: Right And she's gonna have like between two and three legendary resistances, although they are
Delwath: one a day sort of th- They're a, they're i- they are acts a day sort of things, right?
Delwath: So burn it. I mean, it's not like she gets them back if we fight her later.
Seeker: So the, they're imprisonment, magic circle, and
Unknown: binding. But magic circle doesn't work on dragons, does it?
Delwath: I don't think so. Imprisonment is good though.
DM: But you have no idea how to use it
Unknown: No. We'd have to just guess a combination of stones We'd have to guess the combination of stones
Seeker: Which I would like to do, to be honest, but-
Delwath: That like pro- imprisonment's like a super powerful and does what it says.
DM: That's what kept Frogar trapped
Unknown: Yeah, yeah Oh, fuck. We could do that.
Kenzo: Why don't we do that?
DM: 'Cause like there's a high chance that it imprisons Seeker or-
Delwath: Seeker can know how to do it
DM: ... if Slager doesn't know how to do it.
Unknown: That's what's up
DM: So you just guess
Delwath: And, and also chances are fairly high that, I mean, it's gotta have a save, right?
Delwath: It's not just gonna auto work, I don't think.
Delwath: And if it has a save, she'll burn a le- legendary resistance on it.
Delwath: Now, that's useful 'cause it means she has one less later, but
Delwath: it doesn't,
Delwath: it doesn't actually imprison. It doesn't result in her being imprisoned, right?
Kenzo: So here, here's another question.
Kenzo: Um, assuming that she's an extra dimensional portal, which is pretty likely,
Delwath: what are our escape routes? Well, if she's in an extra dimensional portal, the Rainbow Bridge should absolutely work.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: What, can we teleport out of an extra dimensional portal?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: It's only the Rainbow Bridge
Kenzo: Pretty much nothing but the Rainbow Bridge is our escape But if the Rainbow Bridge, if, if we put that there, then what happens?
Kenzo: We have bridge appears to Vindristjarna And, but she can also get on the bridge.
Kenzo: She could But I mean, that would be to our advantage obviously.
Kenzo: Yeah But so then
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: But how long does the bridge stay there?
Kenzo: Just forever It stays until we end it So we could, we could put it there just...
Kenzo: And, and is it a bonus action? How do we, what's the- It's an action It's an action It's a magic action to activate And, and it can only, Seeker do it?
Unknown: Um Or can I do it? I thought anybody can do it
DM: Anybody can do it. It doesn't require attunement.
DM: Whoever's holding the crystal
Unknown: Yeah
DM: It's like a prism that you carry around, but-
Kenzo: Yeah, but who's, who's carrying it?
Delwath: Seeker usually carries it
Unknown: Okay
Delwath: But any of us could carry it
Unknown: Okay. Okay
Unknown: Right
Kenzo: I mean, so we could just, we could just even, you know,
Delwath: put that there whenever I mean, we could just run a, while Be's invisible, climbs or clambers around her, her horde trying to find the jade.
Delwath: As soon as he gets it, we just Rainbow Bridge out.
Kenzo: Dude, seriously Keep her talking Seriously
Seeker: So it's just about stalling
Kenzo: Seriously, I like that a lot.
Delwath: I actually really like that a lot I mean, she might be able to see invisible, but Wellby can also hide Yeah.
Delwath: Right But I like that a lot So invisibility just helps.
Kenzo: It doesn't- I like that a lot
Seeker: I think that's an interesting thought
Kenzo: I think just, man, I mean, if we have to fight, we gotta fight, but it just, this just feels, this feels, this feels pretty nasty I mean, it's all coming in with the idea that
Delwath: we're... I mean, to some extent it goes back to the plan of let's honestly plan on making a trade But no, right?
Kenzo: Like no, 'cause the only thing that we have worth trading is access-
Seeker: More pieces of jade
Kenzo: No, not more pieces of the... I mean, I think the only thing that's worth that, like is, is the access to the Divinity Forge But
Seeker: she would trade probably for Vindristjarna, not that we're gonna sell that She would I, I actually think we have lots of things we could trade.
Delwath: We could, we could
Kenzo: What could we trade for the jade? Wow, I think Apollyon's throne is one thing But she's not, that's not, it's not magical.
Kenzo: She's not gonna do that with straight up- I don't know.
Delwath: I think you're making a deep assumption about what she cares about.
Unknown: It doesn't-
DM: We don't know what she cares about
Delwath: It doesn't mean that I'm wrong I know, I know, but- I mean, it doesn't mean that Apollyon's throne is right, but It's, it's possible Right It's possible Um,
Unknown: but-
Seeker: And like in, like in any good negotiation, you want a bunch of things in your pocket
Kenzo: But I'm just asking what else do we have other than Apollyon's throne?
Delwath: Um, I mean, we have a pile of magic i- We have a long sword of h- I mean, we have tons of magic items we don't use.
Delwath: We have a long sword of heroism.
Delwath: We have, uh, I was looking earlier, like we have a bunch of mag- of decent magic items that we don't, that we're not currently using.
Delwath: Okay. All right Right? And we also have a lot of treasure.
Delwath: I mean, if we wanted to give her piles of gold and jewels, we have piles of gold and jewels,
Delwath: right? Okay So I mean, the three directions of things we could offer is something psychologically valuable like Apollyon's throne, but that only works if she
Delwath: like, I mean, she might love the idea of sitting on Apollyon's throne and being like, "Ha ha, I'm better than you," right?
Delwath: Totally Or she might not care, but like
Seeker: the one- She's concerned with status
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: She does seem to be concerned with status, right?
Delwath: Like having a powerful throne might excite her quite a bit Totally.
Kenzo: No, totally, totally Ego stroking for her feels like a big deal.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: Ac- actually, that's actually a pretty, like-
Delwath: So that's the theory on the throne
Unknown: ... we, we
Delwath: ... is it's very ego stroking.
Kenzo: But also, like we can negotiate with her in like a very, like we know that you're the, you know, like appease to her ego, be like, "You know, you're this like great, you know, powerful dragon."
DM: But this is what, what Ghesh said, is she's like a, you know, she's a-
Unknown: She's Trump
Unknown: ... she's a boss, but she's, she's, yeah
Kenzo: ... she's, she's easy to manipulate.
Delwath: She's easy to manipulate.
Delwath: Yeah, totally.
Delwath: She's easy to manipulate, that's right.
Kenzo: She is a trump of dragons.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: And-
Kenzo: This is actually incredibly important
Delwath: ... we throw in, like if we get any hint that actually she cares a little bit about Apollyon's defeat, we can add that we're asking for a fairly trivial trinket.
Delwath: It's just one piece of jade.
Delwath: It's critical to helping kill Apollyon.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But it's not like we're gonna replace it tenfold.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: Right?
Delwath: Hell, we could offer to come back and give it to her once Apollyon's dead, and then just come back and kill her instead.
Delwath: So...
Kenzo: Hold on. But, but this is, this is... I think this is an incredibly important insight, the, the, that she's the trump of dragons.
Delwath: Yeah.
Seeker: And then how do you manipulate?
Kenzo: Yeah. How do we... This, this is...
Kenzo: Schwartz, we're, we're in a good place.
Kenzo: So we're, we're reminding that, that she's the trump of dragons.
Kenzo: Very ego focused, extremely easy to manipulate 'cause she's like, you know, extremely predictable in that way.
Kenzo: So let's, uh, we're just, now we're gaming through, like how do we, how do we leverage that to our advantage?
DM: All right. Let's keep the rest of this conversation to like 15 minutes.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah [laughs].
Delwath: We've been going for a while.
Seeker: Sure. It's, it's fun, but we're kinda stalling here.
Delwath: It's helpful.
Kenzo: No, but it's also just like, like how's it gonna end other than us like fighting her in a fucking acid bath, you know what I mean?
Kenzo: That's just like, just the...
Kenzo: So, so anyways, we're thinking that actually a trade very well could work, right?
Delwath: [laughs]
Kenzo: 'Cause we got a bunch of stuff. We got things that can like, you know, uh, uh, uh, you know, be ego stroking.
Kenzo: Like the throne's gonna be something she'll, she'll like a lot, you know?
Seeker: We could like name drop Fausto.
Seeker: Say like, "We've hung out with Fausto.
Seeker: Like we could give you an intro."
Seeker: Just think about Trump and d- other dictators.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Kenzo: Well, it's also like, you know, like what do drag- like what does, what do egotistic drag- egotistical dragons want?
Kenzo: They want more money.
Kenzo: Do they want power? Do they want like their name to be spread across the...
Kenzo: Like is she, is she satisfied like just being on this little circular island where nobody else knows even that the island exists?
Seeker: That's a good question.
Kenzo: Or does she want-
Delwath: Ooh. Ooh
Kenzo: ... you know, or is it like, you know, does she wanna be like-
Delwath: But she has a reason for being here, though we don't know what it is.
Kenzo: That's... Oh, that's the other thing.
Delwath: Right?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: But it's clearly enough to keep...
Delwath: I mean, I don't think there's any ev- Well, although it's tricky because the vibe was prisoner guard flipping back and forth.
Delwath: So we don't know if there's some magic.
Delwath: I mean, for all we know, she's been geased to
Delwath: perform this task and is not actually able to not perform it.
Kenzo: Okay, look, I, I think, I think what is becoming clear is-
Delwath: I hope
Kenzo: ... okay, number one, um, we gotta have an audience.
Kenzo: We need to talk with her, and in that conversation, we need to learn about this, this captured guard thing.
Kenzo: We need to understand more about like what she cares about, like, you know?
Kenzo: We do know the ego stroking thing, which is good, so we can definitely leverage that.
Kenzo: But there's a, so there's a cha- And the other thing we're thinking about too is the Wellby is invisible and stealthy, and is just once we get into the, the thing, just you just go fucking find the jade, and then we rammer burst out.
Wellby: That's really interesting.
Kenzo: Right? You just, we just find it, steal it, and then just go.
Delwath: Yep. Bilbo it.
Unknown: Right? So-
Delwath: Bilbo it.
Unknown: Bilbo it.
Kenzo: Bilbo it. Exactly.
Kenzo: Exactly. Bilbo it. But I think we need an audience,
Kenzo: and she's not gonna talk to us outside.
Kenzo: We might be able to get her to come outside the lair.
Kenzo: Like just directly-
Delwath: Is it worth-
Kenzo: ... outside the, the pool.
Delwath: Is it worth trying to have two audiences?
Delwath: In other words, is it worth being like-
Kenzo: Oh, that's interesting
Delwath: ... right, like, like get an audience, right, outside her lair-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... but then come back with the treasure?
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Delwath: Right? 'Cause then we could get a little bit of, uh-
Kenzo: Learn some stuff and then be like, "Okay."
Delwath: Try and learn a little bit about her.
Delwath: Like-
Kenzo: I like that
Delwath: ... like have a negotiation and then-
Wellby: That could play to her ego too.
Wellby: We're here,
Wellby: but we wouldn't dream of going to the other side of the island without your permission as the undisputed ruler of all.
Unknown: Mm. Mm-hmm.
Unknown: You know?
Delwath: But-
Kenzo: I mean, yeah, and, and but, but we do have some insights into, into, you know, what's there.
Kenzo: But, okay.
Wellby: So you want us to pick anything up for you while you're out?
Kenzo: So here's another question.
Kenzo: Okay, I like that a lot. So then we break it up into two things.
Kenzo: So there's an initial negotiation.
Kenzo: We set some terms, and then maybe she's like, cool with us going, you know, going to the island to get the things or going to the west to get the things.
Kenzo: Do we reveal that the...
Kenzo: 'Cause we do have an advantage that she doesn't know about any of you all except for me.
Kenzo: Do we, do we save that for like the reveal at the end?
Kenzo: If I, if I know, like try to get some stuff, you know?
Delwath: Do we have...
Delwath: So-
Unknown: This is interesting
Delwath: ... interesting. Hold on.
Delwath: So one question would be how much time, how many days until Apollyon?
Unknown: 10.
Delwath: 9, 10?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: 10 days.
Delwath: And it's the morning.
Unknown: It's the morning.
Kenzo: No, but I can say I've got means of magic to get me to the tower and back.
Delwath: No, no, I know, but-
Delwath: I'll be back by the end of the day.
Delwath: Yes. It's just there's a lot of bouncing around.
Delwath: [object clattering] Like do we wanna use animal shape and fl- Like there's just a lot of potential hoofing it around, especially if we wanna spend some time with the dragonettes to like-
Unknown: What-
Delwath: ... get info and-
Kenzo: What, what, why do we, what do you mean dragonettes and getting info?
Kenzo: This, this approach would be like-
Delwath: Wouldn't we-
Kenzo: ... telling Gresh, "Hey, I want an audi-" Like-
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: You know?
Delwath: But even just going from here to Gresh and then from Gresh to her lair is gonna take us half the day.
Unknown: But that's-
Unknown: But we still need an audience
Wellby: ... I need some, I need some shade. Do you wanna slide over?
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: I'm also-
Seeker: We can just go inside.
DM: We can maybe just go inside now.
Delwath: [grunts] Right.
Delwath: So then I would suggest we start by let's keep
Delwath: the rest of us a secret.
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: Just Kenzo.
Unknown: Yep. [coughs]
Delwath: Uh, is it worth...
Delwath: I think we probably don't want...
Delwath: We probably all have to be there for the audience, though.
Unknown: Totally.
Delwath: Like it's too dangerous to just send Kenzo.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: 'Cause then if she turns, you're just gonna die.
Kenzo: Well, no, but also like, you know, if, if we decide like, oh, it's better to just ambush right now-
Delwath: Yeah, yeah
Kenzo: ... we just go do it.
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: You know?
Delwath: But so that means the three of us could be invisible.
Delwath: [sneezes]... right?
Kenzo: Yeah. Or turn into animals
Delwath: Or turn into animals.
Delwath: It does mean that there's always a chance she'll detect us.
Unknown: Yeah, or there's like-
Delwath: Right
Wellby: ... an anti-magic field on the way in where she can see invisible.
Delwath: Uh, well, turn into animals is an interesting idea because they-
Unknown: Hmm
Delwath: ... see invisible would help.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Right?
Delwath: Now, if she says, "Hey, I see you have some companions,"
Delwath: I mean, is that-
Unknown: I think that's also fine
Delwath: I think it's okay. We learned something.
Delwath: We learned she can detect us, right?
Delwath: I think actually animal shape makes the most sense just as like innocent creatures, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And then
Delwath: if she calls us on it,
Delwath: I mean, what's the wor- the worst that'll happen is she calls us on it and refuses to bargain 'cause we've been cheating, and then we just have to-
Kenzo: Just then we just go fucking fight her.
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, at that point, potentially just-
Kenzo: The worst, the worst case scenario in all this is we barge in like we always do, head first, and tr- you know, like trigger all the traps, you know, and just absorb all the
Kenzo: things and then, you know. That's what, that's the worst case scenario.
Delwath: Right.
Kenzo: Right? Which, you know, feels [laughs] not unreasonable.
Unknown: Plausible.
Delwath: Which, which feels like kind of like at the end of the day-
Unknown: That's probably what's gonna happen
Delwath: ... that's like our default plan.
Unknown: All right. Let's, I think this is good.
Delwath: All right.
Unknown: Let's go do this.
Delwath: So, so we animal shape.
Delwath: So the plan here, let's just make sure we're all on the same page.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: The plan here is we animal shape.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: Kenzo flies back to Ghesh and tells Ghesh that we-
Unknown: I
Delwath: ... that I, Kenzo, have a way in, a safe way into the tower on the west,
Delwath: and some magic to defeat its magic,
Delwath: but wants to pre-agree with Ra'ghemdros what the payment, like doesn't want to go steal her stuff-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... without her awareness-
Delwath: ... that I'm going to get her stuff, right?
Unknown: No, but I know it's there.
Delwath: But you know it's there. No, no, no.
Wellby: I, I've gone-
Delwath: You want to get in. You know it's there
Kenzo: ... I've scouted it out. I know it's there.
Delwath: You can, you can say I know that Pol- like throw out a couple possibilities like Apollyon's throne, some interesting magic, piles of gems.
Delwath: She would... See what she's most interested in.
Unknown: There you go.
Delwath: Right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: She might say, "I want all of them."
Delwath: She probably will say they're all mine.
Delwath: But try and use insight to see what-
Unknown: Totally. Totally, yeah
Delwath: ... piques her interest the most.
Unknown: Exactly.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And then that, that he wants an audience.
Kenzo: But, but humbly, there's only one thing that I want in exchange.
Kenzo: There's o- you know, like, you know, there's, th- this is...
Kenzo: You know, if, if you're interested in a trade, right?
Delwath: Right. And even more than that, it's a, I realize it's a very large request to be asking for you to part with even the smallest trinket-
Unknown: Mm
Delwath: ... from your horde.
Unknown: Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: But save that for the audience, right?
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Delwath: I think from Ghesh's perspective, it's-
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... the story is just I know how to get there, I know how to safely get there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And I want an audience.
Delwath: But maybe like something about your magic, you're worried that the magic you're gonna use to defeat the, the,
Delwath: um, traps of the tower-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
Delwath: ... won't, it won't, it'll get, it won't work if you have to go through a dimensional portal.
Unknown: Huh?
Delwath: Give her an excuse to meet out of her lair and learn if it's in another dimension.
DM: Oh, that's a good idea.
Delwath: Tell her that the magic you're gonna use, tell Ghesh the magic you're gonna use to defeat Apollyon's traps-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
Delwath: ... won't, you won't be able to hold onto it.
Unknown: It'll be dispelled if you go through it.
Delwath: It'll be dispelled if you go through a portal.
Seeker: Uh, I didn't know that was a thing.
Delwath: It's not.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: So who cares? I mean, it should be.
Delwath: It could be a thing.
Unknown: Maybe it isn't.
Delwath: 'Cause then-
Seeker: For all she knows
Delwath: ... she might say, "Come to my lair anyway," which gives us a clue that either she doesn't believe you or it's not an extra-dimensional portal.
Seeker: I think that's cool.
Delwath: Or she might just buy it and meet you on the surface.
Wellby: I love this. This feels good.
Delwath: Right?
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: So we're on the surface, we're animals.
Delwath: And then we're gonna be animals, and we're gonna be like little tropic birds or something just flying around nearby, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Possibly, like, play it as your animal scouts or like animals that you actually have so that we can be-
Delwath: We're like your animal scouts, right?
Unknown: That's works.
Delwath: So-
Unknown: That also works
Delwath: ... so we can like fly by and be around.
Delwath: We're like the birds who have scouted.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Right?
Unknown: This is great.
Delwath: So that's why we're like hovering right over your head.
Unknown: And we'll be different animals?
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: You have like a eagle on your arm.
Wellby: You have, um, a raven next to you.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: Totally. Totally.
Unknown: That's great.
Delwath: So we're like three of... We're like your animal companions, and then if she senses some magic from us-
Unknown: That's what they are
Delwath: ... totally plausible.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Right?
Kenzo: That's great. That's great.
Wellby: This is the greatest cover story we've ever come up with.
Kenzo: That's great. Okay.
DM: Uh, the only problem is you need to re-up telepathy every hour.
Delwath: Right.
DM: And you can't do it in bird form.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: We can't be in telepathy in bird form?
Delwath: No.
Unknown: No.
Delwath: We can.
Unknown: But you can't re-up.
Delwath: But you can't re-up.
Unknown: Oh, but this conversation-
Delwath: 'Cause that applies-
Unknown: ... is gonna be like minutes.
Delwath: It's-
Seeker: Well, hopefully that... Yeah
DM: ... but you need a way to have Seeker not be in bird form.
Unknown: I, I can-
Delwath: No, no, no.
Unknown: To, to, to reach up the telepathy.
Delwath: We just... You mean-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... you mean because we're worried about the time, like won't we know the time of-
Delwath: Oh, the time of... Yeah. Okay.
Delwath: Like in theory-
Unknown: Leading time, yeah
Delwath: ... we know what time she's supposed, we're supposed to meet there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah. All right, let's-
Delwath: Like presumably she's gonna tell us to come to-
Kenzo: The lair
Delwath: ... the lair
Seeker: At this, at this stage we have an idea for the approach.
Seeker: We do not know what's gonna happen-
Delwath: Yeah
Seeker: ... after our initial steps-
Delwath: Okay. Let's, yeah
Seeker: ... so we should just do the first step. [laughs]
Unknown: Okay. So Kenzo flies down.
Unknown: Well, Kenzo-
Delwath: Don't want anything out. Sorry. Um,
Delwath: are we-
Seeker: Pick your birds
Wellby: If we run out of telepathy, you can also play it as let me consult my animal companions and
Wellby: message it to me. I can-
Kenzo: I mean, we're not gonna... We're, that's not gonna be a problem, though.
Delwath: But we've got a backup.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: We can-
Unknown: That's true
Delwath: ... I mean, can... I mean,
Delwath: can Wellby still telepathy in bird form?
DM: I don't know. That's a good question.
Seeker: We played it that he could yesterday.
Seeker: Yeah. We didn't, I didn't read the spell.
Seeker: So by precedent. [laughs]
Unknown: By precedent.
Unknown: Yes. Um-
Kenzo: That would make sense that you could still access the fucking-
Unknown: So I think-
Delwath: I think it's up, Tim, I don't think it matters what the spell says.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I think it's up to your decision about the essence of the halfling soul-
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: ... and whether it works still in bird form.
DM: Um.
Delwath: I think he's a bird with a halfling soul, so he can, but that's just my call.
Wellby: Oh, so I get a soul?
Unknown: I... [laughs]
Delwath: You do.
Kenzo: It's only the hawk that can sense.
Delwath: Humans have the best souls in the whole world.
Unknown: The fuck?
Delwath: Yeah, they have really powerful souls that can create gods.
Delwath: Nobody else can do that.
Unknown: That's the nicest thing you've said all day.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: I didn't know elves thought that.
Delwath: Why it's so important to protect them.
DM: Yeah, it, it... You retain all your mental statistics and your alignment, so I think it's reasonable.
Kenzo: Really quick, uh, um, the, uh, uh, s- say the thing about the extradimensional portal again thing.
Delwath: So the idea is that you tell Ghesh that you can't...
Delwath: The magic, you have a magic ability that you've created-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
Delwath: ... that will let you defeat the magic.
Kenzo: My staff. I have a magic staff.
Delwath: You have a magic staff.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: There's something you've enchanted from this island.
Delwath: You've, like, put some power from this island into your staff that will dispel the magic protecting Apollyon's tower.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: But-
Unknown: Actually, the spell specifically says you retain your ability to communicate.
Delwath: But if you take your...
Delwath: If you travel to another portal, if you travel to another dimension-
DM: You probably don't want to make it your staff
Delwath: ... don't make it your staff, 'cause then you could-
DM: Yeah, because that's what you just said
Delwath: ... have to lose your staff. Your tattoo.
Unknown: My tattoo. My tattoo.
Delwath: Your tattoo.
Delwath: Perfect. Perfect. Yeah.
Delwath: So if you leave this dimension, if you go to any extradimensional space, the magic's dismissed.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: And you won't be able to go to the to-
DM: [coughs]
Delwath: You won't be able to dispel the magic of the tower.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm. But, but I'm telling her this...
Delwath: So that she comes out of her lair.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: 'Cause the theory is her lair is an extradimensional portal.
DM: And if, and if she doesn't come out of her lair, then you know that she's using mind link instead of being in a different dimension.
Delwath: Right.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: If she doesn't come out either-
Wellby: And we all go in with you.
Delwath: Right. If she doesn't come out, then we assume it's because-
Kenzo: And I, but it's, I need, I need to tell this to Ghesh.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: And so the Ghesh will then-
Delwath: And if she tells us to come into her lair, you can still bring us in animal form because we're your animal companions-
Unknown: Great
Delwath: ... who know all... You need to be able to consult us, 'cause we're the ones who scouted.
Unknown: All right. Let's do it.
Delwath: So if she has a specific question about, like, what the hell is in the palace.
Kenzo: Oh, is the, is the... You still recorded the audio, though?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, it's still recording.
Kenzo: All right. Let's do this shit.
Seeker: Okay. So-
Unknown: Let's go
Seeker: ... bird choices.
DM: [laughs] The most important decision.
Delwath: It really is.
Wellby: I think we should be animals that reflect who our characters are.
Unknown: That's what I'm saying.
Wellby: So like, you could be a lynx.
Delwath: No, probably a smaller cat, right?
Delwath: What would be native to here that would be good at-
Seeker: It doesn't have to be native to here, 'cause it came-
Delwath: That's true
Seeker: ... it came with Kenzo.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Oh, that's true.
Unknown: We could be similar.
Delwath: Sure. Yeah.
Delwath: Like a little-
Unknown: Be a, be a-
Delwath: ... little bobcat.
Kenzo: Little bobcat?
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: Uh, osprey?
Seeker: I'm inclined to just keep the, like, dire hawk or whatever I had from yesterday.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: [coughs] That's fine.
Unknown: That's great. Yeah.
DM: That was a pretty good one.
Seeker: It's, like, dark red feathers-
Delwath: Yeah
Seeker: ... a huge beak, very big talons.
Unknown: Kind of-
DM: Still one, one feather is white.
Seeker: One... Exactly.
Seeker: Thank you. Yep. One-
Delwath: Why do you have a white feather?
Seeker: It's from my Feywild adventure I-
Delwath: Oh
Unknown: ... lost.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: He traded a color of the strand of his hair for-
Unknown: Oh, that's cool
DM: ... a strand... What does it do?
DM: It lets you know when the sunset is or something?
Seeker: Yeah, yeah. The...
Delwath: Right. But didn't it let him travel through the portal, too?
DM: Ah, yes, because you need to know when sunset is on Calgar.
Delwath: Calgar. To open it.
Delwath: Because that's when the portals open.
Kenzo: Right. Right. All right, let's do this shit.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: So let's, um, let's go, uh, um-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
Kenzo: ... uh, Kenzo... Well, actually, you, we're, you're not gonna change.
Kenzo: Well, actually, you can change into animals now.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Because it's been 24 hours of day.
Delwath: It's 24 hours.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: We'll just do the-
Kenzo: So you change into animals now. And in fact, you should come with me as the animals so that Ghesh even know, you know.
Delwath: Ah.
Unknown: You know what I mean?
Delwath: That's a great idea.
Kenzo: So then it's just, like, it's even more of a thing.
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: Right? Sorry.
DM: So you probably all want to be fast flying birds-
Delwath: We'll be fast flying birds
DM: ... to get in the tower and then shift-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... when you're close.
Seeker: Oh, we can always just change back.
Unknown: And Ghesh also knows-
Delwath: You turn into great snipes, which are the...
Delwath: I looked this up.
Unknown: The fastest.
Delwath: The fast- the fastest birds. They can go, like, 30 miles an hour.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: And Ghesh also knows I can fly, 'cause we also raced each other before.
Delwath: Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Perfect. All right.
Kenzo: That's true.
Kenzo: So I'll fly over to Ghesh with my, with my, uh, uh, my bird friends.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: you know, say hello, give him some shit.
DM: Yeah. He's... So he's actually, he's, um...
DM: Uh, so this is morning.
Kenzo: Oh, 'cause has he, has he already gone?
Unknown: Has he-
DM: He's just, he's j- So by the time you get there, it's actually probably, what, like 11:00 or something.
Unknown: Sure.
DM: 'Cause you spend some time, breakfast-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... so everybody inspiration and-
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Um, and, you know, flying even as a fast flying bird still is gonna take an, you know, an hour to
DM: say an hour, but still you're...
Delwath: So it's, like, 11:00.
Delwath: I mean, we just spent an hour plotting too.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. Right. Right.
DM: So it's, like, 11:00 when you get to, to Ghesh, and he's actually, he's super happy.
Unknown: How are you, my friend?
DM: He's just returned.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: 9:00 AM this morning he was summoned.
DM: He w- or, like, at dawn this morning he was summoned to the lair.
Unknown: Uh-huh.
DM: He returns just an hour ago, and he's wearing ano- one of these little amulets-
Unknown: Uh-huh. Uh-huh
DM: ... um, that Murg- Mirgen was wearing.
Delwath: So like-
Delwath: Looking-
DM: ... "This is mine now.
Delwath: All mine."
Kenzo: Which place?
DM: Same place he was before.
Unknown: Uh-huh.
DM: But now he doesn't have to worry about anybody bossing him around to, like-
Unknown: Right
Delwath: ... drive him out.
DM: Um, I w- I was just, I just came back from, from talking to, um,
DM: Mirgen. We're gonna... Uh, she's got some ideas for how to improve this place.
Kenzo: Wow. Well, look at you, Ren.
DM: It's gonna be awesome. You wanna stick around?
Kenzo: Kenzo gives a little, like, you know, a little, uh, little, little pound to his, like, little beak or his little, you know, dragon-
Delwath: He's got little dragon paws
Kenzo: ... little, little dragon fists, like.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: I, I like it, moving up in the, m- moving up in the world.
Kenzo: Feeling pretty good, huh? It's been a good morning?
DM: Oh, it's been a great morning.
DM: Got any more treasure for me?
Kenzo: Well, uh, you know, it's interesting that you ask.
Kenzo: Um, I had a, a, a pretty big day yesterday, um, investigating some stuff out in the west.
Unknown: You're saying that-
Delwath: Ooh
Kenzo: ... you're saying that, uh, the west is a little-
Delwath: Wait, the west?
Unknown: The west.
DM: You must be stronger than I thought.
Kenzo: I told you I could beat you in flying.
Kenzo: I mean, you're, you're, you know, you're not, you weren't that good at flying.
Kenzo: You felt pretty confident about yourself in that, but-
DM: You have to be a little more than a good flyer to go out there.
Unknown: Well, d- so just why...
Kenzo: What's the deal again? Why, why, why does nobody want to go out there?
DM: 'Cause Ra'ghramdos told us not to.
Kenzo: You don't know what she's scared about there?
Unknown: Well, she said it...
DM: Something might notice us.
Kenzo: She said what?
Delwath: No.
Delwath: Why would she tell me that?
Unknown: Huh, that's interesting.
Kenzo: Uh, telepathy?
Wellby: Statues?
Unknown: Giant sword.
Wellby: Shoot darts.
Delwath: Void sword. But the statues are...
Delwath: would also
Unknown: I w- I mean-
Delwath: Medication
Wellby: ... I would love if we missed, like, the true slumbering great evil under the temple.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: I mean, just... But no, but really, like, she's not scared of two fucking CR 13.
Delwath: She wouldn't be, no. She might be scared of the sword.
Kenzo: All right. Well, anyways, let's come back to that one.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: but yeah, I, I went out there.
Kenzo: I had a, I had a really interesting, uh, visit out there.
Unknown: And, um,
Kenzo: Ghesh, I'll be honest, I think, um, there's some things out there that, uh...
Kenzo: What's her name again, the dragon?
Delwath: Ra'ghemdros.
Kenzo: Ra- I think that Ra'ghemdros is gonna be very, very interested and about.
Kenzo: And given how great she is, and that she is the boss around here,
Kenzo: um, I wanted to ask for your help again to see if, uh,
Kenzo: I could have an audience.
DM: Yeah, definitely. And I think, like, given you've already given the plan, like, he's ha- I mean-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... he's, he's pretty...
Delwath: He's in a great mood right now.
Kenzo: He's, he's glad we're... You know, we got a, we got a vibe.
DM: And you got a vibe.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And he's, like, pretty grateful for you.
DM: He's, like, totally happy.
Unknown: All right.
DM: You know, he's not really friends with any true believers, but he can get a message across.
Unknown: Okay. Okay.
DM: It'll take a few hours for somebody to fly to his lair, fly back.
Unknown: That's fine.
DM: You know? He's, he wants to, like, hang out and gamble and chill for a bit.
Unknown: Right, right, right.
Delwath: And have some food.
Kenzo: Here's a question for us, though.
Kenzo: If this does turn into, like, dragonet, like, madness, do we want some, you know, potential support from him and his allies?
Kenzo: Which I think we do.
Delwath: Well, we'd have to let him in on that-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... this is a secret plan.
Kenzo: Well, I mean, less the secret plan and more just, um, um,
Kenzo: you know, we found some stuff, or I found some stuff.
Kenzo: Uh, what's the angle here?
Delwath: The only angle I can think of off the top of my head would be actually tell him that,
Delwath: that
Delwath: if
Delwath: Ra'ghemdros...
Delwath: If we-
Unknown: If it goes south
Delwath: ... if it, if it does-
Kenzo: If it goes south,
Unknown: um,
Kenzo: then there's m- And this is genuinely true.
Kenzo: If there's more in it for you,
Kenzo: we can take her out and then you can have more, uh-
Delwath: I, I, I think we'd want to be like...
Delwath: I mean, it would be a risk for him.
Delwath: But it may not be a huge risk because-
Unknown: This is only if it goes south
Delwath: ... if it doesn't go south, then nothing, then the trade goes out and it's fine.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But the, but the, but the, but the suggestion would be do you have some people...
Delwath: I mean, you could even... The cover story would be,
Delwath: you know,
Delwath: can you get some dragonet, you know, some of your people to show us where the lair is?
Delwath: Like, you know, you came with these, with Ghesh because you're comfortable with him and blah, blah, blah.
Delwath: And what you'd actually tell Ghesh is, "If this go- there's a possibility we're gonna fight her, and could you bring, like, 20 of your dragonets to, like, support us if it happens?"
Delwath: But you have to tell him that there's a possibility we're gonna fight her.
Wellby: If I was him, I would not believe that you could single-handedly defeat a dragon, and anyone who fought on your side would be exterminated.
Wellby: Like, that's a... It feels like a big lift.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Well, it would almost be like if it...
Delwath: It would almost... I think what you'd have to tell him is, "Come
Delwath: if, if you think...
Delwath: if you see an opportunity to help."
Delwath: 'Cause, like, once we all turn into ourselves and are, like, do real damage, maybe he would...
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, it's a, it... [sighs]
Kenzo: But this, I mean, you know, it's marginal benefit, right?
Kenzo: It's like, you know, it's like...
Kenzo: Well, all the dr- the, like, the 100 dragonets are flying around where?
DM: Around the, the tow- around the city area.
Kenzo: Which is far from here.
DM: It's, like, seven miles.
Unknown: Yeah. So whatever,
Kenzo: right? Who cares?
Delwath: I mean, she ha- she definitely has the heart.
Unknown: She has some.
Delwath: She has some there.
Kenzo: I mean, the most we're gonna get is-
Delwath: I mean, you'll see when you get there.
Kenzo: Yeah. The, the most we're gonna get is, like, him and his friends here.
Kenzo: It's gonna be him and, and, you know, it's gonna be, like, 20 of them.
Delwath: Right. But 20 of them might be equivalent to even more than the ones that she has at her lair,
Delwath: right? So the theory would be if we actually were having a combat above ground-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... and she had 20 dragonets and four m- chimera, chimeras-
Delwath: ... and herself, and we had 20 dragonets who would be only...
Delwath: We wouldn't be expecting them to do anything except to distract and attack.
Kenzo: That would be helpful.
Delwath: Right? It would keep the 20 dragonets from, like, causing us a lot of trouble.
Delwath: But-
Unknown: But would they risk their lives?
Delwath: I think they would only risk their lives if it looked like we might actually win.
Delwath: Like, we'd have to show pretty strong attack right away so that all of a sudden they thought...
Delwath: I mean, clearly they would be better off with her dead,
Delwath: but they'd be a lot worse off trying to kill her and failing,
Delwath: right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So-
Unknown: That's fair
Delwath: ... so what are you doing?
Kenzo: Uh, let's, uh, this is, this is, this is too soon.
Delwath: I mean, if you trust, if we trust Ghesh enough to not t- give us, to not, like, sell us out, you just leave it up to him.
Wellby: I don't, I don't, I don't trust him that much.
Delwath: You could drop the hint and just see what he does with it.
Unknown: No.
Delwath: But that would give him the option of selling us out, which might be bad.
Kenzo: Fuck it. Let's not do it. Let's just, let's just go.
DM: Okay. So a round one, um, three dragonets show up to escort you to the lair.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Like, three of the true believers.
Delwath: So at this point-
Kenzo: And I, and I've, and I have... Uh, I'm assuming I've explained to you just so that they're not alarmed, you know, like I went-
Delwath: Yeah
Kenzo: ... with some of my scouting animal friends.
Delwath: Right.
Unknown: You know?
DM: So at this point you're in your...
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Your, your birds.
Delwath: And so I can't-
Delwath: Oh, I should probably be a bird too, actually.
Delwath: And I can't really-
Unknown: I'm gonna be, like, a...
Seeker: I can't really make the ladder part of this.
Seeker: Oh, maybe I could animate...
Seeker: Can I Performance of Creation some kind of...
Seeker: I could do a faldrik
Seeker: ... a mechanical bird and animate that
DM: Well, it's gonna take you at least an hour to get to the lair from here.
DM: It's seven miles away.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Like, it depends on how fast Kenzo can fly.
DM: I mean, it depends on how fast Kenzo can move, right?
Unknown: Right. But Kenzo moves pretty fast.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Well, you can't, you're-
Delwath: But you can't fly
DM: ... wait, you'd have to transform into a bird in order to be able to cover the distance.
DM: So it depends on whether you want to do that.
Wellby: You could do that, though. You have that magic.
Delwath: But to transform into a bird, Seeker would have to un-transform into a bird, which would...
DM: Oh, Seeker needs to do the action to...
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So it's a bit complicated. So it's probably gonna take you, like, an hour and a half to cover the distance.
Kenzo: At, with Raven's whistle?
DM: Raven's whistle doesn't last long enough.
Delwath: Yeah.
Delwath: And you don't want to burn up your charges on Raven's whistle, 'cause we might need it if we're fighting.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Then let's, sorry, then let's, then how do we get there?
Unknown: I mean, you walk. I mean, Kenzo's a pretty fast walker, right?
DM: But-
Unknown: Yeah, I'll, I'll run.
Delwath: Wait, hold on. Seven miles, an hour and a half?
Delwath: That's not a fast walker.
Unknown: No, but-
Delwath: That's why it would take... That's like three miles an hour
Seeker: ... depends on the terrain. No, but I can-
Delwath: Yeah, I know. So like, I guess more than that, but.
Kenzo: But difficult terrain, I can move through like it's normal terrain.
Delwath: Can't you just jog? I mean...
Kenzo: Yeah. Dude, I'll do Jogging.
Kenzo: I'm a fucking superman.
DM: It seems unlikely that-
Delwath: You can jog
Delwath: ... Kenzo can't cover seven miles in
DM: really fast. I mean, you're limited by the speed of the dragonet escorts as well, right?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: So you're, so you can cover it in like an hour, which is how fast they can cover it.
Kenzo: That's fine. All right. So I'm, I'm running.
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... jogging, and then they're flying alongside.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: I guess if we, if you're running, I mean, a, a, a lynx can run as fast as Kenzo.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So you can be a lynx.
Unknown: A lynx.
DM: But, but it's gonna take you an hour to get there.
Delwath: It just means we can't-
DM: Which is l- because that's how fast the dragonets can fly.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: So you can't go faster than them.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: So it's gonna be hard to Performance of Creation 'cause it would go away, unfortunately.
DM: Right.
Delwath: You can't extend its duration, can you?
Seeker: Oh, no, I don't have any way to do that.
DM: You don't have a duration, just a range extension.
Delwath: If you had a double duration, that would be helpful, but...
Seeker: I requested it, but...
DM: You did?
Seeker: We talked when we were talking about the Metamagic, different possibilities.
DM: Oh, right. Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Uh, but it is a good question about telepathy too.
DM: So it's gonna run out.
Delwath: We're gonna not have telepathy.
Kenzo: Oh, we have to have telepathy.
Kenzo: So how do we do this with telepathy?
DM: You have, you have Wellby, messenger.
Delwath: Wellby relays.
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: You can talk to Wellby.
Unknown: That's fine. Okay, that works.
Delwath: Um, is there anything else?
Unknown: You just have Wellby perch on your shoulder as you go.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Scout.
Delwath: Hold on, here's a question.
Kenzo: Let me shoot little bows from your little-
Delwath: Can I, if I don't need to use verbal or somatic components, can I cast spells?
DM: You, not in animal form.
Delwath: Okay.
Delwath: You explicitly can't cast spells.
Kenzo: Does it take an action to-
DM: The actions, uh, the actions you take, you can communicate, but the actions are only the actions on your beast stat block.
Delwath: Okay, good.
Kenzo: If we, if combat begins, does turning from animals into-
DM: It's a bonus. It's a bonus action.
Kenzo: For the person?
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. For whoever's transforming.
Kenzo: Oh, interesting. Interesting, okay. So but initiative is still, like, it's not like you have animal initiative.
Kenzo: It's like you've got your initiative.
DM: Um, no, you have animal initiative, although your alert feat still triggers.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: But Kenzo would have-
Unknown: Of course
DM: ... his own.
Kenzo: Yeah. Ultra, ultra initiative.
Unknown: All right, let's fucking do this.
DM: So you run alongside as these three dragonets are flying with you.
Delwath: Oh, so Tim, can we swap lesser restoration for bravery?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Okay.
DM: I said at next long rest.
DM: Um. [coughs]
Kenzo: I don't know if you want any music either.
DM: Oh, yeah. [claps] So...
Unknown: Very exciting.
DM: You run along, um, you run, you get to this road that Seeker saw that sort of cuts through this garish red spongy moss area.
DM: You can see the, the four chimeras are, like, flying overhead, just kind of watching.
DM: But the, with the dragonet escort, they just completely ignore you.
DM: Um, you run and, and you come to this plaza, right?
DM: There's this sort of open round area, and then the two paths, one that leads up to a hill where there's a villa on the hill, and one that leads straight to the thermal
DM: baths where Ra'ghemdros' lair is.
Seeker: I wonder what that villa on the-
Delwath: That's where we're headed
Unknown: ...
Unknown: cliff does.
DM: And then you see,
DM: um, perched on top of the columns around the, um...
DM: Oh, so a few things. One, as you're approaching, one of the dragonets, like, um, flies over next to you and says, um, "The great Ra'ghemdros has agreed to your audience
DM: and even made, uh, acceded to your special request to leave her lair.
DM: There are two rules when speaking with her.
DM: Do not disobey these rules.
DM: Always let her speak first.
DM: And you might notice some discoloration in her scales.
DM: Never, never mention that in her presence."
Unknown: Oh. Vanity.
Delwath: Hmm.
DM: "If you follow these rules, you will have a successful negotiation."
Kenzo: Thank you for the guidance. It's greatly appreciated.
Delwath: Soul sight her as soon as you see her.
Kenzo: Yeah, of course. I'm gonna do even one more than that.
Delwath: Yeah, like a-
Kenzo: I never use this, I've never really used this, but I can use aura focus.
DM: That's like your normal soul sight, though.
Kenzo: That's normal s- for soul sight?
DM: Yeah, it's like your average soul sight.
Kenzo: But I get a bonus action, um, I can take it to an additional one-arm strike against anybody I'm aura focused on.
DM: That's, that's when you do the aura focus.
DM: That's like the, you can s- you can soul sight them and attack them at the same time.
Unknown: I see.
Unknown: It doesn't give you extra benefits later after you do it.
Unknown: I see. Okay. Okay. Okay, all right.
DM: It's just so you can soul sight somebody and not lose your first round of attacks.
Kenzo: Got it, got it. Okay.
DM: So you see now as you approach the thermal baths, so it's the, the, the view here is, like, you can see, like, half a mile above on the hill,
DM: um,
DM: the...
DM: [upbeat music] Half a mile up on the hill, you can see this, the sort of ruins of this villa and that's, like, half of the villa just completely leveled and the other half has the wall standing.
DM: Um- And then there's like a hill that slopes down and it's like nicely manicured and gardened and you can imagine how at one point this might have looked where
DM: the baths were sort of a, in the center of a sort of decorated garden that you could look overlooking on from the villa.
DM: Um, the baths however are almost completely destroyed.
DM: Um, the only things that you
DM: see, um...
DM: Oh,
DM: where did I put it? I have too many different
DM: notes. Um,
DM: so the only thing you can see that's, so it, it, you can imagine there used to be sort of a, a whole structure built up around these thermal baths.
DM: Um, there's like a grand entrance that has a row of columns that lead into this sort of big open colonnade area.
DM: Um, there would've normally been like a building with like changing areas and sort of, um, you know, relaxation spaces and things like that.
DM: But most of this is destroyed.
DM: The only thing that's still standing is the grand central arch that leads into the,
DM: sort of into this entryway, which is all ruined.
DM: And on the
DM: sort of keystone of the grand central arch you see, um, a,
DM: a symbol, like a stylized flame that's sitting above an open book like this that rises up, and then there's sparks on the top that sort of form
DM: sort of a semicircular crown that kind of looks like a rising or setting sun.
DM: [coughs]
Wellby: Whose symbol is that?
DM: No idea.
Delwath: Is it any... It's not Cha'mutte's.
DM: It's not Cha'mutte's, no.
Kenzo: Arcana check?
DM: Yeah, but it's-
Seeker: That'd be a history
Kenzo: ... history check.
Seeker: Okay. Can I roll history?
DM: Yeah, that's, that's on the history.
Seeker: That's a eight plus f- that's a 23.
DM: Um.
Kenzo: You have a plus 15 history check?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: He's a bard. He has plus 15 to like everything.
DM: You don't, you don't recognize the specific symbol, but it does recall to m- your mind that you've read there are many...
DM: Like Drankor was Popcus, not just like, you know, the Occulta Ludem and Omnis Pura, there was lots and lots of these like magical and some non-magical societies
DM: in Drankor. Like there were tons of them, and your best guess is this is the symbol of one of those.
Kenzo: And sorry, where is the symbol?
DM: There's like a arch that leads into the thermal bath complex.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: And it's like at the keystone of the arch.
Kenzo: Gotcha. But this is not her symbol.
Unknown: This is a-
DM: No
Seeker: It's the former owners of this
DM: ... the former owners.
Unknown: This estate. Yeah.
DM: You then see
DM: Ra'ghemdros herself perched on above the columns of the, uh, of the thermal bath, sort of looking down at this pool.
DM: Um, there's four other dragonets that are kind of flying around just, well they're actually just kind of watching.
DM: Um,
DM: she is enormous.
DM: She's probably at least 30 feet from snout to tail.
DM: Her wings are curled up, but you can imagine when outstretched they must be huge.
DM: Entirely pitch black except
DM: along her left side you can see this long, what looks like a scar that runs almost from her shoulder to her tail.
DM: It's like, it's like that wide
DM: running scar. Um, and it is shimmering with reds and oranges.
DM: It almost looks like there's a sunset burned into the side of her scales.
DM: The rest of her body, the rest of her scales, everything else is just this absolute pitch black sort of like that, um,
DM: you know, the like, I forget what it's called, the like perma-black, right?
DM: Like that sort of really-
Seeker: Oh, antimatter
DM: ... really intense black.
Seeker: Could she... I- is there f- uh, feywild magic that could cause a burn like that?
DM: Possibly.
DM: Go ahead and make an arcana check.
Kenzo: Guys, give me one please.
Kenzo: I'll take the rest of them back in a second.
Seeker: That's only an 18.
DM: I mean, sure.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Why not?
Kenzo: So my soul cider right away you can tell I don't have anything to do with it.
DM: Yep. [coughs]
Unknown: [sighs]
DM: Uh.
Delwath: Oh, hey, have you guys checked in for your flight?
Unknown: No.
Delwath: You should check in right now.
Seeker: Why, is that-
Delwath: It just opened and you get better boarding-
DM: For your Southwest
Delwath: ... for your Southwest. I mean, I bought the like pre-check-in automatically.
Delwath: I bought the early whatever it's called.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: but, uh,
Delwath: but the earlier you check in the better you get from a s- from a line up.
Delwath: It might be like not quite 6:00.
Delwath: It might be like another minute before you can
Unknown: make
Unknown: a...
Seeker: Three minutes.
Delwath: It's worth doing it as soon as you can because
Unknown: you get better boarding position.
Unknown: Cool.
Seeker: [sighs] I was just trying to make
Unknown: Cyberpunk Schwartz. [laughs]
Seeker: That's kind of funny.
DM: [laughs] Awesome.
Seeker: De- you have a De- Deershnirt-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... T-shirt
Seeker: and like a very much costume looking cybernetic arm.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Yeah
Seeker: That one's actually... Oh, Schwartz is spelled right in that one
Delwath: The, the perspective on the arm is a little funny, but
Unknown: [clears throat]
DM: Okay, so-
Unknown: It's cool
DM: ... the only light, the only thing that's not pitch black, um, is her eyes,
DM: um, which glow green when she opens them to look at you.
DM: Um, but she seems to be, um, as- so she's, so you're appro- you like, Kenza's approaching with these, um,
DM: with the three animals around him.
DM: She's sort of waiting for you to walk.
DM: The dragonets lead you into the,
DM: like the center of this thermal pool complex, and you can see there's the one big pool, which is what's been described as what leads to her lair.
DM: And then there's like, two smaller pools.
DM: It's probably like there was like the hot pool and then the cool pool, right, and warm pool, stuff like that.
DM: And you can see there once used to be extensive, um, buildings to the, to the north away, where there was probably additional sort of,
DM: you know, chambers for, for changing or for relaxation or exercise or something like that, but these have all been ruined.
DM: And she's sort of perched above.
DM: So Kenza, Sol Psychser.
Unknown: What do I see?
DM: Um,
DM: so...
DM: Where did she go? Um,
DM: she is,
DM: um, immune to acid and necrotic damage.
Unknown: What's her CR?
DM: Um, 26.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: She's immune to acid and necrotic damage.
DM: She's immune to charmed, frightened, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned and stunned.
DM: [coughs] And blinded, actually.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: Uh, sorry, read those immunities one more time.
DM: Charmed, frightened, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, stunned, blinded.
DM: Um-
Unknown: I can show it. I can
DM: ... she is,
DM: her weakest save is dex.
DM: Her strongest save is con.
Seeker: Her weakest save is dex?
DM: Yep.
DM: She is currently,
DM: although
DM: quite boastful and,
DM: um, you know, ex- sort of, you get this, a vibe almost of like a bit of undercurrent of excitement like, huh, this could be good for me.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Nice
DM: ... there's also
DM: nervousness, and she keeps glancing, Kenza would notice this, she keeps glancing at the villa.
DM: Like, her attention is mostly on the villa.
DM: She seems to only be sort of paying attention to Kenza.
Kenzo: This fits into the, her, her being captured.
Delwath: Hey, Kong, have you checked in for your flight?
Delwath: You should check in to get a good boarding position.
Wellby: Ooh, very good.
DM: And she greets you,
DM: um, she says,
DM: "Uh, greetings
DM: monk and transformed animal companions."
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Give a little wave with my wing.
Seeker: Yeah. Yeah. Chirp.
Unknown: Chirp, chirp.
DM: I am
DM: Ra'ghemdros, daughter of Cha'mutte, the Light Stealer and the Final Shadow, the Devourer of Drankor, the Last Empress of Hkar,
DM: known as the Eternal Night and the Enslaver of the Secret Sunset.
Unknown: Enslaver of the Secret Sunset.
DM: Now, I hear you have come to offer a bargain.
Unknown: Oh my God, Last Empress of Hkar.
DM: Speak.
Unknown: Um, give me-
DM: Mortals.
Kenzo: [laughs] Give me one quick second.
Unknown: Uh-
DM: Yeah. Think about what you want to say.
Kenzo: Hold on. Um, hold on, just checking in actually.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Um, close.
Kenzo: Are you guys, what positions are you guys?
Delwath: I bought early check-in, so I'm A55.
Unknown: You're what?
Delwath: A55.
Unknown: What are you guys?
Unknown: What are you, Eric?
Unknown: [coughs]
Seeker: I just got B51.
Unknown: I'm B54.
Delwath: Schwartz is not flying.
Unknown: The rest of us aren't flying. [laughs]
Kenzo: Oh yeah, and you're not. Um,
Kenzo: I'm highly considering upgrading.
Unknown: Yeah, you're just gonna do the upgrade to A, A1, whatever.
Unknown: Maybe.
Unknown: Good choice.
Seeker: Wait, what does that let you do? Just get off the plane faster?
Kenzo: Why is upgrading cost $0 for me?
DM: Just do it.
Unknown: Because you're an amazing person, I guess.
DM: You probably fly Southwest so much.
Unknown: You should just upgrade.
DM: Just do it.
Kenzo: I mean, I'm definitely doing that.
Unknown: Please correct the... Uh, I did.
Unknown: Oh, wait, what the fuck?
Kenzo: Sorry, just give, just give me-
Unknown: Oh
Unknown: ... one second here.
DM: Is there, did we eat all the grapes?
Unknown: I think they're-
Wellby: No, there should be
Unknown: ... they're in the fridge.
Unknown: Ah, fucking credit card.
Kenzo: It, it, it wants a credit card for $0.
Unknown: [keyboard clicking] Yeah,
Delwath: it wants $70 from me.
Seeker: Yeah, me too.
Unknown: I'm not doing that.
Delwath: I already paid $20 to get A instead of B.
Unknown: I'm not paying another 70
Unknown: to get
Wellby: Tim, I have for you,
Wellby: uh, a black dragon and some medium sized creatures.
Wellby: And I also have for you-
Seeker: Nice
Wellby: ...
Wellby: uh, like swirly things that are probably good for lair attacks.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Is that poison?
Wellby: And minion sized things that'd be good for minion sized things.
Wellby: Not that we expect to fight, but you know.
Delwath: There's something in the villa that she's worried about.
Unknown: Yeah, there is.
Delwath: The feat. It's obviously the feat.
Delwath: Trying to find out what it is.
Delwath: Maybe we can kill the feat.
Kenzo: For her?
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Banish it.
Delwath: I like killing fiends. They're never good.
Kenzo: What is just their status relative to hobgoblins?
Delwath: Worse.
Unknown: Wow.
Delwath: Fiends are humanity's darkest selves.
Wellby: Humanity's darkest selves?
Unknown: I mean, humanity's created them
Unknown: Really?
DM: So-
Delwath: That's what, that's what the centaur told us at the very beginning of the campaign
Wellby: Oh, I remember that One way to destroy all fiends would just be to be, destroy humanity.
DM: So then-
Delwath: Yeah, but the cost is too high
DM: ... then
Delwath: No, that's not im- that's totally immoral
DM: Depends on the
DM: humans, I guess. That would be a good,
DM: like,
DM: villain for a campaign
Unknown: That would be
DM: ... like
DM: a super lawful paladin who's like, "I just gotta kill every human in order to eliminate fiends from the world."
Wellby: [coughs] The ends justify the fiends?
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: Okay. I just upgraded myself.
Kenzo: Uh, okay. [coughs] I think that's it.
Kenzo: All right, cool. [clears throat] Um, uh, what was the...
Kenzo: I know she just, she had a whole fucking shitload of titles.
Kenzo: What was, what wa- what was the one that she was, like, most excited about saying?
DM: Um
Kenzo: As she was, like, listing them off
DM: Probably The
DM: Final Shadow.
Kenzo: Okay. [clears throat] I say, um
DM: The Last Empress of Dunmar.
Kenzo: What, what's, what's the, what's her name again?
DM: Ra'ghemdros.
Kenzo: Dunmar. Dunmar. I s- I say, um, "Oh, Ra'ghm, Ra'ghemdros.
Kenzo: Ra'ghemdros?"
DM: Ra'ghemdros.
Kenzo: Uh, "Ra'ghemdros, The Final Shadow, it's an honor to be in your presence and to have this audience."
Kenzo: And I bow, I bow deeply.
DM: She just kind of nods and gives you an acknowledgement.
Kenzo: [clears throat] As, um, as, uh, Ghesh has t- Ghesh, right?
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: As Ghesh has shared with you, I've traveled to the west.
Kenzo: Uh, and I'm, I'm studying her very fucking closely.
DM: Mm-hmm
Kenzo: Like, for every little reaction as I-
DM: Yeah. [clears throat]
Kenzo: I've traveled to the west, and I've traveled to the tower there.
Kenzo: Do you know of this place?
DM: Make an insight check with advantage for your full sighting.
Wellby: Can we be doing this also?
DM: [dice rolling]
Kenzo: Uh, 18.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: 18 plus whatever.
DM: Plus eight?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, yeah. You're, um...
DM: She's, she, her, you know, her eyes open.
DM: Like, she, her attention is mostly focused on the Villa.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: When you mention you've traveled to the tower, she definitely, like, looks at you, like, pa-
DM: is, like, updating her judgment about you.
Unknown: Like, maybe I should actually pay attention to them.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm. Also, I wonder if it's the fiend who's interested in us or if it's that she's interested in us.
Kenzo: Anyways, um, but, but, uh, but I ask her, "Do you know of this place, the tower?
Kenzo: The tower to the west."
DM: Of course. I know of everything in my domain.
Kenzo: Uh, have you, do you know of what's inside the tower?
DM: I have not been in myself.
DM: I have seen it.
Kenzo: Are you i- interested in what's within the tower?
DM: I would be very interested if you have a way to get in there without drawing attention of the tower's owner.
Kenzo: Does she not know Apollyon's dead?
Unknown: But he's dead.
DM: Is Apollyon dead?
Kenzo: Apollyon's not dead. Or is, does she not know that Apollyon's...
Delwath: Imprisoned? Or do we not know that we've just done something horribly wrong?
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: So maybe we have in fact alerted Apollyon.
Wellby: He would've been, he would've been more imprisoned while he was alive than he is now.
Wellby: Like, when she was alive, that is.
DM: Or when she [clears throat] was born.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. She, he, yeah.
Kenzo: I ask her, "Who's the owner?"
Unknown: Nice.
DM: You know not of Apollyon?
Unknown: I do.
DM: You do know of Apollyon.
Kenzo: I know of Apollyon.
Wellby: Is he not in prison,
DM: though? I'm, I would ask.
DM: She looks...
Delwath: No, preten- we gotta pretend like we know
DM: The,
DM: the elf, the dwarf, and the halfling may as well come out.
Wellby: She has true sight.
DM: Hmm.
DM: All right.
Unknown: All right
Wellby: Well, we'll, we'll all pop out and-
Wellby: ... bow deeply and
Wellby: [clears throat] praise her magnificent vision that
Wellby: penetrates all things.
DM: What of Apollyon? What would you...
DM: I care not if he knows
DM: that you are there.
DM: It is no concern to me if he decides to hunt and kill you.
DM: So if you are volunteering to go, that is a great boon for myself.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: [laughs] So wait, so she thinks that he's alive or captured?
Delwath: Um, no. She's right and he's going to try and hunt and kill us, but how much worse can it be?
Delwath: He's already trying to hunt and kill us.
DM: He's already dragged us all here.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Like, he's, he's been trying to...
DM: He's already doing that, yeah.
Seeker: Uh, uh...
DM: Uh, [coughs] Apollyon.
DM: We are
DM: already
Delwath: in a struggle with Apollyon,
Delwath: and this feint will only, I think, distract him from our true purpose.
DM: Well, that is good then.
DM: You will be willing sacrifices.
Kenzo: Do you have interest in what's there?
DM: I do have great interest.
Kenzo: Both learning of it and then obtaining it?
DM: She looks at you.
DM: I would dearly love
DM: his throne,
DM: and I would be willing to trade.
DM: What is this you wish?
DM: The smallest trinket? A piece of jade?
Unknown: Indeed.
DM: If you bring me his throne.
Kenzo: You'd be willing to make that trade?
DM: I would.
Kenzo: Uh, insight?
DM: Uh,
DM: with advantage?
Unknown: With advantage. [dice rolling]
Unknown: 18.
DM: Yeah, she seems pretty genuine
Wellby: Uh, w- willing to make this trade and then allow us to go freely from your domain, oh great magnificence?
DM: If you go to the tower,
DM: I would not have you linger in my domain,
DM: for I would not wish to draw Apollyon's eye.
Kenzo: But if we can bring you the throne,
Unknown: that would be worth a trade.
Delwath: I'll give you
Delwath: the jade.
Kenzo: And also passage from.
DM: As soon as you take the jade,
Delwath: you must leave immediately.
DM: You will be no longer welcome on this island.
Wellby: All right.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: That's a, that's a fair bargain.
Delwath: Yeah. Let's do it.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: Um, telepathically do we just pull up the throne now or do we leave and come back?
Delwath: Oh, that's interesting.
Delwath: She doesn't have the jade presumably.
Seeker: So we arrange a time...
Unknown: Yeah, tomorrow
Delwath: No, not tomorrow.
Unknown: Too much-
Delwath: In an hour.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Two hours.
Delwath: Give it a...
Delwath: Yeah.
Delwath: When... It's like 1:00?
DM: Yeah, it's like, it's like 2:00.
Delwath: Like,
Delwath: return i- I think we-
Kenzo: Return in an hour
Delwath: ... return in two hou-
Unknown: Two
Delwath: ... returning here with the jade, two hours.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah. We can do this.
Kenzo: We can bring the throne.
Kenzo: Can we do... Where, where do you want to, where do we want to do the exchange?
Delwath: Here.
Kenzo: Yeah, okay. We'll do the exchange here.
Kenzo: We'll, we'll... We can do the exchange here in two hours.
DM: I will be impressed if you can actually pull that off.
Kenzo: Uh, telepathically, um, you know, it's a big heavy throne.
Kenzo: Turn t- to- require us to turn into elephants to push it out of the thing.
Unknown: Um.
Delwath: [laughs] Yeah, that's the biggest problem is I don't know how to get the throne out of the portable hole.
Wellby: Um, we can
Wellby: teleport a single object and the throne would be small enough to be affected by that.
Delwath: We can teleport a single object.
Kenzo: And, and like can Seeker teleport-
Delwath: Right now can we teleport a single object?
Wellby: Teleport spell you can teleport an object.
Delwath: Ah.
Unknown: I didn't know that.
Wellby: You can target an object.
Kenzo: Can, can, b- can S- can Seeker teleport with the throne?
Delwath: If you can teleport an object, sure.
DM: I think it's either an object or creatures.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: Either. Can we do both?
Delwath: But why do we need to do both?
Kenzo: So that we can also be teleported with the, with the object.
Wellby: Alternatively, couldn't we beast shape into elephants and just carry it?
Delwath: Why don't we just teleport the throne out and then beast shape into birds and fly back to the boat?
Wellby: Huh?
Seeker: Or we could bring the bridge.
Delwath: Why do we need to teleport?
Seeker: We don't.
Wellby: Uh-
Seeker: I think, I think we could teleport the throne to the courtyard here.
Delwath: Yeah.
Seeker: I, I just go in the portable hole and teleport it out basically.
Wellby: Can... You can't teleport across dimensions though.
Delwath: But I think once you open the hole-
Unknown: I mean, once the hole is open, it's in this universe
Delwath: ... it's in this universe.
Wellby: Right.
Delwath: It's just a hole.
Kenzo: Sorry, so what's the plan? How do we get the throne out?
Kenzo: Like draw and undo? 'Cause like what I was imagining is if we, if we go, you know...
Kenzo: Now we, we have to leave here to go to the tower or whatever we're doing, so we fly back or we go someplace to the-
Seeker: We just go somewhere out of sight.
Seeker: We open the hole. I go in the hole.
Seeker: I teleport it to where we're staying now.
Delwath: No, no, no. We go somewhere out of sight.
Delwath: We come back and we open the hole in front of her and just teleport the thing out.
Seeker: Oh, okay. Yeah, that's fine.
Unknown: Right?
Seeker: We don't need to pretend.
Unknown: We don't need to pretend at that point.
Delwath: That's right.
Kenzo: But do we not want her to know that we have a portable hole though?
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Why do we care?
Kenzo: I mean, it feels-
Wellby: Like maybe she sees the other stuff in the hole and we're like, "Yeah."
Kenzo: Yeah, it feel, it feels kind of nice to just teleport the throne there and just the throne just appears and here it is, right?
Delwath: I guess.
Wellby: We don't want to burn this best lie for it or-
Delwath: I don't know how we do that.
Delwath: Would we teleport the throne here with us not being there?
Kenzo: That's, that's what I'm saying.
Wellby: Oh, yeah. If you want to... Are you-
Unknown: Can we teleport us with the throne?
Unknown: Are you... Do you want to keep talking to Ra- Ra'ghemdros?
Delwath: Uh, no. I think we agreed to...
Delwath: We tell her
Delwath: we are... We will accept this deal, and we will return in two hours.
Kenzo: Hold on. Hold on. Let's just...
Unknown: Hold on.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Let's just tr- wait, wait, wait, wait.
Kenzo: One, one second just to like, you know, quick...
Unknown: Okay. I mean,
Kenzo: this can't be...
Kenzo: It, it cannot be the case that we can just come back here and then we're leaving the island.
Kenzo: Like she might be agreeing to this, but-
Delwath: No, a fiend is gonna break out and try to kill us or something horrible like that.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yes, exactly. Exactly.
Delwath: Something's gonna happen.
Kenzo: Yeah. Th- this, this is not, this is not we just get the jade and we leave right now.
Seeker: It seems all too straightforward, doesn't it?
Kenzo: Yeah. At, at like fucking 1:15 in the afternoon on Saturday.
Kenzo: There's just no way. [laughs] There's just no way.
Unknown: There's no way that's happening.
Delwath: But I mean,
Delwath: I don't know-
Unknown: Because-
Delwath: Like, okay, why don't we just play it straight?
Delwath: Like-
Kenzo: Well, no, we do. We do, right? I think we do
Delwath: ... honestly, if we're gonna kill something, I'd rather kill Apollyon's serpent than her.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: Like ultimately if we get forced into them making a deal with her to fight off Apollyon, fine.
Wellby: Okay.
Delwath: Right?
Wellby: Can you ask her what's in the bill? I mean,
Wellby: I don't know.
Kenzo: Is that a curiosity?
Wellby: I don't know if we wanna push it, but...
Delwath: We could.
Seeker: Use, use a proper title of address.
Delwath: Um, how-
Kenzo: Actually, um, is there...
Kenzo: Do you think you can ask her telepathically?
Delwath: How... You're a half a mile.
Unknown: God.
Wellby: I could, but it seems like a bad idea.
Delwath: Could you what?
Kenzo: Ask her telepathically. That's what I half thought.
Delwath: You could.
Kenzo: I mean, you could just be like, "Out of my halfling curiosity..."
Kenzo: You know what I mean? Do one of those. 'Cause, you know, 'cause if I ask her out loud, the fiend's gonna fucking hear.
Delwath: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: You know?
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: That's the whole-
Delwath: That's half a mile away, but yeah.
Kenzo: No, but the... Clearly she... You know, like the fiend is monitoring this conversation somehow.
Kenzo: Scrying and/or whatever.
Delwath: Well, Apollyon probably is, not so much the fiend.
Delwath: The problem here is that when we broke into the tower, we tripped Apollyon's auto always, ever, for now and forever until the, till we kill him-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... permanent scry on us.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So now he's watching everything we do.
Wellby: But he probably can't see us through the magic shield.
Kenzo: Hey, can you, can we... Can we like...
Kenzo: The, the, the top's spinning. Can we have spun the top when we were at, uh, Dimitar's place just for fun?
DM: At some point
Kenzo: Yeah, we must have spun, like, like we spun the top at some point after we-
DM: Yeah, we must have spun it before the tower
Unknown: It was before the tower.
Unknown: Huh?
DM: Oh, you're right. You're right. Um-
Kenzo: Well, it was before the tower
Unknown: Right
DM: When you spun the top. But also there is an anti, presumably even Apollyon's permanent scry can't penetrate the anti-magic shield.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: So then are we...
Delwath: But why is she worried then?
Wellby: Say that to her.
DM: Huh?
Unknown: Well, let's, let's ask that.
Wellby: Like, would-
DM: I mean, you could, you can keep talking to her.
DM: I didn't mean you have to end the conversation.
Wellby: Yeah, just-
DM: Okay, yeah. Go ahead.
Wellby: We, we know that... No, go ahead.
Delwath: I was gonna say, um,
Delwath: are you,
Delwath: are you interested, are you, are you enemies of Apollyon?
DM: She kind of looks down at you and,
DM: uh,
DM: opens her eyes and grins.
DM: You see her teeth for the first time.
DM: I am happy you are enemies of Apollyon.
Seeker: She's limited in what she can say.
Kenzo: Uh, a- a- do I sense anything behind her grin?
DM: Um, just kind of like,
DM: you know,
DM: somebody's gonna die.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: But it's not gonna be her.
DM: If you and Apollyon fight, maybe you'll kill her.
DM: Maybe he'll kill you.
Wellby: Isn't he-
DM: Uh-
Wellby: ... for- forgive our ignorance, but it seems the whole island is shielded so thoroughly.
Wellby: Surely it's shielded even from him.
DM: You have not seen his true power, I believe.
Wellby: Hmm.
Unknown: What is his true power?
DM: Uh, make a persuasion check.
DM: Can roll with advantage.
Kenzo: 19 plus whatever my persuasion thing is.
DM: Eight or a five or something.
Wellby: It's your persuasion.
Kenzo: Oh, just plus one, 20.
DM: Okay. Um,
DM: she sort of hesitates and,
DM: you know, paces around a little bit and,
DM: hmm,
DM: she doesn't,
DM: she doesn't answer your question but the, but you sense from soul sight that, like, she is, like, genuinely afraid of Apollyon.
DM: You will find out, is what she says.
Kenzo: But you're, you're afraid of him even now, right now?
DM: I mean, do you say you're afraid of Apollyon?
Unknown: No.
DM: But that's the sense you get. She's afraid of him.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Not like in the past, like right now.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: He doesn't seem higher than 22.
Wellby: Is he imprisoned?
DM: All prisons fail,
DM: and she glances.
DM: She's like you... It's obvious she glances at the villa at this point.
Wellby: Even
Wellby: yours?
DM: Of course not mine.
DM: I told you I'm in the slave...
DM: I am the enslaver of the secret sunset and will be forever.
Kenzo: What is the secret sunset?
DM: She kind of looks at you.
DM: Did you not hear the word secret?
Kenzo: [laughs] Excuse my-
Seeker: It's the emberglass thing
Unknown: ... [laughs] my, uh,
Kenzo: human intellect.
Unknown: You might
Delwath: be interested to know
Delwath: that Apollyon's prison will fail in
Delwath: nine days.
DM: I told you all prisons fail.
Delwath: So if there's any preparations you think you might need for the collapse of his prison,
Delwath: I would advise making them.
DM: I have.
Wellby: Huh.
DM: Did we not just make a deal?
Unknown: What does that mean?
Delwath: Apollyon's... Wait, Apollyon's throne wasn't actually...
Delwath: We didn't detect any magic on it, right?
DM: On what?
Delwath: Apollyon's throne.
DM: Nope.
DM: No, she's clearly implying, like, you're gonna go to the tower, Apollyon's gonna target you.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: And either you'll kill her and it'll be fine, or he'll kill you and maybe that'll be enough.
Delwath: But we won't be here in nine days.
DM: I know. That's her whole point.
Unknown: You'll be somewhere where he can get you.
Delwath: But if the fiend trapped on this island is Apollyon's servant-
DM: Maybe you're misunderstanding something.
Unknown: Right. Okay.
Kenzo: Yeah. This, this whole, uh, what is the secret sunset?
Kenzo: That's interesting. Uh, his-
Wellby: The secret sunset is-
Kenzo: She's the enslaver of the secret sunset.
Kenzo: You want to do a history check?
Wellby: Secret sunset is a insurance against Apollyon one way or another.
Kenzo: You trying to figure out what the secret sunset is?
Seeker: I thought that was, there was, like, a curse on part of the Feywild.
DM: There was. That's where s- that's where you Seeker traveled.
Seeker: Right. Yeah.
DM: The Cloudspinner was the boss of the fey, Archfey of Amberglow and-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
DM: ... Queen of Sunsets.
Seeker: Right, the Cloudspinner.
Delwath: Wait, did, did Cha'mutte...
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: What?
Delwath: So the Cloudspinner mysteriously vanished-
Unknown: Right
Delwath: ... right around the time Drankor fell.
Unknown: Right. Who's the Cloudspinner?
Delwath: The person who made the Cloak of Rainbows.
Delwath: The fey queen who made the Cloak of Rainbows.
Wellby: Fey and fiend are different, right?
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: Fey and fiend are definitely different.
Kenzo: Very different.
Delwath: But they both start with the
Delwath: letter F. But, but, but, but hold on.
Unknown: So
Seeker: Tyffina was part of the resistance against...
Seeker: Oh, but Tyffina was actually
Seeker: a gata.
Unknown: The
Delwath: Cloudspinner misvanished under very mysterious circumstances and once she was-
Delwath: Once she vanished,
Delwath: Amberglow, her kingdom, started to fade, right?
Unknown: All kinds of bad things started to sneak into it.
Delwath: But she made the cloak of rainbows for the orcs, for the free orcs.
Unknown: What is the-
Wellby: That is maybe a red herring.
Seeker: It does seem like I'd-
Wellby: Can you rack your brains and history and archive it?
Kenzo: Yeah, history, history on the Cloudspinners.
Delwath: Well, I shouldn't share too much meta, but, but Tim and I spent a lot of time talking about what happened to the Cloudspinners.
Delwath: Like, I'm not gonna tell you.
Seeker: Hmm. But it has, it has to do with...
Unknown: Like, okay, I'm just-
Delwath: And the Sunset Scad Gok Scar.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: That's obviously related. But can you-
Unknown: Did Fae become a fiend? Is there...
Kenzo: Just Secret Sunset, you wanna, like, History or Archon check that?
Seeker: Okay. Can I do that too?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah.
Seeker: So is that History or Archon?
DM: What are you trying... What do you wanna know?
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: what is the-
Kenzo: What about Secret Sunsets? She, she said Enslaver of the Secret Sunset.
Delwath: Yeah. That's, that's what it is.
Seeker: So what... Yeah, what was the Secret Sunset?
Delwath: The sunset ru- the sunset in the Faewild runs right through her kingdom.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Whose kingdom?
Delwath: The Cloudspinner. Like, the Faewild, remember, the Faewild is ti- like, each physical place, and the sun is in a fixed position everywhere in the Faewild, right?
Delwath: So-
Unknown: Okay
Delwath: ... so ti- so the sun moves not because the sun moves, because you walk.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: So there's a physical point in the Faewild which is the sunset.
Unknown: Uh-huh.
Delwath: That is the point, and it runs right through Amberglow.
Delwath: It runs right through her old kingdom.
Kenzo: Amberglow is...
Delwath: Cloudspinner's old kingdom.
Unknown: Oh, shit.
Kenzo: And she's the enslaver of-
Delwath: So Enslaver of the Secret Sunset sounds an awful lot like...
Seeker: But Secret Sunset is not a phrase I remember-
Delwath: No
Seeker: ... hearing about, so I wanna do a history check about it.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah.
Seeker: So I'm gonna do that now.
Seeker: That's a 20.
Delwath: 20 total?
Seeker: Total.
DM: I mean, Secret Sunset isn't a phrase that, like, comes to mind particularly.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: But you know dragons are prone to twisting...
Delwath: I mean-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... you look at her title, right?
DM: Like, she's obviously also not the last Empress of Hkar, unless she's, like, interpreting this as the last piece of Hkar.
Delwath: That's-
Seeker: That's what I was thinking, yeah
DM: ... right. So she's, like, clearly Devourer of Drankor.
Delwath: Like,
Delwath: you know, she's-
Unknown: What are-
DM: So she could be boasting
Wellby: ... what about, um,
Wellby: uh, powers to see...
Wellby: Like, to perceive people or consciousness?
Wellby: Like, how do we know it was a fiend in the first place?
Delwath: Kenzo.
Unknown: Kenzo.
Wellby: Like, can Kenzo, now that he's a mile away,
Wellby: get a better sense of who is imprisoned up there, and if it's maybe not strictly a fiend, but, like, a fiend that was once a fae, or, uh-
Kenzo: That's actually true. Yeah, I can use...
Kenzo: I can... 'Cause we're gonna, we're gonna, um, rest again.
Unknown: So I can-
Delwath: Yeah
Kenzo: ... I'll, I'll do my fucking ultra focused, um, aura sense into, into the villa.
Delwath: Uh, you sense the fiend.
Delwath: It's a fiend.
Unknown: Hmm. Hmm.
Delwath: Um...
Kenzo: Anything more about the fiend?
Delwath: Uh...
DM: I don't look at this too closely.
DM: Anything more about the fiend?
Delwath: Um...
Unknown: So...
DM: It's a reasonably strong fiend.
Kenzo: Reasonably strong, huh?
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: Is there anything else we wanna talk about for now?
Kenzo: I mean, can we learn a little bit more?
Kenzo: I mean, uh, uh...
Kenzo: Oh, shit, I was about to say, like, does she know that we killed Shamat?
Unknown: We didn't kill Shamat. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Um, is there anywhere, um...
Kenzo: I feel like we should talk to her a little bit more, actually.
Delwath: Yeah, I do too. I'm just not sure what to ask her.
Unknown: Um, uh...
Delwath: Like, she's clearly interested in the villa, but it's hard to ask her why directly.
Delwath: She keeps looking back at it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: She doesn't
Delwath: seem too worried about...
Kenzo: When she glances back at the villa, is she glancing back in fear, curiosity?
Kenzo: Like, like, you know, just like... Again, I'm, I'm, like, super locked into her, like, any-
DM: It's more, it's just, like, the center of her...
Unknown: It's just like she's pi- you know.
Delwath: It's like she's watching it.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: Like she's guarding over that place.
Seeker: Guarding over it.
Delwath: Um, Tim?
Delwath: Yeah?
Delwath: There's no reason... Like, wait, what did you say she was im- She's immune to charmed, frightened...
Delwath: Why is she guarding over it?
Wellby: You're gonna look for surface thoughts?
Delwath: Yeah. Why not?
Unknown: Oh.
Seeker: Oh, great one, last Empress of Hkar,
Seeker: what's over there?
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Hold on. Hold on, hold on.
Seeker: I see, I've seen you glancing.
DM: I assume you're using subtle so she doesn't know you're casting a spell.
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: Okay.
Kenzo: Well, we know what's over there. It's a fiend.
Delwath: Yeah. I'm gonna, I'm gonna subtle spell Detect Thoughts.
Seeker: I'm just curious what she says about it.
Delwath: Um,
Delwath: I may as well use a warlock slot since we'll almost certainly
Delwath: short rest. Um,
DM: she, she kind of says, um,
DM: you know, "Impertinent dwarf.
DM: Seems ridiculous to think that I would tell you such information
DM: when you offer nothing in return."
DM: But her surface thoughts are clearly like, "I have to guard the prison."
Kenzo: The prison?
Seeker: And she's a little defensive about it, I would say.
Delwath: I have to guard the prison.
Seeker: So she's guarding something.
Seeker: The fiend is a captive, but she has to...
Kenzo: What is the... Who is in there?
Seeker: Or is she lying?
Kenzo: Can you use clairvoyance into the, into the villa?
Wellby: She'll know that you're casting.
DM: She'll know you're casting a spell and she'll probably get pretty pissed.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Um, but we think she's gonna have to return to her lair.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Can we send an animal in there?
Wellby: Yeah, but she's... I mean
Delwath: Is there... I'm gonna ask her again a little bit, like bow.
Delwath: Uh-
Unknown: We can do that in an hour
Delwath: ... when we depart-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... uh, and when we return, um, is there anywhere that is off limits on this island?
Unknown: What? What are you asking?
Delwath: I'm asking her if there's anywhere off limits.
Kenzo: What does that mean, off limits?
Seeker: To us.
Delwath: To us that we're not allowed to go.
Wellby: [clears throat]
Delwath: Would not want to trespass where we're unwelcome, but, um,
Delwath: we may be-
DM: I will grant you passage.
DM: All that is off limits is
DM: keeping what you find.
Wellby: Very good.
Delwath: She doesn't mention the villa.
DM: She doesn't mention the villa.
Wellby: Do you...
DM: Oh, there's like four chimeras and four dragonettes flying around, right?
Delwath: Check.
DM: I mean, it would be obvious.
Delwath: If we teleported inside the villa, why would it be obvious?
DM: It, I mean, it wouldn't be obvious.
DM: If you walked there, it, yes, it would not be obvious at all, right, if you did it that way.
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: You don't...
Wellby: I mean, surely you're not a creature of worry, but when Apollyon's done killing us, won't he come back to his tower and his forge again?
Unknown: Uh, forge?
Wellby: Hmm?
Unknown: Forge.
Wellby: Yeah, what?
Delwath: [laughs]
Wellby: We could have heard stories of that possibly.
Delwath: No, we told her we knew it was in the tower.
DM: Kenzo said he had scouted the tower.
Kenzo: Yeah, but we, we haven't told her yet what we found, so.
Unknown: Yeah, whatever.
Seeker: It's fine.
Seeker: The hypothetical thing.
Wellby: She put those things together.
DM: I mean, she did see, she did ask specifically for the throne.
DM: Yeah.
DM: She's obviously seen inside the tower.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah. Okay.
Delwath: Um,
DM: you know, she, she, uh...
DM: You know, she's kind of, um...
DM: She doesn't, she doesn't respond i- immediately a- and it's clear, like, um, you know, her,
DM: her surface thoughts are something like, "Why do these pests keep bothering me about Apollyon?"
DM: 'Cause obviously she just doesn't wanna think about Apollyon.
Wellby: Hmm.
Delwath: Right? Like-
Wellby: Understood
DM: ... this is Trump Dragon, right?
DM: It's something that d- disturbs her, just doesn't, she just doesn't wanna think about it.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: She's like, "That is your concern, not mine,
Unknown: unless he can sail."
Kenzo: Let's just do the fucking thing.
Kenzo: I mean, it's like,
Kenzo: well, she wants, she wants a throne.
Unknown: This just feels so weird.
Unknown: What is this? Just some kind of trap.
Delwath: We'll find out when it happens.
Delwath: I think we just tell her we'll return in two hours.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: And we may
Delwath: return somewhere a little different than right here, but we'll let you know when we...
Delwath: We may be returning in haste via magic.
DM: Um, she orders one of the dragonettes to fly up to the chimeras and tell them you are not to be disturbed until the next morning, [clears throat]
DM: and then vanishes to her lair, leaving the four dragonettes to watch.
Kenzo: She, she, she like disappears?
DM: She dives into the water.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Okay.
DM: So the chimeras will not attack you until tomorrow morning.
Unknown: Well, that
DM: The dragonettes are still watching.
Delwath: Let's just go in the villa.
Delwath: Okay, let's, let's, let's get...
Delwath: We have two hours until we're supposed to meet her again, right?
DM: Yes.
Kenzo: Could you be sense, send something in there first?
Delwath: So the first thing we do is just, what's the...
Delwath: Is there a place we can just like...
Delwath: I mean, we can just tele- we can talk telepathically, so.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: We only need a few minutes to bring her the throne.
Delwath: So-
Kenzo: Let's go investigate the villa.
Delwath: I mean, we could just dimension door inside it.
Kenzo: Well, but why not a little more subterfuge?
Kenzo: Should we just, uh, do like some clairvoyance and/or, you know, send a, send a be sense back in to get-
Wellby: Send something in to get
Delwath: Sure, but I mean, disappearing from right here to teleport somewhere far away is exactly what they expect to do.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Right? So dimension door-ing somewhere else, they totally expect us to teleport.
Delwath: I mean, sure, investigate it first.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: But I think it's extremely subterfugy to teleport to an unexpected location.
Delwath: I'm sure everybody expects us to teleport from here.
Delwath: We set it up that way on purpose.
DM: Yeah, you said you were gonna teleport to the tower.
Wellby: So we dimension door right inside the front door?
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: Wait, but don't we want to investigate it first?
Delwath: The villa?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Uh, probably. [laughs]
Seeker: Yeah, let's fucking do that.
Delwath: Please.
Wellby: Sure.
Seeker: Use the beast trick.
Wellby: I mean, uh, bat out of my hat and-
Delwath: Okay
Wellby: ... be sense and-
Unknown: Do you want to do something smaller that's not gonna be, like, immediately killed by the flying things?
Unknown: Like-
Wellby: I got bat, a rat, and a frog.
Unknown: Rat.
DM: A rat's gonna take a while to scramble up a half mile journey.
Delwath: I mean, the other thing is a half mile is a little too far for dimensional.
Delwath: We have to like walk closer to it.
DM: Well, if you walk... So the road goes like this, right?
DM: The villa's here. This road goes further.
DM: If you walk, if you follow the road back to the plaza-
Delwath: Ah, we'd be within-
DM: You'll pass within 1,000 or within 1,000 feet.
Kenzo: Let's do that.
Delwath: Okay.
DM: What's the range of dimension door?
Delwath: It's 500, but it's, but it's not south.
DM: Oh, so Seeker can-
Delwath: It's 500. I can double it too.
Delwath: I took distance back.
DM: Right, right. Okay, so both of you can double the distance of dimension door.
Unknown: That's cool.
Seeker: And then it's for two creatures.
DM: But, but-
Unknown: Which is the, we can both do it.
DM: Yeah, if you can both do it, yeah.
DM: So you would walk within 1,000 feet if you just follow the road back to that place.
Wellby: All right. Like, if, if everything's-
Unknown: Send the mouse in.
Wellby: Uh, yeah, sure.
DM: Send what?
Unknown: Send the mouse in.
DM: Send the mouse. So you like start walking back so you get closer.
Delwath: I mean, before we go in, I think we need to...
Delwath: It would be useful to, to...
Delwath: I think we might want... Well, I can...
Delwath: I don't know.
Wellby: We can also just like use animal shape to enhance and go like-
Delwath: No, I think Dimension Door is better
Unknown: All right. So-
Delwath: No, I can-
Kenzo: No, but isn't being ants better so that, that we...
Unknown: Yeah, in goes the bat.
DM: I mean, the, the dragonets are watching you, right?
DM: These four dragonets you left behind are obviously watching you.
Kenzo: Yeah, but if we disappear and turn into ants, then, you know, they're not-
DM: They're not gonna... That's gonna look like-
Unknown: We, like we tell the truth
Unknown: ... teleportation.
DM: Exactly.
Delwath: Like, what's the advantage of turn- Oh, 'cause it doesn't use a spell.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Well, and also, like, if we go into the, up into the thing, we're not obviously, like, a bunch of fucking humanoids that licked the, the, the phoenix seeds.
DM: Oh, inside the-
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, on the other side of the Dimension Door, you know?
Kenzo: It's like, then we can at least have some, you know,
Kenzo: like look around a little bit before we, you know.
Delwath: Well, let's scout first.
Kenzo: Yeah. Send the, send the bat and mouse in.
Unknown: All right.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: So I'm gonna send in a rat.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Rat.
DM: Rat.
Kenzo: Right? Rat, I think, should be better.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, okay. So
DM: where is this? Uh, you send a, a rat.
DM: Scrambles up-
Seeker: Climb and drop it in place
DM: ... scrambles up into the, into the, um, th- these sort of ruins, right?
DM: Um, and you can see it's, so like the interior, there's o- there's basically no standing walls in the interior.
DM: In fact, like, the, the...
DM: There's still a few, like, piles of rubble.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: But there's nothing that's standing more than about four feet high.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um, and you sort of explore around a little bit.
DM: Um,
DM: uh, it's basically entirely cleared out except, um, there is a,
DM: uh, uh,
DM: stairs down into a cellar.
DM: And in front of the stairs down into the cellar, um, you see two,
DM: um, like floating...
DM: It's hard to describe them.
DM: They're sort of like floating pools of acid that seem to be just kind of floating,
DM: keeping guard over the stairs down.
Unknown: Floating pools?
DM: Floating, like, columns of sort of blobby columns of acid that are floating in the air.
Delwath: And the stairs go down into something?
DM: Into something.
Delwath: And can we, can the bat see, like, the bottom step?
DM: The rat.
Delwath: The rat. Like, it can see somewhere.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Can it, uh, can we try stealthing its way?
DM: Um,
DM: yeah, make a stealth check. I mean, it's a rat.
DM: There's, there's other little small mammals in here.
DM: [die rolling]
Wellby: That's an 18 on the die.
DM: Okay. Yeah, that's it.
DM: The, the, the two floating pools of acid, acid don't seem to have been told to burn rats.
DM: Heads down into the cellar.
DM: Uh,
DM: down in the cellar, um, th- the rat does not have darkvision, right?
Unknown: Uh.
DM: Just checking.
Wellby: I don't know.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: let me check.
DM: Well, in any case, the, the, the first place it comes to, it doesn't matter because it's lit.
DM: The, the, um, the,
DM: the rat goes down the staircase and you see down through the rat down below a,
DM: um, a large room, maybe,
DM: uh, one-
Wellby: Rat does have 30 foot darkvision.
DM: Okay. Maybe 25 by 25 foot square.
DM: Um, there are,
DM: um...
DM: So in the center of the room,
DM: um, there is a large, like a, like a,
DM: what do you call them? Like the, the, like the st- like a tomb sort of looking thing.
Unknown: Sarcophagus kind of thing?
DM: Yeah, but it's not, it's not a tomb. It's just like a marble table where you would, like, rest a coffin or something.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: If you were just, like, pre- for a funeral or something like that.
DM: There's magical flames that burn
DM: seemingly using nothing in two, in four ornate braziers that are stationed at, like, the four corners of the room.
DM: Wow.
DM: Um, there's nine statues depicting a variety of men and women, usually in elegant clothes.
DM: The statue on the far western wall is larger and depicts an, like an imposing man, probably a wizard seated, um, holding one hand with the palm up,
DM: an open book resting on the palm and a flame, um, coming up from the book.
Kenzo: It looks like Apollyon?
Delwath: And does it look like the thing we saw on the door?
DM: It looks like the thing we saw on the door.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: and the rat can't read and you can't read.
DM: Can you read Drankhoran?
Unknown: No.
DM: There's an inscription in Drankhoran.
DM: Um,
DM: there are also, um, decorated, there's like, um, painting, the walls are all painted in a mural that seems to be depicting, like, um, what
DM: it...
DM: So actually, Grog has been to the Land of the Dead.
DM: Um, like the, the first panels are sort of, are showing sort of like a, a, a group of mourners around a, a coffin, and then it shows like a, a soul sort
DM: of stepping out of the coffin.
DM: Then it depicts like six panels of like a journey through the Land of the Dead.
DM: And then the last panel sort of going clockwise around the room, um, shows the eight Masumuna gods depicted in sort of a circle, um, holding their
DM: arms out as if to, like, welcome the soul.
DM: And then there are two exits on either side of the large statue
DM: on the western end.
Unknown: Sure.
Wellby: What, what do they smell like?
DM: What does what smell like? The statues?
Wellby: Rats have... No, the two exits.
DM: Um, they, they're both right next to each other.
DM: They smell exactly the same.
Wellby: All right, I'll take the left door.
DM: The rat disintegrates in a burst of flame.
Wellby: It is always so traumatic when I am in the animal as it dies.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: My goodness.
Wellby: Not one of these has survived past 10 minutes.
Delwath: [laughs] Here's my idea.
Delwath: Make the trade, get the jade, Dimension Door into the bottom room be- beneath the acid, see what's there.
Wellby: Ooh. The room that the rat was just in?
Delwath: Yeah.
Delwath: Make the trade first so we have the jade.
Kenzo: And then we can teleport from there.
Delwath: And then if we have to, we teleport back to Milo if, if things go really bad.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Cool. Do that.
Unknown: We don't know where the boat is.
DM: Uh, I mean, there's a good chance you miss and end up just in the ocean.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Or we teleport to the monastery with Dimitaur.
Kenzo: But then we have to travel from the monastery, like, super far to get to the boat, right?
Wellby: We could animal shape. We could-
Delwath: Oh
Wellby: ... theoretically see the boat from the monastery.
Delwath: Right. In theory, we could animal shape into birds and fly.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Right? Fine.
Unknown: All right.
Delwath: Or we try the Rainbow Bridge.
DM: Man, that animal shape is a really useful spell.
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: It turns out.
DM: That was a good choice.
Delwath: Um, also-
Wellby: We can't Rainbow Bridge 'cause we can't leave Milo behind.
Kenzo: We can't... We can only Rainbow Bridge from the, the lair.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Well, no.
Unknown: But, but-
Delwath: That's a good point. Leaving Milo behind is probably bad, right?
Wellby: Yeah. I mean, it's a non-negotiable.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: But le-
Delwath: We can come back for him, though.
Unknown: What the fuck?
Wellby: We can come back for everything.
Wellby: We can come back for the jade.
Delwath: No, no, I mean...
Unknown: What? I missed something.
DM: If you Rainbow Bridge out, Milo, Tilly, and the halflings are still-
Unknown: And Milo
DM: ... currently circumnavigating the-
Delwath: Right
Delwath: ... No, I mean, come back immediately.
Unknown: Milo and them
Delwath: Right? Like, if our only choice is to die or Rainbow Bridge.
Kenzo: Wait, we can't Rainbow Bridge from...
Delwath: We don't... No, we don't know. We don't know if it'll go through the shield.
DM: You, you have no idea if the Rainbow Bridge can penetrate the antimagic shield.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Like, you're... But you know it can cross planes.
Unknown: Right.
DM: So if you're in a different plane-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... then theoretically you should be able to Rainbow Bridge.
Kenzo: Oh, holy fuck. This is kinda crazy.
Kenzo: Can we go inside, uh, the, um...
Kenzo: Can we go inside our portable hole and then Rainbow Bridge from inside the portable hole?
DM: There's not room to open the Rainbow Bridge in the portable hole.
Kenzo: But if there were, could we?
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: That's pretty fucking crazy.
Delwath: I mean, I think we have a number of possible escape routes.
Delwath: What the fuck?
Wellby: Could we go in the mirror and open the Rainbow Bridge from inside the mirror?
DM: Uh, yes, but you'd use an awful lot of cells because you'd have to join everybody up into one.
Unknown: We'd have to... Yes. Yeah. Yep.
DM: You probably don't have space for that.
Kenzo: That's interesting, though.
Wellby: Oh, but the mirror would be left behind.
DM: The mirror would be left behind.
Kenzo: Okay. All right. Anyway, so let's go, let's go, uh...
Delwath: But I, I think we're better off just short resting
Delwath: and chilling, right?
Delwath: Keep going until we're, like, somewhere...
Kenzo: Do you want to Clairvoyance inside of that room?
Delwath: Hmm.
Delwath: I mean, you could.
Unknown: Yeah. That's a good idea.
DM: Yeah.
DM: I mean, inside the room where the rat was you would probably just see what the rat saw.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I was gonna say, what are we gonna learn that-
Kenzo: No, inside the... Can, can you try Clairvoyance into the room that-
Seeker: The next room
DM: ... where the rat died?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: Yeah, that room.
Delwath: How well can you position Clairvoyance?
DM: I mean, you can just arbitrarily say anywhere.
DM: It's doesn't... You don't need to be describing it.
Delwath: Right.
Seeker: We can direct it, yeah.
Delwath: Perfect.
Kenzo: Just tell it however many feet from, you know.
DM: Yeah. Seeker's... I mean, Seeker is very good at, uh,
DM: geological math so [laughs] you should be able to guess roughly where the...
Kenzo: Wait, I mean, okay, do I have, like, a...
Kenzo: You know, with the, with aura sense, don't I have a very precise sense of, like, where the, um [crunching], where the fiend is?
DM: Um, yeah, it's, like, under the villa.
DM: It's in this basement complex.
Unknown: But, like... But, like-
DM: You don't know exactly
Unknown: ... Okay.
DM: You can't p- pinpoint it to the foot.
Delwath: Okay.
Seeker: Oh, the other thing we were gonna do is use that wand
Seeker: to, to detect nearest portal.
Seeker: The, the detect portal? Do you wanna try that?
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. Great idea.
Seeker: What direction does that face?
Unknown: Great idea.
DM: Um,
DM: so-
Unknown: Ah, there's one in the villa too
DM: ... the villa.
Unknown: Holy shit.
Seeker: Only there.
Unknown: Well, I guess points to the nearest.
DM: You're closer to the villa than the lair.
Delwath: Fuck.
Kenzo: Is that good or bad for us?
Delwath: Well, [crunching] and I think,
Delwath: I think we need to deci- I, I still think the right plan is to just-
Unknown: Get the jade
Delwath: ... play it straight with the dragon.
Unknown: Yeah, I think so too. I think so too.
Delwath: And then go try and see what's going on.
Delwath: Then, then go explore the villa 'cause we can't resist.
Kenzo: That sounds reasonable.
Delwath: Right? With the theory that
Delwath: if we, um...
Delwath: If something goes really wrong in the villa, at least we have the jade so, like, we kinda just-
Kenzo: Teleport
Delwath: ... run, right?
Kenzo: Teleport back to the, uh...
Delwath: But with Wellby's good point that we don't wanna, like, abandon Tilly.
Delwath: So, like, our best plan is to cast Teleport to go back to the...
Delwath: Well, or more likely-
DM: Teleport to the monastery
Delwath: ... teleport to the monastery, which would be much more likely to see than fly to the boat.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: But if we're in some extra dimensional space, we can't teleport.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yes.
Kenzo: 'Cause then we Rainbow Bridge.
Delwath: Yeah. But then we've abandoned Tilly.
Unknown: But then we'll come back.
Delwath: So-
DM: Yeah, you can... Right, but coming back is actually very-
Unknown: Tricky
DM: ... tricky because you don't have any other boats.
Unknown: We need another boat.
DM: [laughs] And you can't fly Vindristjarna through the antimagic shield.
DM: It'll crash.
Delwath: Right.
Delwath: And you can't, uh-
Kenzo: And there's nothing... There's no... There's nothing else.
Kenzo: If we're in the extradimensional space, there's nothing we can do to escape other than Rainbow Bridge.
Wellby: Can you walk on water? Couldn't you just run back across the ocean?
Unknown: I could. I could.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Run back.
DM: Can... It would be difficult because it's quite stormy, but Kenzo could probably try that, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I could run back.
Delwath: Um, I'm also, when we have a moment, gonna send the Winxies-
DM: Yep
Delwath: ... to give them a message that says we're trying something
Delwath: slightly stupid and dangerous.
Delwath: [laughs] Um-
Kenzo: AKA being our normal selves.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: And that if things go really wrong, we might end up far away from here without them, and to give them some sort of, like-
DM: Some number of days
Delwath: ... some number of days and just flee-
DM: Okay
Delwath: ... if, if, if like
Delwath: by tomorrow, the day after tomorrow morning-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... we have not heard back-
DM: Let's be sure. Yeah
Delwath: ... either from the... Well, then I can send the lynxes again easily enough.
DM: Yeah. Yeah.
Delwath: Right? Right.
DM: Right.
Delwath: If you haven't heard back from us in some form,
Delwath: right?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: And, and honestly, no, if you haven't heard from these lynxes, 'cause like if things go really wrong, we're gonna be like trapped by a fiend and geased into like killing them.
DM: Right.
Delwath: So [chips crunching]
DM: Okay
Delwath: ... if the lynxes have not given you-
DM: So you send the message.
DM: Milo writes back, "I see I'm rubbing off on you."
Delwath: [laughs]
DM: "I would expect nothing less
DM: of my dear friend Wellby than charging headlong into reckless danger."
Delwath: [laughs]
Unknown: Nice.
Wellby: Proceeding carefully into a thoughtfully measured risk.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Milo. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: And he says, "We will act appropriately.
DM: Uh, we have already found a tree
DM: that offered to make itself into a mast."
Delwath: Brilliant.
Wellby: A horse did?
Seeker: It, it offered?
Wellby: Okay.
DM: Well, Tilly's a druid.
Unknown: Yeah. Ah.
DM: She can also talk to trees.
Seeker: Amazing. [coughs] All right.
Wellby: So we are...
Wellby: Sorry. We're dimension door-ing into the tomb room?
Kenzo: No, no, no. Now we're clairvoyancing into the tomb room.
Delwath: But before we do anything, we're gonna come back and trade the throne for the jade.
Kenzo: No, but before we do anything, we're gonna clairvoyance into the, into the, into the-
DM: Okay. So you put the sensor like how many feet past where the rat died?
DM: [clears throat]
Wellby: Uh, was there visibility into the hallway past that doorway that the rat went?
DM: Um, oh, yeah. The rat would've been able to see.
DM: So it, the rat could see actually, there, there was a long, there was a corridor, like a 15 foot wide corridor that led down into the darkness
DM: to, uh, an opening at the far end that the rat could just barely see.
Wellby: Just inside that opening?
Seeker: Yeah, yeah. So, uh, if you can estimate that distance, I'll just put it there.
DM: That would be like, like 30, 35 feet.
DM: So 30 feet would be the...
DM: There's like 25 feet to the, to the opening, and then the rat could just see beyond it with its dark vision before it got flashed by flame.
DM: So you, so you tell me how many feet into the opening you want.
DM: One, five, 10.
Delwath: Five feet past the opening.
DM: Okay.
DM: Cast the spell. Ooh, this is gonna be interesting.
Delwath: I cast clairvoyance.
DM: Um.
Wellby: I'm gonna spin the top while he's doing that.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
DM: It's not spinning.
Wellby: Oh.
Wellby: [paper rattling]
DM: You see, um,
DM: so this, this is a, this is like a, a cross shaped design, right?
DM: Your, your, the eye is in the center of a crossroads, like where there's a corridor that goes this way and there's a corridor that goes this way.
DM: The, the two that go this way, the...
DM: I'll call them the north and the south corridors, lead to,
DM: um...
DM: They, they open up into small almost like meditative or contemplative spaces where there's like fine silvery ash that kind of forms like a, almost like
DM: a Zen sand garden in both sides.
DM: Um, there's like, uh, a couple of sort of darkened pieces of stone that have been arranged, that seems to have been untouched for many, many years.
DM: And there's, there's like nooks in, in all of the walls in those two passageways where somebody could like sit in prayer or meditation.
DM: In the direction going back,
DM: you just see this, this corridor, and you can see it looks like, it actually looks like a crypt.
DM: Like the walls are lined with
DM: hundreds of urns that probably hold the cremated remains of the whoever.
Delwath: All the kings.
DM: The kings.
Seeker: And one tiny smoking pile of rat bones.
DM: One tiny smoking pile of rats.
DM: It's clear that walking into the crypt triggered some sort of booby trap.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: In the other direction, um, the wall ends in a dead end, and you see a
DM: flaming red eye surrounded by a ring of shadows painted on over, like
DM: completely obliterating what used to be, um, that book symbol painted on the wall.
Delwath: The Cha'mutte symbol?
DM: Yes.
Seeker: It's a red eye surrounded by a ring of shadows?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Loser.
Kenzo: Is that the symbol of Cha'mutte?
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: So wait, that was just a, the end of the corridor?
Delwath: Wait.
Wellby: Was that always the end of the corridor?
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: That it just ended in a blank wall with that?
DM: Mm-hmm.
Wellby: Or was that like a constructed...
Wellby: Is there something behind that that you can see through?
DM: Uh, I mean,
DM: go ahead In Seeker and make a perception check.
Delwath: [dice rolling] 13.
DM: As far as Seeker can tell, there's, it's just a wall.
Delwath: Just a wall.
Seeker: I listen for a minute.
DM: Dead silence.
Delwath: Dead silence. Yeah.
Kenzo: Wait, the... Sorry. The, the, the, uh, the f- eye thing, that's a, a pattern on the wall?
DM: Yeah. It's painted over the symbol of the book with the flame that used to be on the wall.
Delwath: From the previous owners.
Unknown: Cha'mutte's dead, right?
DM: Yep.
Delwath: No, but it's, he built the prison.
Kenzo: He built the prison.
Delwath: Right, sure, he built the prison.
Seeker: What prison?
Unknown: The prison that the, the...
Delwath: Okay. Under the villa is a prison, right?
Unknown: Cool.
Delwath: We know that the fiend-
Delwath: Ra'ghemdros is...
Delwath: No, the fiend's part of the guards, I think.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: Ra'ghemdros-
Kenzo: I thought the fiend is what's-
Seeker: Oh, oh, the Cloudspinner's imprisoned down here.
Delwath: The Cloudspinner's imprisoned.
Unknown: Oh, man.
DM: The-
Seeker: Oh
Delwath: ... that's why I have to go, to free the Cloudspinner.
Unknown: Oh, man.
Delwath: I mean, could be wrong, but...
Kenzo: No, she's the, she's the secret, secret son
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: We got it, yeah.
Delwath: Exactly.
Kenzo: So, so the fiend is guarding the dragon.
Delwath: Pretty sure the prison was built by Cha'mutte.
Delwath: Seems likely, right?
Delwath: He would totally build a prison here.
Delwath: That's totally in keeping with his deal, right?
Delwath: The anti-magic shell probably makes it way better, right?
Delwath: 'Cause you can't...
Delwath: It, like, makes it a stronger prison, right?
Delwath: 'Cause it's hard to...
Delwath: It just en- en- enhances the ability to, right?
Delwath: He builds a prison here long ago.
Delwath: Maybe he even starts the plague from here, right?
Delwath: Like, obviously there's like-
Unknown: What?
Wellby: Practices it, yeah.
Delwath: Yeah. Like, like the... A whole bunch of people were killed by the plague, right?
Delwath: So, like, he has the... He takes this over, right?
Delwath: Like, it's his thing.
Delwath: And he builds a prison here, and then he assigns his daughter to be the prison guard,
Delwath: right, of the prison that's here.
Seeker: So when... There might be other entities beyond...
Seeker: in addition to the Cloudspinner in there.
Delwath: And I bet you the fiend...
Delwath: I mean, may... Either somehow the Cloudspinner's been turned into a fiend,
Delwath: right,
Delwath: or the fiend is not...
Delwath: But keep in mind, you can't sense things on other dimensions.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Hmm.
Unknown: Well, we know there's a portal here.
Delwath: We know there's a portal here.
Kenzo: Yeah. The th- there's a... The prison is, is, is in the portal.
Delwath: So, so I think the prison is on the other side of the portal, and there's a fiend.
Delwath: Cha'mutte was big into fiends, right?
Delwath: Like, Cha'mutte's whole deal was fiends.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah. So yeah, the sh- the fiend is the guard outside the portal.
Delwath: So the... Right.
Wellby: We have a portal detector wand.
Unknown: Yeah, we already used it.
Delwath: We used it.
Unknown: That's how we know there's a portal.
Delwath: There's a portal into Delwath.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Oh, oh.
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: We do know that.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: Yeah. So the fiend is, like, Cha'mutte's secondary-
Kenzo: So this is another s- this is another side quest.
Unknown: Right. This is, we're not killing the dragon.
Delwath: It becomes the main quest.
Kenzo: I mean, we'll see what happens with the dragon situation.
Unknown: Okay. All right.
Unknown: This is all good stuff.
Kenzo: I mean, w- we might end, end up having to kill the dragon anyways, but in the context of rescuing the, uh, Cloudspinner as opposed to, uh, you know.
Delwath: Like, maybe she'll show up.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Oh, that might be something that would draw her out of her lair.
Kenzo: Totally would. Totally would.
Unknown: That, that's that-
Wellby: And, and she's afraid of the fae.
Wellby: I mean, having the fae as an ally in the fight against her wouldn't be powerful.
Kenzo: Well, she's, she's, she's not afraid of the fae.
Kenzo: She's, she's just like...
Kenzo: 'Cause, you know, the whole time she keeps glancing over.
Unknown: She's not-
DM: I mean, she seems kind of paranoid about-
Unknown: Right
Delwath: ... breaking free.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: And she's obviously been injured.
Delwath: Right. That scar.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: That's some fae magic.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Wait. Is the Cloudspinner gonna be on our side?
Delwath: Yeah, definitely.
Kenzo: Definitely?
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: We should... Why, why would they come?
Wellby: At least when it comes to killing-
Delwath: I mean-
Wellby: ... the dragon.
Delwath: A,
Delwath: no matter how much the Cloudspinner has their own politics, like, who's not gonna be on your side when you broke them out of jail?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: They're now trying to kill their guardian.
Unknown: Kill their captor. Yeah.
Delwath: Right? Like...
Unknown: True that. Okay.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Plus, like, the whole thing with the orcs, I mean, like, Cloudspinner clearly-
Unknown: She-
DM: ... was the one who, like, freed, like, started the whole feud
Unknown: ... Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
Unknown: Totally. Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Right. She definitely has, like, that lore.
Kenzo: She's, she's our, she's our friend.
Unknown: A good guy.
DM: We could possibly- And the whole, the whole, like, Apollyon-Cha'mutte deal with...
DM: The whole Apollyon's whole deal and Cha'mutte's deal with her, she wouldn't give up the secret of the cloak.
Delwath: Right. That's why they got...
Delwath: That's why they, like-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... came after her.
Kenzo: Yeah. All right, let's do this shit.
Unknown: Go ahead.
Wellby: So this is a sequence question, right? It feels like it makes more sense-
Kenzo: We get the jade first
Wellby: ...
Wellby: I think it makes more sense to get the Cloudspinner first-
Unknown: Hmm
Wellby: ... and then kill the dragon with her on-
Delwath: But that, that assumes we have to kill.
Delwath: Like-
Kenzo: But right now we have a way of getting the jade without-
Delwath: Why don't we get the jade?
Kenzo: We're just gonna do the trade. Get the jade.
Delwath: Why don't we just do the trade straight up?
Kenzo: And get the jade. Then we go... 'Cause, like, the, the dragon's gonna come out anyways, but later.
Seeker: We're just buying the jade. It's totally straightforward.
Kenzo: Yeah. Because if we, if we do the Cloudspinner first, then we still have to do fucking acid lair and all this fucking shit.
Delwath: 'Cause then if she flees back to her lair-
Unknown: That's so horrible
Delwath: ... we have to go after her.
Wellby: All right.
Delwath: Into the acid lair.
Seeker: I f- I finally got my cloak fixed.
Seeker: I'm not doing any more acid. [laughing]
Delwath: Even with your ring of resistance to acid.
Unknown: All right.
Delwath: I think we just straight play it.
Delwath: I think she's gonna play straight.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Everything-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... we learned about her suggests-
Kenzo: Yeah. There, there is no... 'Cause she-
Delwath: She's gonna play the jade straight
Kenzo: ... she, she doesn't know that the jade is Rai's hand.
Kenzo: She doesn't know any of this shit, you know?
Delwath: But even if she does-
Unknown: Or she does
Delwath: ... I don't care.
Kenzo: Or she doesn't care.
Delwath: I don't think she cares.
Unknown: Yeah, exactly.
Delwath: I think she wants to sit on Apollyon's throne and pretend like she's, like-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... the emperor of, you know...
Delwath: It plays into her title, right? Like, it lets her, like-
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I think she's gonna really enjoy sitting on Apollyon's throne.
Kenzo: That, that's her shit. She, she's, she's dragon throne.
Delwath: Right? Like, you're giving Trump a giant golden throne.
Delwath: Like, of course he's gonna want it.
Unknown: All right.
Wellby: All right. So we do the deal.
Delwath: So-
Unknown: Yes
Delwath: ... short rest.
Delwath: I think we just short rest, do the deal.
Wellby: And then we dimension... After the deal we-
Delwath: And then we dimension door
Unknown: Into the building.
Delwath: Yeah. But we could also-
Seeker: We're saying like, "Bye, we're leaving the island," and but we're not.
Delwath: Correct. Yeah, exactly.
Unknown: Yeah. Totally.
Wellby: Just like we're teleporting.
Delwath: We're teleporting, right? But instead we dimension door.
Delwath: Like, like, she's not gonna...
Delwath: We're casting a spell where she can't tell.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: And because we know, because of the rat, we can figure out...
DM: You can calculate which any of those three rooms you can choose to appear in.
Delwath: Right.
Unknown: Awesome.
Delwath: Okay?
Unknown: All right.
DM: So if anybody needs to short rest, go ahead and do it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Um,
Delwath: we all still have hero... Let's see.
Delwath: I'm gonna short rest.
Delwath: I'm just trying to think if there's anything
Delwath: I want to-
Unknown: I don't think it has any effect on me.
Wellby: Is there inspiration to give out in advance?
Delwath: No, because it's gonna take it all...
Delwath: Everything's an hour.
DM: But you can, you can al- well, nobody's used their heroic inspiration, right?
Delwath: I'm just trying to think if there's any-
Unknown: Not today
Delwath: ...
Delwath: spells I wanna cast.
Seeker: So maybe just before we do the trade,
Seeker: I should set up both the ladder and my construct.
Delwath: But they can't come with us.
Kenzo: Through the dimension door?
Delwath: No.
Delwath: Do, do it after the dimension door.
Unknown: As far as you know, you're not teleporting.
DM: You didn't see any... You might be teleporting immediately into a trap.
Seeker: But there's no-
Unknown: But there's no-
Seeker: Not a fight
Unknown: ... there was no fight
Seeker: So I can do it down there. Okay. You're safe.
Unknown: Right? So you should have a few minutes.
Delwath: We can only take two people.
Delwath: You take one, I take one.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: That's it.
DM: You're very li- I mean, again, you could be teleporting straight into a trap.
Unknown: You have no idea.
Kenzo: In what? Through the di- through the dimension door?
DM: Through the dimension door.
Delwath: The floor could, like, do 500 points of damage.
Unknown: The floor could be lava, right?
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: I mean, their symbol is a flame, but
DM: you, uh, in none of the...
DM: You saw, you investigated all three rooms with clairvoyance and the rat, and there were no moving creatures, unless there's a dead silent, invisible creature.
Wellby: Which is very possible.
DM: Um-
Wellby: I like this plan though.
Unknown: Yeah, me too.
Delwath: I will re-up age just 'cause I haven't been keeping track of the time-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... before we short rest.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Okay.
DM: So you return...
DM: So how are you getting the thing, the thing out of the...
Delwath: I think we're gonna have to turn back into elephants.
DM: I mean-
Wellby: I'd like to be an elephant
DM: ... the most dramatic thing would be to, she knows you can turn into animals.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Show up
DM: as elephants dragging the thing behind you.
Seeker: Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: To her lair.
Unknown: That's a good idea.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah, let's do that.
Seeker: Oh, yeah, 'cause animal shape's still active.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It's still active. Yeah, yeah. I mean, you might wanna drop it and cast a better concentration spell once you get into the...
Seeker: But for now we can use it. Right.
DM: Yeah. Okay, so the four elephants come parading, dragging the throne down to the...
DM: You know, one dragonet sees you coming and flies down and, and alerts her, and you see her fly up and her wings, her wingspan is like 50 feet, something like that.
DM: And she's, you know, she's clearly extremely happy.
DM: She's holding this like tiny little jade in her hand, and she flies down.
DM: Um, for one, she's actually not paying attention to the villa.
DM: She's just looking at the throne and watching-
Unknown: Kenzo
DM: ... these like four elephants like-
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... dragging it in sort of, you know...
Kenzo: Yeah. As, as Ken- as, as we're, as we're dragging it and pulling it up, Kenzo, I'm gonna use a little cantrip just to like g- like get extra boom boots.
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Uh, I was gonna say. Uh,
Kenzo: Ra'ghemdros, Light Stealer, Final Shadow [laughs], Devourer of Drankor, the Last Empress of Kar, and the Eternal Knight and the Enslaver of the Secret Sunset, we bring to
Kenzo: you your new throne.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: She cackles. She like flies down, and she drops the jade.
DM: And she just like, without too much trouble, she grasps it with two of her claws.
DM: She strains a little bit to like lift it up into the air,
DM: like flies off.
Kenzo: Kenzo grasps the jade super fucking fast, like-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... ultra fast.
DM: The... You'll get the jade vision when you next long rest.
Unknown: Yeah, that's fine.
DM: Um,
DM: what?
Unknown: No.
Wellby: Yes.
Unknown: We got the jade. We got the fucking jade.
Unknown: Look.
DM: She flies. She's like-
Seeker: Big moment. Yeah
DM: ... sh- and she's holding it now, and she's flying around like showing it to the, um,
DM: uh, showing it to the dragonets and she says in a, in this like booming voice, "My servants, go forth and let it be known your empress has a new
DM: throne."
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: And she dives into her lair.
Wellby: Awesome. The servants are gone.
Wellby: The chimeras are not gonna bother us.
Wellby: Her attention is elsewhere. Dimension Door, here we go.
Delwath: Holy fuck. Yeah. Before we do, I just wanna think, do we want any other long duration
Delwath: prep spells?
Delwath: So I could, I could cast up to two spells that would last an hour and then use a ritual to get back my slots.
Delwath: Like, do we wanna be invisible?
Kenzo: That feels useful.
Wellby: Doesn't hurt.
Seeker: Doesn't hurt, right. Well- We just have no idea what's down there ...
DM: Dimension Door will break invisibility on you two.
DM: Why?
Delwath: It's casting a spell. Right.
DM: Oh.
DM: But they could be invisible.
Kenzo: Which is not unuseful.
Wellby: Doesn't hurt.
Kenzo: By the way, we did do this in the right order.
Unknown: I think so.
Wellby: Yeah. This is, this feels good.
Kenzo: Although if we'd gone to talk to her first, she might've been like, "Go bring me back the throne," and then we would've gone on a quest to go get the throne.
DM: Sh- yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: That's exactly what she was gonna do.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: We just made it easier. We just made it shorter.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: yeah, I mean, sure.
Delwath: We could do invisible.
Delwath: Or is it worth...
Seeker: Let's just save it. I think we should see what, see what happens out there.
Delwath: Let's just see what... It's only a minute inside, so it's maybe more flexible.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah, let's just save it.
Wellby: But we should've... Did someone attune to the ring of acid protection and fire protection?
Seeker: Oh, I don't have that on my sheet.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: So we'll just say it is.
DM: So you can pick acid and fire.
DM: That definitely seems like the two most useful.
Delwath: Ah, yeah. Yeah. Oh, yo, yeah, you can do both.
Kenzo: That's so useful. Yeah.
Kenzo: That is so useful.
DM: You also have a ring of fire protection.
Kenzo: I do, but I'm not attuned to it.
DM: If you want to swap it out for cloak.
Kenzo: For cloak. Ah, for fucking plus one AC.
Unknown: No, fright is also...
DM: Fright is also... That's true.
Wellby: Fright is really good.
DM: I'm into fright. That's probably better.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Um...
DM: Okay, so which room?
Seeker: Wait, I, I gotta pee.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Also, we got the last piece of jade.
Seeker: We got the jade. Holy shit.
Kenzo: Thanks for texting her, texting her full title.
DM: Yeah. [laughs]
Kenzo: That was actually a lot of words.
Wellby: Yes.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Fuck.
Delwath: That was like surprisingly...
Delwath: I actually thought she would probably just accept it if we did a trade.
Kenzo: But the tim- a lot... Do you know what I'm saying?
Kenzo: It's like if we had gone down the dragon first, she would've been...
Kenzo: It would, so it would've felt like we like achieved this big thing, but we didn't know what we were achieving [laughs] when we went there.
DM: Right.
Kenzo: And also, we just got the throne 'cause we're greedy.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Right.
Unknown: We almost didn't take the throne.
Unknown: So there was a good chance we might've just left the throne, and then she would've said, "Go get the throne."
Kenzo: Go, go get it and we would've gone back.
DM: Oh. [laughs] So it's convenient that you were greedy.
Kenzo: Well, we're just, we're just really into freedom and liberation.
DM: Yeah. [laughs] Um-
Wellby: Of objects
Unknown: ... objects don't belong to us.
Delwath: [laughs] But not so much the freedom and liberation of objects that we do actually possess.
Wellby: Well, they're already free.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: They're already free.
Wellby: Yeah
Delwath: Oh, by the way, don't forget my sword tells me if any fiends are within 120 feet of me.
Unknown: I know.
DM: Right now you're 1,000 feet away.
Delwath: I know.
Wellby: So which room are we going into when we go?
Delwath: I think we should go into the room with the glowing eye.
Unknown: I like that.
Delwath: 'Cause we know there's two traps for bypassing.
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: Why not bypass the obvious traps right off the bat?
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: I mean, the eye will probably immediately, like, cause us to
Delwath: be insane and try and kill each other or something like that, but-
Unknown: That's-
Kenzo: Wait, no, but, uh... So again, like, this cloak thing is so great, right?
Kenzo: Uh, everybody within 30 feet of me gets advantage on saving throws-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... to avoid being charmed or frightened-
Unknown: Yep
Kenzo: ... or to end those conditions on itself.
Delwath: Yep.
Unknown: That's awesome.
Kenzo: Let's just stay close.
Delwath: Yeah. The other thing to keep in mind, if we get desperate and we're fighting fiends,
Delwath: I can plant my sword in the ground and create a magic circle that fiends can't cross.
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: How big is, how big is the magic circle?
Delwath: Uh, it's pretty big.
Delwath: It's like 20 or 30 feet.
Unknown: Great.
Delwath: Uh, no, it's a 10-foot radius, so it's 20 feet across.
Delwath: Um,
Delwath: and
Delwath: any fiend can't willingly enter the circle.
Delwath: It can't even teleport into the circle without making a charisma save.
Kenzo: Are fiends typically, uh, magic users?
Delwath: They can be.
Delwath: Um, it has disadvantage on attack rolls, and targets within the circle cannot be possessed or charmed or frightened by fiends.
Delwath: But I can't use my sword 'cause it's stuck in the ground.
Unknown: So
Seeker: the binding stones
Seeker: can also do magic circle.
Delwath: Oh, that's good.
Delwath: That's useful. Takes a minute.
Delwath: I mean, the nice thing about my sword is it's an action casting time instead of a bonus action.
Seeker: 'Cause that's always been the problem with all the binding stone stuff.
Seeker: Anyway, I'm now-
Wellby: You can reverse the direction of it also
Seeker: ... I'm now de-tuned anyway, so.
Unknown: So.
DM: Yeah, you can reverse the direction so it's-
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... fiends are trapped within it.
Delwath: But it's hard for me to do that with my sword.
DM: But that doesn't really work for the sword 'cause it would have-
Delwath: 'Cause I have to willingly-
DM: ... to be trapped within it with the fiend
Delwath: ... Right. Now, I mean, I could.
Delwath: It's an action.
Delwath: Ah. It... Does it...
Delwath: It's not a spell slot.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: That's true, so you could do that and teleport.
Delwath: I could do that and then bonus action teleport.
Unknown: Except then it can take your sword.
Delwath: Then, then I'm leaving my sword behind.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Which is a little disappointing.
Unknown: That's it.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: Okay. You guys ready?
Delwath: Yep.
Unknown: No pressure.
Delwath: What's our, um... I... We're taking a break in a little...
Delwath: We're gonna start the dungeon and take a break in a little bit and-
DM: I think that's the plan
Delwath: ... like 4:00, you're gonna...
Delwath: thinking of coming with us?
Wellby: I think I'm gonna skip it. I think it's smarter to do even, so.
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: Just 'cause of the uneven ground.
Delwath: Difficult terrain.
Wellby: Difficult terrain.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: You gotta do what you gotta do.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Disadvantage.
DM: Okay, so you teleport into the room.
Delwath: Dimension Door?
Unknown: Dimension Door.
DM: Dimension Door.
DM: Both of you cast a spell. You appear-
Seeker: Oh, I have to knock that one off
Unknown: ... um, in the-
Delwath: Yeah, me too.
Kenzo: And we can still teleport from here back to wherever the fuck we want.
Delwath: Correct.
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: So you appear in, in the center of this, of this four-way intersection, right?
Delwath: Yep.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: uh,
DM: okay. So, hmm.
DM: Uh, so you probably both... You can't both appear in the f- You can't all appear in the same square.
DM: So let's, let's draw it so I know exactly where you appear, 'cause a bunch of things might happen at once.
Delwath: Why, why are so many things happening at once?
Kenzo: Yeah, I mean-
Delwath: I mean, no reason.
Kenzo: Is it like somebody shows up with popcorn and cotton candy?
Delwath: [laughs]
Kenzo: We have to decide which snack that we want.
Kenzo: It's, like, a lot of decisions around snacks probably.
Seeker: It's really... Is it-
Unknown: They're just gonna ask you, like, you know.
Delwath: Which movie do we wanna watch?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: It's, like, gonna be very overwhelming.
Delwath: It's like-
Unknown: Which soul?
Wellby: There are gonna be too many choices.
Kenzo: Yeah. It's gonna be like, you know, do you want a rom-com?
Kenzo: You wanna watch an anime?
Kenzo: There's too many.
DM: So this is, like, what you're, what you're aware of.
Delwath: And this is where the rat came through?
Unknown: Nope.
Delwath: Ah. Damn it.
DM: I'm, I'm drawing it.
Delwath: Okay.
Delwath: Ra'ghemdros.
DM: I may not, may not have made that exactly the right size.
Unknown: These are the stairs.
DM: The rat came down here.
DM: This is, like, the sarcophagus.
DM: This is the big statue.
DM: There's, like, statues around here.
DM: This room is all lit by-
Delwath: And there's, like, a wall there, yeah.
DM: There's a wall here. These, this is-
Delwath: Those are the two
DM: ... this is the fire trap.
Delwath: Right.
DM: You presume it's probably on both entrances.
DM: These are crypts. This is crypts.
DM: This is the Cha'mutte's Eyes right here.
DM: This is, like, zen garden, zen garden.
DM: That's crypts.
Kenzo: And there were no other stairs or anything else in them?
DM: No other stairs or anything, so just put your tokens where you guys wanna appear.
Delwath: And somebody has to be within five feet of Delweth, and somebody has to be within five feet of Seeker.
Unknown: Yep.
Seeker: Yeah. I think we're, we should probably put them
Unknown: maybe there.
Delwath: I think so, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Doesn't the zen garden feel safer, though?
Delwath: I wanna be in, in the direct path of the eye.
Seeker: So we'll, we'll just be on either side of Seeker.
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: And then Seeker and, I mean, Wellby in-
Unknown: Let's do that.
Delwath: Yep.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: That's fine.
Kenzo: And then... What?
Unknown: Like this?
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Or, like, maybe offset a little bit so that we're not-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... quite as vulnerable to line of effect.
Unknown: I mean, if the eye shoots lasers.
Seeker: Whose, whose effect, you know?
DM: Okay, so you appear.
DM: It's dark, but you all have darkvision.
DM: Um, it's quiet.
DM: Uh, nothing seems to be moving except Delweth.
DM: Which one is Delweth, Mike?
Delwath: Yep.
DM: Um, you're facing the corridor?
Unknown: Uh,
DM: somewhere off to your right about 30 feet away-
Unknown: Wait, to the right's the door
Unknown: ... is a port.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: Isn't this the, the, the wall?
Unknown: It's past the wall.
Unknown: Huh?
Delwath: Past the wall.
Unknown: Past the wall.
Kenzo: Past the wall there's a fiend?
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Delweth's sword is, like, glowing faint blue.
Kenzo: Can you, uh, do a ghast- like a, a Ghostly Gaze, look around?
Delwath: It's not a bad idea. Sure.
Seeker: I'll, I'll do Tremor Sense at the same time.
Delwath: Yeah.
Delwath: Um, but hold on.
Delwath: Let me just think for a minute.
Delwath: Do I wanna show myself to the eye?
DM: Oh, but
Delwath: I could see... I'm gonna go through the gaze from right here to start
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay
DM: And just walk through the wall right here.
Kenzo: You might wanna start calling your constructs too,
Wellby: and ladder and whatever, but-
Seeker: Well, I'm just gonna do tremorsense first as an action
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: So I can see 30 feet any-
Seeker: Oh, it's a bonus action, actually
Delwath: ... I mean, in theory, I should be able to see
DM: through-
Wellby: Yeah
Delwath: ... like any, any solid object-
Unknown: Yep
DM: ... within 30 feet.
Seeker: So I, I awaken the ladder also.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Wow.
DM: Put out the ladder.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: And I have 120 feet of darkvision now.
Wellby: Yep.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Ladder also sees th- so
Delwath: as long as the wall is within 30 f- feet, I can see an additional 90 feet past the wall, as long as I don't hit another wall.
DM: Yep.
DM: Delwath is looking into a
DM: large room-
Wellby: Can you draw it?
DM: ... immediately to his right.
DM: [sniffs] Um-
Wellby: Oh, boy
DM: ... yep. One, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
DM: One, two, three, four, five, six,
DM: seven. Okay. Uh, it might not quite fit.
DM: Oh, it just fits.
DM: Okay. Delwath is looking into a large room.
DM: Um,
DM: I need to look at my notes for exactly what you see, so but you can, you can draw these as I add them.
DM: So you can probably see into the whole room-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... because it's within
DM: your 90 feet of darkvision.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: at the far wall, directly across from the Eye of Cha'mutte, there's about a, a, like a semicircular like fountain that extends out
DM: about 10 feet from the wa- from the wall and then goes in a s- well, I can just draw it.
Delwath: So like that?
DM: Yeah, like that.
DM: Um, from which you can see like waves of heat, like shimmer.
DM: It's like lava in that fountain.
Wellby: The floor is lava.
DM: In the middle of the room,
DM: uh, sort of like right up against, right there, yeah, there's like a, a, a round stone table
DM: that's hollow in the middle,
DM: and there's, um...
DM: So it's like a, it's like a donut shaped table.
Unknown: Ah, okay.
DM: Um-
Wellby: Reception.
DM: What?
Wellby: Like a reception desk.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: It's, it's bigger than that. It's more like a meeting table.
Delwath: But is it big as-
DM: It's like, it's like an oval shaped meeting table.
Delwath: Oh, so it's like-
Wellby: How big is it across?
Delwath: It's more like that?
DM: Like that. Yeah, it's like that.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: Um, on the north wall, so up, there's a whole bunch of stone shelving,
DM: um, with about 10 books on it.
DM: On the south wall, there's a large mirror.
Wellby: Oh.
Wellby: Oh, perfect.
DM: And, um-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Standing in between the, um,
DM: the stone table and the lava
DM: is
DM: a large fiend.
Wellby: Friend like
Wellby: that.
Seeker: So maybe the-
DM: The-
Unknown: What was this? What was this?
DM: Books
Seeker: ... a prisoner is trapped in, in a mir- in a m- in a mirror somehow.
DM: Possibly.
Seeker: It's like another-
DM: Yeah. [coughs] Need a-
Unknown: ... kind of mirror.
DM: Uh.
Kenzo: Can you identify the mirror as an action?
Seeker: Um, oh, wait.
Seeker: So when did we use identify?
Seeker: That was yesterday.
DM: Yesterday.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: That was yesterday.
Seeker: So yeah, I could.
Seeker: I'd have to touch it though.
Wellby: It might-
DM: Is that large? Yeah.
DM: Um, this, this is actually a little bit...
DM: It's more like...
Delwath: You'd have to touch it while a fiend is trying to kill you.
Seeker: Yeah, so we might need to run.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Well, just if it's, if it's, uh-
DM: Yeah, this is the wrong place
Wellby: ... can you scatter us into the room directly
Wellby: from where we are right now?
Wellby: Like you can see, because of the see through walls thing.
DM: I can see that. I think you need a still line of effect.
Wellby: Oh, that's unimpeded. Sure.
DM: Yeah. So the fiend is standing right there.
Wellby: It's like-
DM: It's about, it's about 10 feet tall.
DM: Um, it's got horns and like a sh- cloak of shadow that falls off of its back, and it's holding a huge whip in one hand, and it's just kind of standing there almost like
DM: a statue, flames burning around it.
DM: Basically a balrog.
Unknown: But a small one.
DM: Small-ish balrog.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: It's only 10 feet tall.
Wellby: Drac is gonna teleport in here.
Unknown: I've possibly think we're in, like, in a good ch- position.
Unknown: You feeling like really happy and excited about how things are going?
Unknown: Are you sure? I-
Wellby: Over
DM: Maybe it doesn't... What does it target?
DM: Does it target-
Delwath: To target, you need line of effect to the target.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: But not to the destination.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: You just need to be able to see it.
DM: It dep- teleport spells either target a destination or-
Delwath: No, it targets like a person
Wellby: ... circle and drag
DM: ... okay. No, yeah.
Unknown: It-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... it, yeah. I think, I, I mean, just looking at the, the, the thing is unclear, but looking on RPG.StackExchange, the general-
DM: If the target is a person-
Unknown: ... theory
DM: ... and you can move them to a line of sight, you only...
DM: It's like misty step, target self.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Oh, no, misty step you need to see the target, but target self.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So if you can see through a wall-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... you can misty step through a wall.
Delwath: Yeah, it's the same. I mean, I need line of effect on these guys.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: It's 'cause it's six targets.
DM: Right.
Delwath: But I can... That's fine.
Kenzo: You can see all of us right now.
Delwath: Yeah, I could scatter us into the room.
Wellby: Wow.
Kenzo: That's brilliant.
Delwath: I couldn't scatter the fiend 'cause I don't have line of effect.
Wellby: Right.
Delwath: But I can see through the wall. Should we just do it?
Wellby: Hell yeah.
Wellby: Right?
Wellby: W- w- yes.
Delwath: Where does everyone wanna be?
Delwath: 120 foot range, so.
Wellby: What if Seeker goes at the mirror,
Wellby: and as your action, identify the mirror on your first round?
Kenzo: I think that's... Yes, I think that's strong.
Wellby: 'Cause, like, if we can... If it is as simple as, like, break the thing and she's released, like, maybe we do that immediately.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Seeker: All right. All right. Okay.
Kenzo: Yeah, I think Identify the mirror right away.
Wellby: Put you two in melee and the ladder-
Unknown: Yep
Wellby: ... I mean, to
Kenzo: The ladder, the ladder in between, uh-
DM: Yeah, yeah
Kenzo: ... the fiend and Seeker.
Delwath: So-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... I could bonus action scatter,
Delwath: but how does this work with initiative?
Seeker: That's a good question.
Wellby: It's... There's not a surprise round anymore?
DM: Um, so I would say
DM: I think scatter happens before initiative.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: It's standing guard.
Kenzo: So we still have to roll initiative, but you-
Unknown: But you still roll initiative
Kenzo: ... but we just get to be where we are.
Delwath: Turn, turn negative one would be s- turn zero would be scatter.
DM: Scatter happens before initiative.
Delwath: And then we roll initiative when we appear.
DM: Yes.
Delwath: Potentially he has disadvantage, but maybe not.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: And-
Delwath: Let's fucking do that
Delwath: ... but that means I do-
DM: You do get advantage.
DM: It might get disadvantage depending on how prepared it is.
Unknown: Right.
DM: You would be straight plus.
Delwath: But I, I would just...
Delwath: The spell is before combat.
DM: Is before combat, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Great.
Delwath: So there's no reason to, like, bonus action it or anything like that.
Seeker: Let's write down another...
DM: Yeah, you want to summon anything before you go?
Unknown: I can-
Unknown: Oh
Delwath: ... target only five creatures with scatter?
DM: Oh, so that's the five of you.
Kenzo: Wait, no, target five creatures.
Kenzo: You're targeting four of us. You're yourself.
DM: Plus the la- plus the ladder.
Unknown: Well, um, oh, oh, you have, you have to scatter yourself.
Unknown: He is one of the targets.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
DM: He has to scatter himself.
Unknown: Okay. All right.
Seeker: 'Cause... So I could do the summon.
Seeker: It m- may as well actually.
Seeker: I haven't tried this before.
Seeker: This, um...
DM: But you can't teleport it into the room.
Seeker: But it's gonna be in the doorway.
DM: Well, there's no doorway.
Unknown: What doorway?
DM: There's just a wall.
Kenzo: This is a wall.
Seeker: Oh.
Kenzo: Yeah. We're, we're subterfuging the wall if you're using this.
Seeker: So it's... There's no way to do the summon construct.
DM: I mean, there might be a secret door, but somebody would have to go touch the eye to find out.
Kenzo: We're doing this the hard way.
Seeker: I volunteer my construct.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: I mean, you could also just summon that...
Delwath: I mean, it would be...
Delwath: You could do that instead of the ladder.
Seeker: No, I already, I already got the ladder.
Unknown: You already have the ladder.
Seeker: Yeah.
Unknown: Um-
DM: Wait, you should check. Is summoning the ladder an action or a bonus action?
Seeker: It's...
Seeker: The ladder is an action.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Yeah. So you can-
Delwath: But it can attack with a bonus action, right?
Unknown: Right, right.
Delwath: So if you are casting your Identify having the ladder-
Unknown: Right
Delwath: ... on your turn, the ladder can attack and you can identify.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And then next turn you could summon the construct.
DM: And then you could summon the construct.
DM: Which can attack without any action at all.
DM: It just, you just tell it, "Attack the thing," and it does.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Let's do that.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Um, I am...
Delwath: Let's see. Uh,
Delwath: do we think we are in a rush?
Kenzo: What is that? What do you mean?
Delwath: Do you think it makes sense to prep...
Delwath: Like, I could cast Invisibility and then take one minute to get my slots back.
Unknown: Do you think we have a minute?
Kenzo: Right now?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Well, we can-
Delwath: Probably safe to wait a minute, right?
Seeker: We can watch the fiend and see if he-
Delwath: Oh, I can't 'cause that always goes to the gaze.
Unknown: I cannot wait a minute.
DM: You can't.
Kenzo: But what does Invisibility even get us?
DM: Well-
Kenzo: 'Cause we're gonna attack and then move it right away.
Delwath: Yeah, that, that's true.
DM: Well, you get, it gets you advantage on your first attack.
Unknown: Advantage on your first attack.
Kenzo: We already... Oh.
DM: Well, we'll probably have that.
Unknown: We're gonna get-
Delwath: No, but I, I don't have time.
Unknown: I-
Wellby: ... various advantages
Unknown: ... I, um...
Unknown: It shouldn't work
DM: You have to do scatter within the minute of ghostly gaze.
Seeker: Oh, oh, I forgot to do the, um, glove feature for the-
DM: For the ladder
Seeker: ... ladder,
Seeker: which will be... Oh man, but we don't-
DM: Fiends are almost certainly immuned to fire damage.
Seeker: Right. So maybe it should be...
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Can you, like, give it boosted speed or the, like...
Kenzo: Uh, Tim, can I... I'm gonna do, uh, Langal's Claw.
Kenzo: It's a bonus action, but I'm gonna do it in round zero.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: So I don't have to waste a bonus action on it.
Delwath: And I'm gonna use my Almeraca's Wand to get back a slot so that I'm more down...
Unknown: 'Cause I haven't recovered from Dimension Door either.
DM: Right. So you're only... Okay.
Delwath: Oh, no, scatter's not a slot, but I'll be full instead of...
DM: Yeah
Seeker: ... I still get to be full.
DM: So all this is happening within, like, the first, like, within a couple seconds.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: I mean, if combat goes more than eight rounds you lose the Langal's Claw, but it seems unlikely.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: You'd probably be dead if combat goes eight rounds.
DM: Correct.
Seeker: I will do the-
Unknown: Wow
Seeker: ... the water intent.
Seeker: I'd say things like that too
Seeker: ... using three charges.
Seeker: Wait, I used one before? Oh.
DM: No, no, you just didn't... You forgot to reset it from your Long Rest.
Unknown: It doesn't automatically reset.
DM: Oh, I have to manually do that.
Unknown: You have to manually reset.
Delwath: Yeah, items are annoying because you have to manually reset.
Seeker: Which is super annoying.
Seeker: Okay. So I use three charges to do the water effect on the ladder, which gives it the reaction when it takes damage it makes a slam attack against a random enemy within five feet.
DM: Oh, that's cool.
Delwath: So everybody, our positioning is gonna be Kenzo-
Kenzo: In melee
Delwath: ... and Seeker and the ladder in melee.
Unknown: I mean-
DM: Not Seeker
Delwath: ... Kenzo, Delwath, and the ladder in melee.
Delwath: Wellbee in the corner somewhere.
Delwath: Seeker next to the... Yeah.
DM: Just put, position you where you are.
Unknown: To the ladder.
Delwath: Um, I want to be away.
Delwath: I think we should be far away from the hot burning water.
Wellby: Do you want to put-
Delwath: You should stand on the table
Unknown: ... Kenzo-
Kenzo: Oh, I have 15 feet of punch.
DM: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: I'm gonna get over here.
DM: Fine.
Wellby: Do we want more between Seeker and the fiend?
Unknown: Yeah, the ladder-
Unknown: Is that enough?
Delwath: The ladder's large, right?
Seeker: Is the ladder large size or-
DM: Um.
Kenzo: No. We've never said the ladder is bigger than five feet.
DM: We've usually... No, we sort of alternate.
DM: You can choose when you summon it whether it's medium or large.
DM: It's usually large.
Unknown: I think you want it big. You want it to take up space.
DM: So take one of those large...
Wellby: Here's a large ladder.
DM: Here. Just use the...
Delwath: Here. Just put it on there so we can slide it.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Amazing.
Delwath: So the ladder's there. Delwath is here.
Delwath: That, like, blocks it. That cuts it from Seeker.
Delwath: You guys over here to pepper attacks.
Seeker: This time weirdly the ladder is, like, dripping.
Unknown: It's wet.
DM: [laughs]
DM: Water is dripping off it.
Unknown: Wet ladder.
DM: All right. Well, got it.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Holy shit.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Don't forget you have plus 20 hit points and Kenzo has plus 20 hit points.
Unknown: Ooh.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: What's that?
Delwath: The ma- eight. I cast eight again.
Delwath: I cast eight every day going forward.
Seeker: That's, that's the max HP.
Seeker: Amazing.
Delwath: So update your max HP by 20.
Delwath: Sorry s- sorry, Wellbee.
DM: Um-
Unknown: But the ladder doesn't get that
DM: ... go ahead and roll initiative.
Delwath: Yeah, it's not free.
Delwath: And the ladder wasn't-
Unknown: So you two with advantage, you two straight dice
Kenzo: 21.
Wellby: Holy shit. You rolled two 11s and I rolled two 11s.
Delwath: 19.
Seeker: Uh, 16.
Wellby: That's really improbable.
Delwath: 21, 21, 19, 16.
DM: You wanna switch?
Delwath: Is there any-
Kenzo: That is really weird
Delwath: ... is it, is there any upside in...
Delwath: We don't know where it's gonna be.
Delwath: 19 is pretty close to 21 though.
Wellby: We could give-
Delwath: But do we want-
Wellby: ... Seeker identify
Delwath: ... Seeker to get, go first, go Seeker?
Delwath: Maybe.
Seeker: I think it, I can... It could matter 'cause that could change everything about how we approach this.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Um.
Kenzo: What did you roll? What was yours?
Unknown: 16.
Delwath: Do you wanna swap Kenzo with...
Delwath: Kenzo, do you wanna swap with Seeker?
Wellby: And then I'll give you all advantage-
Delwath: Yeah
Wellby: ... presumably,
Wellby: when I hit relatively early on.
Delwath: Do you have to hit for that to happen?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. Okay.
Delwath: I think that's the right move.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Is it worth... Hold on. Can we, can Seeker give everybody one bardic inspiration?
Delwath: Yep.
Delwath: I think it's worth, 'cause then he doesn't have to use his reaction.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: All right. So we've all got bardic inspiration.
Delwath: Everybody's got one bardic inspiration.
Kenzo: We should all have one that we can use whenever we want.
DM: That you can use whenever you want. So you're down three inspirations.
Delwath: Four-
Wellby: And that's any roll whatsoever?
Delwath: Any d20.
DM: Any d20.
Wellby: Any d20.
DM: Four if you wanna give inspiration to the ladder.
Seeker: Oh, yes. I'm doing that as well.
Delwath: Okay. So you're down one ladder.
DM: So you only have one left for emergencies.
Delwath: You've only got one left.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: Do you wanna save, what, two for emergencies?
Delwath: [coughs] Well Seeker, Seeker would probably give one to the ladder.
DM: Seeker's definitely giving one to the ladder.
DM: Come on, the ladder has saved you guys so many times.
Unknown: The ladder-
Wellby: How much of the ladder has inspired us?
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: That's true. That's true.
Unknown: The ladder-
Seeker: Someday the ladder will give out the inspiration.
DM: So Kenzo and Seeker are switching, so Seeker's first.
DM: Seeker's 21. Wellby's-
Delwath: Seeker's 21, yeah
DM: ... Wellby's also 21.
Unknown: 21.
Delwath: Yep.
Unknown: And I'm now 16.
Delwath: You're 16. Yeah.
Unknown: Still pretty good.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: I mean, well, the fiend's probably... Well, anyways.
Delwath: I mean, the fiend might go first.
Delwath: We don't know.
DM: Go ahead. Seeker's up first.
Seeker: Um, Seeker, uh, puts the goggles on and glances over at the fiend.
Unknown: Ah. What?
Seeker: Realizes he shouldn't... What?
Wellby: Go ahead.
Unknown: No, no, no, go.
Seeker: Realizes he shouldn't look directly in the mirror probably, 'cause we don't know anything about what it does, and does a kind of like backhanded, uh-
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Nice, nice
Seeker: ... tapping it with a fingertip.
DM: Okay. The mirror is a scrying mirror connected to Ra'ghemdros's le- uh, lair.
Delwath: Oh.
Seeker: Which direction though?
Delwath: Fuck.
DM: She is watching everything you do.
Delwath: Oh.
Delwath: Smash it.
Delwath: Fuck.
Unknown: Shit.
Seeker: Um, and okay, is this, uh, um, when you de-
DM: That's your action
Seeker: ... what happens when you destroy it? Okay, I can't do anything else.
Delwath: Well, no, you can-
DM: What are you... What's your action? Sorry
Delwath: ... you can... Can't you as part of a move break a mirror?
Delwath: That seems-
DM: I mean, it's a magic mirror.
DM: It's not gonna just break if you s- if you hit it with a fist.
Delwath: No, if you just punch it, it won't, it won't, it won't break.
Wellby: Hmm.
Wellby: You want me to shoot the mirror instead of the fiend?
Delwath: Uh, it might be too late.
Seeker: But she knows now that we're here.
Delwath: 'Cause she saw us appear here.
Delwath: So I mean, maybe there's a tiny window where if we destroy it literally this second...
Kenzo: But it, it already doesn't matter. She's coming.
Delwath: But I think she probably knows.
Seeker: So wait, I, I can look for a second in the mirror.
Unknown: What do I see?
DM: No, no, it's one way.
Delwath: It's the other direction.
DM: It's from the lair to here.
Seeker: So it's just a mirror.
DM: It's just a mirror, and you see your reflection.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: So we don't know whether she's looking through at this moment or not.
Unknown: She, she, she-
DM: There might be a reason why she never, never leaves her lair.
Delwath: It's 'cause she's constantly staring through this mirror.
Seeker: But is she still showing off the throne right now?
DM: Maybe.
Seeker: So she's not in the lair.
Delwath: [groans]
Seeker: Is, is the mirror attached to the wall in such the way that if I took my cloak off, I could throw it over it?
DM: I think you can go that. She'd be...
DM: No, no, it's like, it's like-
Unknown: Oh, it's huge
Delwath: ... 15 feet wide.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: It's a massive mirror.
Unknown: Big old mirror.
Wellby: Oh, man, so we're not bringing it with us anyways.
Wellby: Oh, what a bummer.
Delwath: It's probably not that useful.
Delwath: Okay, so the question-
DM: Unless you want Ra'ghemdros to be able to spy on you from anywhere.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: Well, you could look. You could see what the weather was on deck without leaving your quarters.
Kenzo: I'll need to get her mirror on the other side.
Delwath: Conceptually-
Unknown: Then we can have the two
Delwath: ... maybe-
Kenzo: Send us some mirrors
Delwath: ... the ladder could try and do something
Kenzo: To destroy the mirror?
Seeker: I was thinking about that. Can the ladder do a forced slam on the mirror?
DM: The ladder could. I mean, it's, I mean, it's not indestructible, but it's gonna...
DM: It, like, it has hit points and an AC.
DM: It's like-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... gonna take some effort to crack.
Delwath: I... [sighs] So, so okay.
Delwath: There's one-
DM: Seeker has his bonus action, has the ladders up, so.
Unknown: Yep, that's-
Delwath: Can, can we have, like, 30 seconds?
DM: You can have 30 seconds.
Delwath: Like, 50/50 shot probably that she's seen us already.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: If she's seen us already, there's no point.
Kenzo: There's, so there's zero point, 'cause she's just gonna come here anyways.
Unknown: We-
Delwath: On the other hand, 50/50 shot, if...
Delwath: We also don't... Like, if one attack from the ladder could in fact break the mirror, there's at least a decent chance that what happens is she glances over and sees it's broken,
Delwath: and still is gonna come. She's probably not gonna come, but at least she doesn't know what's going on.
Delwath: But I don't know if it's worth
Wellby: I don't, I am skeptical the ladder can do enough damage.
Delwath: Can Seeker make an arcana check to have some idea?
DM: Yes.
Kenzo: Thank you. Thank you.
Unknown: [laughs] Oh, good idea.
Unknown: Thank you.
Seeker: I didn't think of that. Okay.
Seeker: That is a 27.
DM: I mean, a magic mirror of this size, you'd guess it probably is pretty easy to hit, but you probably need to do, like,
DM: 30 or 40 points of damage to shatter it.
Seeker: Ladder's not gonna do that in one go.
Seeker: But Wellby could.
Wellby: Probably.
Delwath: Can you sneak attack a mirror though?
DM: I don't think... You can't sneak attack a mirror.
Delwath: You can't sneak attack objects.
DM: Yeah. It's gotta be, and it's probably gotta be, like, bludgeoning force.
DM: Like, you-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... piercing. A arrow would probably work, but yeah, you can't sneak attack a ladder.
Unknown: No.
DM: I mean, a,
DM: a object.
Seeker: And so the, the ladder just has a 1d10 plus 5 attack.
DM: I mean, the ladder could-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... if you had 30 seconds, the ladder could smash it without any problem.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
Seeker: Right, right. Just by hitting it three or four times.
DM: Just by hitting it three or four times.
Delwath: Honestly, combat is probably no more than 30 seconds total.
Delwath: Combat moves fast.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So I think-
Seeker: All right, so the, the ladder needs to just attack the-
Delwath: I think our best bet is...
Delwath: I mean, unless she can teleport. The only problem is if she can teleport.
Kenzo: She can definitely teleport.
Wellby: But she'll be here in human form, not dragon form.
Delwath: She-
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: We don't know if she can teleport. She dove into the...
Delwath: She didn't teleport.
DM: She's, you've never seen her teleport.
Delwath: She swam.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: She wouldn't fit in this room.
Seeker: Yeah, but as, as, as a dragon.
Delwath: As a dragon.
Kenzo: Yeah, she does come, she has to come as a human or nothing.
Delwath: We don't even know.
DM: Can all dragons become humans?
Delwath: Not... No.
DM: No. Not all dragons can become humans.
Delwath: I think-
DM: In fact, that tends to be a trait of green dragons more than other dragons
Delwath: Okay, let's just kill the fiend.
Seeker: So the, the ladder actually should probably just attempt to grapple the fiend, I think.
Wellby: I think so
Delwath: Oh, you know what? We made a mis- t- t- Kenzo going first is super useful for this fight
DM: It's soul sight
Unknown: Yeah. We don't know anything-
DM: Well, too late.
Delwath: Too late. Yeah, grapple.
DM: I mean, Wellby's also useful for getting advantage, so...
Delwath: Well-
Seeker: Um, so I have advantage
DM: Now you can use your ability to not, to know if it's gonna succeed its save
Delwath: Against-
DM: Whatever you wanna do
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Seeker: So I use my spell attack-
Delwath: I might just fight it, though
Unknown: ... to let the-
DM: That's true.
Wellby: Do we just banish it?
DM: [clears throat]
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: Doesn't it stay there if it's banished?
Delwath: Uh, the new, the new...
Delwath: The banish doesn't, it's not perma-banish-
DM: Uh-
Delwath: ... unless it's a summon.
Kenzo: The dragon can't change into a human if it's-
Delwath: No, no
Unknown: ... it's gonna like vanish
Delwath: No, no. Aberration slash elemental-
Unknown: ... and be back
Delwath: ... fey or fiend
DM: Yeah. Go ahead.
Wellby: Especially because-
DM: That is attacking or trying to grapple
Seeker: So ladder is grappling the fiend
DM: ... right? That's a saving throw on its part
Seeker: And just for a 21
Wellby: ... chamber was absolutely-
DM: Well, it automatically hits. The fiend has to make a save.
Seeker: Oh, okay. That's not even an attack roll.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: And it's gonna have legendary resistance, though.
DM: It succeeds.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: And Seeker's turn is complete.
DM: Okay. Wellby, you're up.
Wellby: I'm gonna take steady aim and shoot the fiend and try to blind it.
Seeker: It's got eyes.
DM: Well-
Seeker: Hit him
Wellby: ... that's a 22.
DM: 22 hits.
Wellby: 22 hits.
Wellby: That's not great.
Wellby: That's 16 plus 6 is 22 with a DC 18
Wellby: something save. Uh, dex save.
DM: Uh, it succeeds the dex save.
DM: It bats your, um, your arrow just far enough away from its eyes so it's not blinded, but still scrapes across its face.
DM: How much damage? 16 damage is that?
Wellby: Uh, 26.
DM: 26 damage.
DM: Um-
Wellby: So I said-
DM: What?
Wellby: Uh, yes.
DM: Okay. And it looks-
Wellby: 22
Delwath: You plus, plus 6 damage
Wellby: ... 22 damage
DM: 22 damage, okay. And it looks, turns somewhat angrily at
DM: Wellby, but Delwath gets in his attack.
Delwath: Okay. Advantage, right?
DM: Advantage.
Unknown: Why do you get advantage?
DM: Wellby hit it.
Delwath: Wellby hit it.
Unknown: Ah, okay, okay, nice.
Delwath: Uh, I'm gonna bonus action mark it, hunter mark it.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: So 13 plus 10.
DM: 20 hits.
Delwath: Oh, wow, and I do a lot of damage.
Delwath: It's a fiend, right?
DM: Yep.
Wellby: Can you like mega smite it or-
Delwath: I do 40, 48 damage every time I hit 'cause my sword is like glowing with like-
Delwath: The elven vengeance anger, dude
Delwath: ... vengeance and the sword will like light up like 10 times brighter than you ever seen.
Delwath: There's like this whisper coming in Elvish of like, "Kill the fiend.
Delwath: Kill the fiend. Kill the fiend."
Kenzo: Elves are scary, man. I never...
Kenzo: Why do elves get
DM: [clears throat]
Delwath: Uh-
Seeker: It's a little, it's a little intense, yeah
DM: It is a little.
Delwath: So t- um,
Delwath: 4, 11-
Unknown: 16
Delwath: ... 16 plus 10.
Unknown: 26.
DM: Uh, 26 damage.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Yes. That's on my first attack.
Delwath: Second attack also hits.
Delwath: Uh, 10,
Delwath: 12, uh, a t- 20, 32.
Unknown: Damn.
DM: 32 damage.
Delwath: Yep.
DM: Yep.
Delwath: Third attack.
Kenzo: Also hits.
DM: Also hits.
Unknown: Holy fuck.
Delwath: 10-
Kenzo: The fiend slayer
DM: Nice and strong
Delwath: ... 10, 15, so 25, 35.
Kenzo: Damn. You did like 100 points of damage.
DM: Uh, at the end of
DM: Delwath's turn, before it goes, it's going to use a legendary action,
DM: um, and it is going to strike with its whip at Delwath.
DM: Uh-
Unknown: Is that an attack? It's an attack roll, right?
DM: It's an attack roll.
DM: Um, that is only a 20 to hit.
Delwath: That misses.
DM: It is going to strike with its whip again
DM: on its turn.
Delwath: Uh, hold on, hold on. Uh...
Kenzo: Yeah, use that, yeah.
Delwath: Okay, yeah.
DM: Um, that is a
DM: 30-something.
Delwath: Uh, mark of the hunter.
Delwath: Roll D6. On a four or higher, it misses me.
Delwath: Whoa
DM: It deflects off
DM: of Delwath.
DM: It is going to-
Delwath: Like a sh- like the frost of my shield-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... like, like this icy thing comes up and it just cracks.
Kenzo: Maybe we just let Delwath handle this one.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: I think he can take it by himself.
Delwath: I have a gift for fighting. Tim gave me a magic weapon.
DM: It's gonna attempt to bite you.
DM: That's a-
Delwath: Can't use my action again
DM: ... uh, 24.
Unknown: There's nothing I can do about that.
Unknown: Shield?
Delwath: I can't.
DM: Use his reaction.
Delwath: Ah.
DM: Um, and that's gonna be 26 points of fire damage.
Delwath: Oof.
DM: And then it's gonna slash at you with its claw.
Delwath: How many fucking attacks does this thing get?
Unknown: Four apparently.
Unknown: It... No, it used a legendary action.
Kenzo: And that's what's getting three.
DM: Now it's getting three.
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: And that's gonna be a 26 to hit.
Delwath: Jesus.
DM: Um, and that is gonna be-
Delwath: 12 points
DM: ... 6
Wellby: Maybe we don't leave it just Delwath [laughs]
Delwath: Yeah, maybe we-
DM: That's 12 points of force damage with its claw-
Delwath: We help
DM: ... as it turns in anger towards staring intently at Delwath.
DM: That ends its turn.
DM: Kenzo is up.
Kenzo: Fucking soul sight this motherfucker.
Kenzo: What do we know about him?
DM: Uh, it's immune to fire and poison damage.
DM: It's immune to charm, exhaustion, frightened, and poisoned.
Kenzo: CR?
DM: CR 20...
DM: Uh,
DM: well, I sort of made it up.
Unknown: Whatever.
DM: I'll say 25-ish.
Unknown: All right.
DM: Um,
DM: best save is charisma.
Unknown: Worst?
DM: Worst save is intelligence.
Kenzo: Any idea about wisdom? No idea.
DM: In between charisma and intelligence.
Kenzo: Sorry, what was it immune to again?
DM: Fire, poison, charm, exhaustion, frightened.
Kenzo: But now it's stunned
DM: Now it's stunned
Kenzo: Oh, it's, it's, it's... Okay, it's a, it's a...
Kenzo: To frightened, yes
DM: You can try stunning it
Kenzo: I can try stunning it. Okay.
Unknown: Okay, cool. Perfect. Okay.
Kenzo: Oh, and not force?
DM: Not, nothing about force
Delwath: All right. So it went Kenzo's up
Unknown: Yep
DM: Kenzo's up
Kenzo: All right. And I get advantage, right?
Delwath: Yep.
DM: Yep
Kenzo: Okay. So, um, first staff attack.
Kenzo: Oh, no, I'm using Langal's claw.
Delwath: Yeah
Kenzo: So I'm gonna do, um, punch.
Kenzo: Uh... Uh, that hits 23.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: 5 plus 5, so 10 damage and, um, stunning strike.
Kenzo: So he has to make a DC16 Con save.
DM: Uh, yes.
Unknown: Succeeds?
DM: Succeeds
DM: Yep
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: okay.
Kenzo: Second attack-
Delwath: Wait, did you say it was not immune to blinding, I guess?
DM: Uh, it's not immune to blinding.
DM: It just made the dex save.
Delwath: Yeah
DM: Sorry, how much damage did you do with that attack?
Unknown: 10
DM: Okay
Kenzo: Okay. Second attack I'm gonna...
Kenzo: I'm actually gonna use, um,
Kenzo: um, Fist of Planar Power
DM: Okay
Kenzo: It's, it's not immune to psychic damage?
DM: It's not immune to psychic damage
Kenzo: Okay, cool. Um, so what do I do for this?
Kenzo: It's a-
DM: It's a save. It has to make a saving throw
Kenzo: Yeah, 16, uh, 16 strike
Kenzo: Strength save
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Uh, that's a natural one.
DM: It fails
Kenzo: Okay. So now I do 3d10 damage
Delwath: No Legendary Resistance
DM: It's not gonna use Legendary Resistance on a punch
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. Fair enough.
Delwath: Fair enough
Kenzo: So I just do... I just, it's just straight 3d10, right?
DM: 3d10, and you can move it up to 20 feet towards you if you want
Unknown: There's-
DM: Or away from you
Kenzo: ... there's no... We're not... There's nothing that...
Kenzo: There's no need to move it right now, right?
Delwath: Yeah, I don't think so
Unknown: Okay
Unknown: Hold up, though.
Wellby: Yeah
Wellby: If you move it, would they get opportunity attacks?
DM: Yeah, because it's forced movement
Kenzo: Oh, that's actually a good idea. Uh, 19
DM: Okay
Kenzo: So that's the second attack.
Kenzo: Um, and now I've got three unarmed strikes,
Kenzo: or three flurry of blows.
Kenzo: Okay. So first one...
Kenzo: Oh, no.
Kenzo: 17
DM: Misses
Delwath: Fuck
Kenzo: Do I want to use my Bardic Inspiration on that?
Delwath: Nah. No, I don't think so.
Unknown: Okay
Delwath: Save your Bardic Inspiration for a saving throw.
Kenzo: That's true.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah
Unknown: All right
Delwath: Be cool
Unknown: All right.
Kenzo: I hit. Uh, this one does 20 damage
DM: Okay
Kenzo: And then the third final attack,
Kenzo: that also hits and does, uh, 13
DM: Okay.
DM: It looks kind of pissed.
DM: Um,
DM: at the
DM: end of Kenzo's turn, it is going to teleport to there.
DM: To right there
Delwath: To the corner. Huh
DM: Seeker, you're up
Wellby: Um, all right.
Wellby: Hidden door over there
Delwath: Or it's just there's a trap if we move past here.
Delwath: Um-
Wellby: Or area of effect
Delwath: Yeah
Unknown: Oh, it's going there to, like, blast the whole room or something
Delwath: There's gonna be, like, a heat blast or something like that
Kenzo: No, he's gonna, like, shoot up
Delwath: Yeah, yeah
Seeker: Um, I'm gonna summon-
Kenzo: How tall is the ceiling?
DM: It's like 20 feet. It's pretty tall
Seeker: Um, I'm gonna summon a clay construct spirit.
Seeker: So we also need a...
Seeker: And that is of what size?
Seeker: It's probably medium
Delwath: Medium
DM: Medium. Just grab a-
Unknown: Just grab-
DM: ... grab the orange die, orange d6.
DM: That's a good construct
Seeker: Oh, yeah. And that, that can appear...
Seeker: Occupied, unoccupied space you can see within range, so that's...
Seeker: Oh, the range is 90 feet-
DM: Yep
Seeker: ... so that can just go right up in his face.
Delwath: Can you put it over one, towards the wall?
Unknown: So left
Delwath: Yeah. Just to keep the path open
Seeker: Line of sight. There you go.
Unknown: Okay
Delwath: Well, I just I need to run up to it.
Delwath: I don't want too much clogging
Seeker: Um, because it is a clay construct, um, when it takes damage it makes a slam attack as a r- response
DM: Okay
Unknown: Cool
Seeker: Um, so similar to the ladder.
Seeker: So the ladder will just go up and attempt to grapple again
Unknown: Yeah
DM: Well, don't block... You probably don't want to block Delwath's path
Seeker: Oh
DM: Now, the ladder could fly
Seeker: Oh, yeah. Yeah
DM: With a 20 foot ceiling
Unknown: Fly up. Yeah
DM: So just say it's flying
Delwath: Yeah
Unknown: Perfect
Delwath: Yeah, the ladder's 10 feet up
Unknown: Right
Delwath: Punching down
Unknown: Give it a little...
Seeker: Yeah, acceleration
Delwath: Perfect.
Delwath: Perfect
Seeker: And so it makes...
Wellby: With advantage
DM: Yep
Unknown: It's a 10. Oh, why is it damage?
DM: The advantage is-
Unknown: Until the end of, uh-
Delwath: Until the, until the monster-
Delwath: Until Wellby's next turn
DM: Yeah, so it's-
Seeker: Ooh, crits. The ladder crits
DM: Nice. [laughs]
Seeker: So does that mean 2d10-
DM: 2d10 plus 5 force damage
Seeker: So that's...
Kenzo: 14. Uh, 13.
Kenzo: 13 plus 5
Delwath: Wait, what?
Unknown: 13
Unknown: That's a s-
Delwath: That's a 6
Unknown: Oh, a 6
Seeker: 6 and a 4.
Unknown: So it's 15
DM: 15 force damage. Okay.
DM: That ends Seeker's turn.
DM: Well, no, the construct can attack when you summon it
Unknown: Oh, it can?
DM: Yeah. It doesn't require an action.
DM: It acts immediately after you in initiative, and you can command it without requiring an action.
Seeker: Okay, awesome
Seeker: So that... What is its attack?
Seeker: Oh, I need to check its... [laughs] It 20 also
Delwath: Lots of, uh, multi attack
Seeker: So it gets two slam-
Delwath: What spell level did you cast?
Seeker: ... two slam attacks.
Seeker: Which s- I chose the-
Delwath: What spell level was it?
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: I don't know if I-
Delwath: What spell, uh, slot level did you use?
Kenzo: I guess I used six
Delwath: Then it gets three attacks
Unknown: Oh, yeah
Delwath: It's the number of attacks equal to half its spell level
DM: Ah, but at the end of Seeker's turn before the construct goes,
DM: it's gonna slam in, it's gonna s- slam it Delwath again with the whip
Delwath: Oh, all the way across?
DM: It's 30 foot whip
Delwath: Okay. Well
DM: Um, that's a
DM: 26
Delwath: Um, oh, no.
Delwath: Shield wouldn't help. I'll, I'll, um-
DM: Oh, you don't have your reaction back, back yet
Unknown: Oh, 'cause I haven't gone yet
DM: You haven't gone yet.
Delwath: Oh, wait, how did... Oh, it's his legendary action.
DM: Legendary action. Uh, and make a strength saving throw.
Unknown: Uh-oh. That's big.
DM: Um, you take 13 points of lightning damage.
Unknown: 20.
DM: Uh, 20 total?
Delwath: 19 total. I rolled a 20.
DM: Um, it pulls you into the lava.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: What? With a what?
DM: Make a dexterity saving throw.
Unknown: Uh, bardic inspiration
Kenzo: on your, on your strength saving throw?
DM: Oh, you can bard-, you could bardic the strength save.
DM: You could fail a-
Unknown: Or I could-
DM: ... natural 20.
DM: You can.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Or I could-
DM: It's a 19. It's a DC 24 strength save.
Unknown: All right.
Delwath: Let's see, 2d... Which is more likely to succeed, 2d4 or 1d12?
Kenzo: Matt, ChatGPT.
Unknown: Two...
Seeker: Wait, wait, so-
DM: You're gonna use your 2d12
Unknown: ... 1d12, right?
Unknown: Yeah, but I can do bo- I can do both.
Unknown: Oh, I'm sorry.
Unknown: Six.
Delwath: That's great. So what's the total?
Delwath: 20-
Unknown: 25
Unknown: ... 25.
DM: That succeeds.
DM: But you still do take, uh,
DM: 13 points of necrotic damage and 11 points of fire damage.
Unknown: So I'll just-
Kenzo: Fiend doesn't like you
Delwath: ... I'm getting beat up here.
Unknown: Fiend doesn't like you.
DM: He's got a glowing fiend sword.
Kenzo: I know. Fiend does not like you.
Unknown: And-
DM: Now the clay golem gets to go.
Seeker: So three slam attacks.
Unknown: Um, I have a feeling it's all with, uh, advantage.
Kenzo: You have a potion?
Seeker: All with advan- Oh, I better just-
Unknown: You should have a potion of greater restoration
DM: ... you can drink a potion as a bonus action.
Unknown: Grab a-
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: ... excuse my very 20.
DM: Can you-
Unknown: Another two more
Unknown: ... I do have
DM: a-
Kenzo: We should all have... I've got, we should all-
DM: It's three attacks
Kenzo: ... we should all have potions of, uh, superior-
DM: I guess
Unknown: ... restoration.
Wellby: You have to roll three sets of two
Unknown: ... superior restoration.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah. I'll just roll them separately.
Seeker: Okay. So first slam attack
Seeker: is, uh, it's with my s- It's the plus 10, right, my smell attack?
DM: Yep.
Seeker: So that's a 21.
Unknown: That hits.
DM: That hits.
Seeker: Second one
Seeker: is a 20.
Unknown: 20, that hits.
DM: That hits.
Seeker: Third one is, uh, 18.
DM: Misses.
Seeker: So two hit, and then it's, it says 1d8 plus 4 plus the spell level's bludgeon damage.
Seeker: That's 1/8 plus 10.
DM: Yep.
Seeker: Times 2.
DM: That's 2d8 plus 20. That, that clay golem's pretty good.
Seeker: I just need to do two-
DM: Seeker is just standing in the back commanding an army of monsters.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Of clay and more clay matters.
Unknown: So that's 12-
Unknown: 32 damage
Seeker: ... plus 2, 32 damage.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: Not bad.
Seeker: Good job, clay construct.
DM: Oh, no, not quite.
DM: It's almost bloody.
Seeker: Uh, that ends-
DM: That's Delwath's turn?
Seeker: ... the clay's turn.
DM: Uh, Wellby's turn.
Seeker: Oh, and how many hit points does it have?
DM: Uh-
Delwath: Oh, 'cause, right, we haven't come back to the top of the order yet.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. We haven't yet.
DM: No, Seeker's the top of the order.
Unknown: No.
DM: Seeker went-
Kenzo: Seeker traded with me
DM: ... Seeker traded with Seeker.
Unknown: I traded with Seeker.
Delwath: Oh, oh, oh, right, right, right.
DM: Seeker's the top of the order. Seeker went, legendary action.
DM: Clay went, Wellby went.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: Wellby's turn now.
Delwath: Wait, did it go between... No, I went before him, right?
Delwath: Yes, I did.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You went before Seeker-
Unknown: Before, you go after Wellby
DM: ... but it potentially has more legendary actions.
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah.
Wellby: So Wellby flies up to the top of the room, up here.
Unknown: Just 20 feet.
DM: Just 20 feet up, yeah.
Wellby: And should
Wellby: toss me a couple of d20s.
Delwath: Hell yeah. Do you aim for blinding?
Wellby: Should I blind or daze?
Unknown: Oh,
Delwath: what's the save on...
DM: It's all dex saves, right?
Wellby: No, daze is con.
Unknown: Damn.
Unknown: Which I-
Unknown: Are you c-
Unknown: You can... I mean, I don't know
Seeker: ... are you here or here, Wellby?
Seeker: The construct you're attacking right away-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... is kind of clutch.
Unknown: Here, here
DM: ... so that's good.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: That's what I thought. Yeah.
DM: Um.
Wellby: I'll blind again. Blinding's been good.
Delwath: Blinding's good. Anything, yeah.
Seeker: That's on thing for sure.
DM: I would say that's, uh, no, that's 20.
Delwath: Inspiration. Oh, 20 should hit.
DM: 20 hits. 20 hits.
DM: 20 hits.
Wellby: All right. DC 18 dex save.
DM: That succeeds.
Wellby: Uh, 10,
Unknown: 18,
Wellby: 24 plus 6 is 30.
DM: 30 damage. It is bloodied.
Unknown: How many, uh... Hold on.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: That ends Wellby's turn.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Still gonna try and pull Delwath into the fire.
Seeker: Oh, man.
Unknown: I don't have my reaction.
DM: That's a 22 to hit.
Unknown: That hits.
DM: Make another strength save.
Delwath: Oh, man. Guys, I'm gonna need...
Delwath: I guess I'm gonna have to 11.
Seeker: We'll remember you fondly.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Oh. Uh, 17.
Wellby: Do bardic inspiration?
Unknown: Bardic inspiration.
Delwath: Yeah, I'd have to roll an eight or higher.
Seeker: Or the heroic.
Unknown: Yeah, but that, that, that's heroic.
Delwath: You could... I'm not gonna do better than an 18 on a reroll.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I can reroll the bardic.
Wellby: Not terrible odds.
Unknown: Ugh.
Unknown: Uh.
Delwath: I could reroll it.
DM: You can.
Wellby: Not terrible odds.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: The whip wraps around Delwath's legs-
Unknown: Oh
DM: ... it's a very Gandalf moment, and pulls him straight into the lava.
DM: Make a dexterity saving throw.
Unknown: Nope.
DM: Delwath lands in the lava.
Unknown: Uh.
DM: At the start of your turn, you take 8d6 fire damage.
Unknown: 8d6.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Uh...
Wellby: He could, he could-
Unknown: I can hit points
Delwath: ... I have 60 left.
Unknown: He'll, he'll make it.
DM: Uh, did you get the-
Unknown: I don't know
DM: ... um, 18 damage from this attack?
DM: No, you didn't tell me.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: I have-
DM: 18 damage from that attack
Delwath: ... I have 40 left.
Unknown: All right. All right.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: He's probably survived that.
DM: And that ends... That's your turn, so 8d6 fire damage.
Unknown: That's your turn?
DM: Yeah, 'cause that was-
Unknown: That was my turn
DM: ... his legendary resistance.
Kenzo: Oh, now it's your turn. Yeah, yeah.
DM: Now it's Delwath's turn.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
DM: I'm gonna do the damage.
Seeker: You're gonna get out of there.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And that's my attack. I gotta roll a 10, 12, 14,
DM: 24, 25 points of fire damage-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... from the burning lava.
Delwath: I have 20 hit points left.
Unknown: Nice. Nice, strong.
Unknown: Um-
Wellby: Feeling good ... if you were like second level, that'd be amazing.
Delwath: Yeah. [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: I can just... Uh, uh, I can move, right?
DM: Um, yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: You can move. I would say it's gonna take you, like...
DM: I mean, it's, like, difficult terrain to climb out.
Delwath: Well, I only need three.
DM: It'll take, like-
Delwath: I don't need a lot of move
DM: ... yeah
Delwath: ... to get uncovered.
DM: Say it costs 10 feet of movement to climb out.
Delwath: Can you... You can't use a potion as...
Delwath: You can't... Can you drink a potion as a free object interaction as part of moving?
DM: Nope.
Unknown: But it's a bonus action.
DM: It's a bonus action.
Delwath: Better drink a potion instead of-
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah
Unknown: ... um.
Wellby: Yeah. This one.
Unknown: Drink the potion.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Instead of attacking?
Delwath: No, no, no, no, no. Instead of
Delwath: bonus act- I mean, I have another...
Delwath: I was gonna cast my spell that adds 2d6 to all my attacks
Delwath: But
Delwath: I'm not gonna kill him this turn, and I'll die next turn if I don't heal.
Delwath: I'll probably die next turn anyway, but-
Seeker: He's mad at you.
Delwath: [laughs] Um-
Seeker: The fiend has a bit of a thing for Delwath
Delwath: ... screw it. Uh, guys, when I go down, somebody heal me, please.
Unknown: We got you.
Delwath: That's all right.
DM: Yeah, we got you.
Wellby: All right. What's going on?
DM: Delwath is underneath the...
DM: is underneath the ladder, right?
Delwath: Yeah, like, I, I can't really fit there.
DM: Yeah, that's fine.
Delwath: I'm standing under the ladder-
DM: You're standing under the ladder
Delwath: ... in front of the fiend. Yeah, I'm, I'm drinking a potion, so 8d4, I'm just gonna roll that on.
DM: I mean, so y- wait, just to confirm, your sword does radiant damage, right?
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: But-
DM: You also notice that the wounds-
Wellby: 37
DM: ... so the wounds that everybody else makes would be closing up except for the radiant damage that Delwath is dealing.
Delwath: No.
Delwath: The bonus damage is radiant.
DM: Yeah.
DM: It regenerates each turn unless it takes radiant damage.
Wellby: Oh, any radiant damage that turn.
DM: Any radiant damage that turn-
DM: Prevents it from regenerating
DM: ... prevents regeneration.
Wellby: Awesome.
DM: So it's-
Unknown: I'm really pissed at Delwath
Delwath: ... 50 hit points left.
Delwath: Like I said, I'm probably going down, but I have my reaction back.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: That's good.
Delwath: So that helps.
Wellby: You got this.
Delwath: All right. Attack number one, I'm smiting this.
Delwath: I'm gonna smite, but-
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Oh, wait.
Wellby: Natural 20.
Delwath: 20. I'm out.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh, shit.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: Aljur's Smite doesn't take a reaction.
Delwath: It doesn't take a bonus action?
Delwath: It doesn't, it's just... Okay.
Delwath: So plus-
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: All right, all right. I'm smiting this guy on my crit.
Delwath: Aljur's Smite does 6d8, plus I'd be 4d8, so 20d8.
Kenzo: Shut the fuck up.
Wellby: Holy cow.
Unknown: [laughs] That's, that's a lot of d8s.
Delwath: [laughs]
Unknown: That's pretty good. I don't think you're gonna kill it 'cause you only just bloodied it, but-
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. But let's see.
Unknown: 20d8.
Wellby: If we were-
Delwath: I'm gonna, I'm gonna roll 10 at a time.
Delwath: 20d8, yes.
Unknown: That could be it.
DM: That's a good, that's a good amount of damage that could be.
Delwath: The, the elven sword like just lights with a blinding radiant magic.
Delwath: Like, did I do... Yeah, 'cause-
DM: Yeah, that's right
Delwath: ... plus one plus five is six.
DM: Plus four is 10.
Delwath: Plus the four I normally do.
DM: Probably.
Delwath: Three plus one. Okay.
Unknown: What the fuck?
Delwath: First round-
Seeker: They don't go on there because... Okay.
Delwath: Wow.
Wellby: That was 11 eights.
Delwath: I rolled fi- six eights.
Delwath: Holy shit.
Delwath: That's practically... Okay.
Delwath: What's the max damage? I did two, three, two, four, five, six.
Delwath: Did six points less than max damage on that roll.
DM: So 80.
Delwath: 80.
DM: Minus six.
Delwath: 74.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Holy.
Delwath: That's only half the damage.
Delwath: I'm pissed at this guy, too.
Delwath: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: Still very good.
Delwath: Still a good roll.
DM: Awesome.
Delwath: 15, 20,
Delwath: 30,
Delwath: 44 plus eight,
Delwath: 52.
Wellby: Plus six.
Delwath: Oh, plus six is 58.
Delwath: So 58 plus 76 plus 10 from my plus 10.
DM: 58. I, I already got the 74.
Delwath: Uh, 74, sorry. So another 58, another 68.
Unknown: That's a huge-
DM: And you're adding your proficiency for-
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. That's why plus 10 instead of plus five
DM: ... yeah.
Unknown: That's a huge amount of damage.
Wellby: What was the total damage?
DM: It's pretty hurt. After Delwath's turn-
Delwath: That was only my first attack
Unknown: ... it was like 140.
Delwath: I have two more attacks.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: [laughs] That was like 140.
Delwath: Okay.
Kenzo: Well, you were able to get out of the lava and then do the th-
Delwath: I jumped out of the lava, sword first, whacked at the damn thing.
Delwath: I used my move. I drunk a potion on the way.
Unknown: What the fuck?
DM: Man.
Wellby: Crit number two. Oh.
Delwath: No. 16. That's gonna miss.
Unknown: Miss.
Delwath: Third attack.
Delwath: 17.
DM: Yes.
Kenzo: Well, I mean, you can be pretty satisfied with that.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: After Delwath's turn-
DM: After Delwath's turn
DM: ... before it starts its turn-
Unknown: Oh, no
Delwath: ... a wall of fire-
Delwath: ... appears.
Unknown: Oh, no.
DM: Give me a marker.
Seeker: Black one.
Wellby: Oh, no.
Seeker: There's a blue one. There's a purple one.
Delwath: Right there.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Trapping the two constructs and Delwath inside with the fire.
DM: The flame is facing in.
DM: It's immune to fire.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So-
Delwath: So I get a save?
Wellby: Is Wyath's disturbing?
Delwath: Uh-
Unknown: It's opaque. None of you can see.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: Yes. Um-
Wellby: Because the three people outside all do ranged attacks and-
DM: Each creature in the area-
Unknown: But it's opaque. You can't see through it
DM: ... each creature in the area gets a dex save.
DM: So construct, ladder, and Delwath all get dex saves.
Wellby: How tall is it?
DM: Uh-
Unknown: The fire
DM: ...
DM: uh, it goes all the way to the ceiling. It's 20 feet high.
Unknown: Wait, is it casting a spell?
DM: Yeah, it's casting a spell.
Delwath: Would Counterspell work?
DM: It gets a save, so it could use a Legendary Resistance.
Delwath: I'm using Amica to tell me-
DM: Oh
Delwath: ... if it would work.
DM: Oh.
Delwath: But you have to decide if it's using Legendary Resistance.
DM: Yes, it would work. It's using a Legendary Resistance.
Delwath: So it would not work.
DM: It would not work.
Delwath: So there's no point in casting it.
Delwath: It's not gonna work.
Kenzo: Well, it, it could, it burns the, burns the Legendary Resistance.
Delwath: I know, but why trade a spell slot for Legendary Resistance?
Wellby: All right.
Delwath: I don't think, I don't think it's worth it.
DM: I don't think so either.
Delwath: 'Cause I only have one slot.
Delwath: Or no, I have two spell slots left.
Seeker: Um, so the dex save for the
Seeker: fire.
Delwath: Uh, 14 dex save.
DM: Uh, that fails.
Seeker: Fuck. The ladder has a plus two.
Seeker: That's a 15.
Delwath: I mean, you guys know there's no way I'm...
Delwath: I'm gonna be down after its turn.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I don't think I can survive.
Wellby: Can you dispel magic on the wall of fire?
Seeker: And the construct rolls a 19.
DM: Okay, so that's nine,
DM: eight,
DM: two. So 19 points of fire damage if you fail, half that if you succeed.
Seeker: I am, I don't...
Unknown: Whatever.
Kenzo: Round up or down?
DM: Round, round down.
Seeker: So the ladder-
DM: It's a 19.
Delwath: How much damage?
DM: 19 damage.
Seeker: The ladder failed.
Wellby: Survived.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: And then the, the-
Delwath: Yeah, I'm okay, but I just, now I'm down to 30 hit points
Seeker: ... and the construct succeeded.
Delwath: It gets three attacks.
Seeker: So that's 10.
Kenzo: Oh, that's its first. It's cast a spell.
DM: That was its... That's, that uses up-
DM: That's a legendary action
DM: ... its legendary action before its turn
Unknown: So wait.
Delwath: So now it's gonna get three attacks on me.
Unknown: So the-
Wellby: Then, now it's its turn?
DM: Now it's its turn.
Seeker: Wait, wait, but the, um, the construct has the berserk lashing response.
Delwath: Oh, so it-
Unknown: So it gets-
Delwath: But that's to a spell, not a... Is it only to melee attacks or can...
Seeker: It says the trigger is the spirit takes damage from a range.
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Nope, it can attack.
Seeker: So that's a slam attack.
Unknown: Nice. [clears throat]
Seeker: Um, so that's just [dice rolling] a 20.
Seeker: That's a 21.
DM: That hits. Maybe it'll f- maybe it'll fail its concentration save.
Seeker: Concentration. And then the, um...
Seeker: It's one D8 plus [dice rolling] 10.
Unknown: I would...
DM: Can you use legendary resistance?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: 'Cause it's a save, but it would burn a legendary resistance.
Unknown: Is that a 15?
Unknown: No, that's worth it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Totally worth it.
Seeker: Where's D8? Um, [dice rolling] so that's, um-
DM: 16
Seeker: ... 16.
DM: So the, the thing punches it, and for a moment it, it's been so focused on, um, on Del- on just Delwath is all it cares about, that the,
DM: that the
DM: golem's punch catches it totally by surprise, and for a moment the spell flickers.
DM: And then it burns a legendary resistance to maintain concentration.
Seeker: What's up, construct?
Unknown: And then-
DM: So then, um...
Delwath: Legendary resistance means it can choose
DM: ... if it's, if anytime you fail a save it can choose to succeed.
Unknown: Ah, okay.
Unknown: Right. And then-
Delwath: There's no way around it 'cause it's just literally choosing to succeed.
Seeker: So the, the ladder also gets...
DM: A reaction
Seeker: ... a reaction because of the water-
DM: Yeah
Seeker: ... feature. When it takes damage it makes a slam attack, so it's a slam attack basically.
DM: [laughs] So that one...
Unknown: [clapping] Thank you, Seeker, you're a friend.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: That was also a funny scene.
Unknown: You're like trapped in the middle of a ladder and a clay golem.
Unknown: Wait, how much damage did the, the 60?
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: All right, and so now the ladder-
Unknown: A wet ladder. [laughs]
Seeker: The wet ladder, sizzling-
Seeker: From the fridge
Seeker: ... remains. [dice rolling] That's a 28-
DM: That hits
Seeker: ... to hit. No. Is that right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: That's a 28 to hit. [dice rolling] And so it does-
DM: That time it succeeds naturally on the con save.
Seeker: Um, and what is the-
Kenzo: Why does it have to roll con save?
Delwath: ... that thing's concentration?
DM: 'Cause it did concentration on the wall of fire.
Unknown: Oh, anytime it gets hit.
DM: Anytime it gets hit.
Unknown: The slam attack is-
Kenzo: Oh, that's good
Seeker: ... one 10, which is five
Unknown: ... well, maybe. Fuck.
Delwath: The, the problem is it's opaque, so you guys can't target it with attacks.
DM: You have to come through it in order to-
Kenzo: Ah, but I, I can still just punch through it.
Wellby: Oh, but it always moves with disadvantage.
Unknown: No, it means you, you can't see.
Unknown: But so there's only like-
DM: You have disadvantage on the attack.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah. 'Cause you can't see it.
Seeker: So the ladder does 11.
DM: Okay. But it succeeded on that concentration check.
DM: It's, it's below 100 hit points.
DM: [dice rolling]
Seeker: Good job, everybody. Go team.
Unknown: All right.
DM: Now it turns to Delwath.
Kenzo: Now Operation Delwath Survive begins.
DM: Bite attack is a
DM: 24.
DM: [dice rolling]
Delwath: I think I'm gonna cast Shield, and so I have two s- ways I can do it.
Delwath: I can boost my AC to 26.
Unknown: Yep, Shield.
Delwath: That'll last for the entire...
Delwath: Yeah, I'm gonna cast Shield.
Unknown: Oh, yeah. Hell yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: It'll last for the whole, the whole-
Delwath: It'll last till my next turn.
Unknown: [dice rolling]
Unknown: Yep. What's that?
DM: That's a 27 on the claw.
Unknown: That hits.
Unknown: Fuck.
DM: That's 16 points of force damage.
Unknown: That's okay.
Unknown: And then the whip.
Unknown: Oh, no.
Unknown: 26 or below. [dice rolling]
DM: That's a
DM: 27.
Unknown: Fuck.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: That's...
Delwath: I'm not gonna survive that. [dice rolling]
Wellby: What do you have, 14, 17?
Seeker: 17. Can the ladder fl- pick him up and fly him out when he goes down?
DM: That's, [dice rolling] that's 13 points of lightning damage-
Unknown: Ow
DM: ... plus-
Unknown: Ow. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Ow.
DM: ... 14 point... Or sorry, not lightning.
DM: 14 points of fire damage and for- 13 points of fire damage and 14 points of necrotic damage.
Unknown: No.
DM: Delwath goes down, but that ends its turn, so it can't stab you dead.
DM: [dice rolling] Kenza, you're up.
Unknown: All right. Um, [sighs] fuck.
Kenzo: Do I, um, Step of the Wind and pull you out of there?
DM: I mean, this thing looks like it's about to cut Delwath's head off.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: That seems smart.
Delwath: Oh, can you just move me?
DM: Yep.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Delwath: Without moving you. No, no, no.
DM: He has to run.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: But he can r- he can use Step of the Wind.
DM: He can run in, punch it twice, grab you, and run out.
Wellby: And take damage from the wall of fire.
DM: You will take damage from the wall of fire.
Wellby: Whatever. Fine.
Wellby: Do you have fire resistance?
DM: No, no.
Unknown: I do.
DM: Seeker, Seeker, who's been ignored the entire combat.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: I think everybody's been ignored.
DM: Everybody's been ignored.
DM: Nobody's been taking damage.
DM: Nobody's taking damage except Delwath.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. No. [laughs] But that would be good, right?
Wellby: It's so good.
Seeker: Step of the Wind would get you out of there.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. Fuck.
Kenzo: Um, let me just think for a second here.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: I guess you don't want to push him or move him anywhere, right?
Seeker: Why did he go in that corner?
Delwath: To cast the wall of fire.
DM: He went in that corner to pull Delwath into the lava.
Seeker: Right.
Delwath: But that also-
DM: That also set up the wall of fire
Delwath: ... it's a pretty defensible position for him.
Kenzo: All right. So, um, how much move do I have?
Kenzo: How do I find out my m- what?
Unknown: It's like a g- good deal.
Unknown: If you use Step of the Wi- it's...
Kenzo: It's a lot.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It's 65.
Unknown: Uh.
DM: It's that number right there.
Kenzo: Yeah, it's 65.
DM: And with Step of the Wind, that's doubled, so you can run 130 feet.
Kenzo: Okay. All right. So I can get you out of there.
DM: So you can run like four laps around the room.
Kenzo: Okay. I will, I'll do that just for effect.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Just like Kenza starts, like, running really fast.
Delwath: Punch him, drop me off next to Seeker.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And then run back so that you're within range.
Kenzo: Yeah, perfect. So okay, so...
DM: Okay, so when you run through the wall of fire, let me just double check.
Delwath: You take the wall of fire damage twice, but-
DM: Um-
DM: ... it's fine. It's okay
DM: ... no. When it enters the wall for the first time on his turn.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: So you take 5d8 fire damage.
Unknown: You don't get a save to resist it 'cause you're running through it.
Unknown: Fuck. [dice rolling]
Unknown: So you take, oof, three.
DM: [dice rolling]
Unknown: Man. All right.
DM: 11.
DM: [dice rolling] 16 points of fire damage.
Wellby: Does evasion half that, or is that not relevant since you jumped out of the way?
DM: Uh, no, because, so if when the wall appears you can try and jump out of the way-
Wellby: All right
DM: ... and avoid the damage.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: But if you run through it, you just take the damage.
Wellby: Yeah, fair.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: All right. So I'm in here. Um, and I will, uh,
Unknown: uh... Wait. Hold on.
DM: What, what, what are we doing?
DM: Um, um.
Kenzo: No, I'm gonna attack it twice and then leave.
DM: Attack it and then leave.
Unknown: Yeah. Okay.
Seeker: Yeah. With Delwath.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: Don't forget about him.
Kenzo: Wait, but why can I only at... Oh yeah, 'cause I attacked it twice.
Delwath: As your bonus, you're using your bonus action to move.
Kenzo: To do, to do the Step of the Wind. Okay.
Kenzo: All right Um, okay, cool.
Kenzo: Then I'm gonna at- well, I don't need Len'ghal's Claw anymore, so I'm just gonna attack with my staff.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: And, um, I don't have advantage, right?
DM: No.
Delwath: Correct.
Kenzo: Wow, this feels, feels so naked.
Delwath: Right?
DM: Yeah. [laughs]
Kenzo: Feels so naked rolling without advantage.
DM: [laughs] Just single d20.
Kenzo: Okay. I hit it very well.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: oh, and then now this is...
Kenzo: Oh, actually, you know what? I still use the claw 'cause I, I get the b-
DM: You get the bonus.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: It's better than just using the claw.
Kenzo: Okay, I'll use the claw.
Kenzo: So that does 15 damage, first attack.
Kenzo: Um, oh, and I'll do stunning strike.
DM: Maybe it'll fail, but it's still got two...
DM: Uh, crappy roll.
Unknown: If-
DM: But burns another legendary resistance.
Kenzo: Nice, nice. All right, we like that.
Kenzo: Okay, second attack.
Delwath: Try a counterspell.
Kenzo: 21 hits.
Kenzo: Uh, seven damage.
Kenzo: Um, and now I will step of the wind, grab-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... Delwath.
DM: So Delwath also fails a death save for being pulled through the fire.
Seeker: Oh.
Delwath: Ouch.
DM: Drop him off.
Kenzo: Um, but hold on here.
Kenzo: I can do stuff for people that are dying.
Kenzo: Um, what are the things I can do?
DM: But you've already used your action and your bonus action-
Unknown: Yeah, I have
DM: ... so you're pretty much done.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: But Seeker c- Seeker just g- Seeker's next.
DM: Seeker can pick him up.
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Just cast healing word.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Okay. Um, I think...
Unknown: Do I wanna stay over here?
Kenzo: Where do I wanna be at the end of this?
Kenzo: Uh, I still wanna be, I guess, 15 feet away from him, so I can punch him some more.
Kenzo: I... Well, but I can always run back.
Kenzo: Where do I wanna be? Do I j- should I just wanna be over here with you guys?
Delwath: No, no, no.
DM: No.
Delwath: Go within 15... I'd go back.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Go back.
DM: I agree.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: So keep him contained.
Wellby: Don't stay too bunched up with everyone.
Unknown: Okay. I'll, I'll, uh-
Seeker: Throw some fire at him, Wellby
DM: ... that ends Kenzo's turn.
DM: Beginning of the next turn-
Kenzo: Actually, wait, before I go here, I just run around and he's still in the way.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Oh, oh, oh, wait, wait, wait, wait. I...
Delwath: Who's... Remind me the...
Delwath: Before you end your move, remind me the initiative order.
DM: Seeker, clay golem, Wellby, Delwath.
DM: In that order.
Delwath: No, stay a little bit away from him.
Unknown: Why?
Delwath: 'Cause that way, if I cast a spell-
Kenzo: Oh, you can do sickening radiance.
Delwath: Or, uh, I... Wait, he...
Unknown: He's not vulnerable to anything, right?
DM: Nope.
Delwath: But I have a couple of spell options.
Kenzo: Oh, whatever else is here.
Delwath: I mean, I can actually make people immune if it doesn't-
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: No, no, it doesn't matter. I can make him immune to a spell.
Unknown: All right. All right, fine.
Seeker: Um, should I cast my highest level healing word available?
Delwath: Yes, please.
DM: Don't burn your teleport spell.
Delwath: Not your teleport spell.
Seeker: Oh, not that high level.
Delwath: Six if you have it.
Seeker: Fifth. It's, it's fifth level, so that's-
Delwath: Or fifth if that's...
Seeker: 10 D4 plus five.
Delwath: Yeah.
Seeker: I'll just automate that one.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Um, 10 D4 plus five
DM: is
DM: 20, is 28.
Delwath: It's not amazing. I can healing word myself or my turn,
Delwath: but.
DM: So that's your bonus action.
Delwath: Ooh.
DM: So that means the ladder can't attack, but-
Delwath: The construct can
DM: ... the construct can.
Unknown: Wait.
Unknown: What's the-
Delwath: The ladder uses your bonus action
DM: ... the ladder uses your bonus action.
Delwath: But you still have an action.
Unknown: But you still have your action. You can cast another spell.
Unknown: Stepping to him is great.
Delwath: But I can't cast healing word right now.
DM: But-
Seeker: Wait, how do I use my bonus action then?
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: It's a healing... It's a healing word.
Seeker: We're so powerful now, it's crazy.
Delwath: You cast a cantrip. You can cast a cantrip.
Unknown: Do so many interesting things.
DM: 17. You use your bonus action to healing word.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: And then you... That's the same as you normally use your bonus action to command the spirit, the ladder.
Kenzo: Ah, ah.
DM: Can't do two bonus actions.
Kenzo: Can re-roll any saving, saving throw too.
DM: Um-
Seeker: For Keith
DM: ...
Seeker: so I can't comm-
Unknown: That's awesome
Seeker: ... so you're saying I can't control the ladder, but the construct can.
Delwath: How much HP does it have?
DM: But you can control the construct.
DM: Construct.
Unknown: It's currently 12.
Seeker: So it'll just do its same-
Seeker: But I can also-
Seeker: ... triple attack again.
Seeker: Does it have advantage again?
Unknown: Uh, no.
DM: Okay.
DM: No advantage anymore, right?
DM: It's not blinded.
DM: We're out of the first turn. There's nothing giving advantage.
Seeker: So I just make the three attacks.
Seeker: 17, 19...
Seeker: Oh, no. They're plus-
Unknown: Those are the straight rolls.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: 17, 19, and 11 are the straight rolls.
Unknown: It hits.
Delwath: Yeah.
Seeker: Yes. And so then it's...
DM: I forget.
Delwath: So, so Tim?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Just to be clear, using my sword to create a magic circle is not-
DM: It's an action, but not casting a spell.
Delwath: Okay.
Unknown: Oh, fuck.
Delwath: So I could bonus action cast a spell.
DM: Yes.
Seeker: So its attack, uh,
Seeker: is 1d8 plus 10, so that's 3d8 plus 30.
DM: You're good.
Seeker: Where... Yep, there's all the D's.
Wellby: It'd be nice to hit it with more radiant damage though.
Delwath: It's pretty weak against radiant.
DM: Yeah, if its turn comes around without Delwath hitting it with radiant, it's gonna heal a bunch-
Unknown: 14
DM: ... 'cause it hasn't been hit with radiant yet.
Wellby: We can just repeat last round again.
Wellby: Kenzo can run in, punch it, and pull you out safely.
Seeker: So it does
Seeker: 44.
Delwath: Yeah, that's a good point.
Unknown: Total.
Delwath: We don't have a good source of ranged radiant damage.
DM: Okay. Um-
Kenzo: Sickening radiance
DM: ... so it needs to roll-
Delwath: Sickening radiance
DM: ... concentration
Delwath: ... it's pretty heavy damage
DM: ... three concentrations.
Delwath: But it's also concentration.
DM: But the, both the ladder and the, um,
DM: golem who are standing in contact with the burning fire take 22 points of fire damage at the end of their turns.
Unknown: Each of them?
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Take 22. Okay.
DM: Oh, those are all good rolls.
DM: It succeeds on concentration on all three of its rolls.
DM: And that ends
DM: Seeker's turn and the golem's turn, so Wellby is up.
Unknown: Hey, Tim, really quick. Uh-
DM: Uh, except...
DM: Mm,
DM: is it one user?
DM: Um, go ahead, Wellby, but I just need to check one thing.
DM: It might, it might be casting another spell.
DM: I have to see what's concentration on.
Delwath: Um, quick question, Tim.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Uh,
Delwath: what was my question?
Delwath: Do you take damage... You take damage from the wall of fire if you're in its radius.
DM: If you end your turn in its radius, you take damage.
Delwath: Okay.
DM: Or if you pass through it.
Delwath: And does it go up to the ceiling?
DM: It goes up to the ceiling.
Kenzo: Tim, one other quick question.
Kenzo: Um, when I unarmed strike, I can grapple?
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: Is that on every unarmed strike I can grapple?
DM: In, if you wanna, instead of making an unarmed strike, you can attempt to grapple.
DM: It makes a strength saving throw.
Kenzo: But I mean instead of doing... So, like, flurry...
Kenzo: 'Cause normally I do flurry of blows as an action.
DM: Yeah, you can replace one of your unarmed strikes with an attempt to grapple.
DM: It makes a strength saving throw. If it fails-
Unknown: Oh, and there's no damage
DM: ... there's no damage.
Unknown: Got it. Okay, okay. I see.
DM: But if it fails, you've grappled it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: It goes right after me?
DM: It goes right after you. You gotta kill it.
Delwath: I mean, I could do a suicide run.
Delwath: Just don't know if that's a good idea.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: I'm gonna punt him.
Delwath: Well, that's-
Wellby: No, I think it's a good idea.
Delwath: Yeah, but it's, it's like-
DM: Seeker has a scroll of resurrection.
Wellby: And more healing, and you can Step to the Winds him out of there.
Kenzo: Yeah, I know, but there's a dragon that's gonna come and teleport here and we have to kill it.
DM: This is the thing.
Delwath: This is just part one of the battle.
Wellby: We're, we're 18 seconds into this right now.
Delwath: Yeah. If we get 10...
Delwath: I'm hoping, I'm pretty sure, I mean, with no way are we gonna kill a dragon if we can't short rest.
Delwath: We can short rest in 10 minutes.
Delwath: If I'm alive,
Delwath: I could cast Prayer of Healing and get a short rest in 10 minutes.
Unknown: We're gonna have 10 minutes?
Delwath: I think so.
Wellby: I'm just, I'm gonna-
DM: I, you're, you're making a lot of assumptions about the dragon's abilities to shape change [laughs].
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: The dragon might not-
DM: It might just be waiting outside for you.
Delwath: Yeah. Okay. All right.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: [laughs] I'm up.
DM: Uh, yeah, you're up.
DM: I, I just need a re- it might be doing something.
Delwath: Fuck.
DM: Uh, but I'll just have it do two things at the end of your turn instead of in between.
Wellby: Awesome.
Wellby: Um, I have advantage from dex, or from re-
DM: Dex, yep
Wellby: ... I have disadvantage from it being 0 HP.
DM: So it's a straight roll and it's in, in combat with your allies, so you still get sneak attack.
Wellby: I flip the switch on the clockwork amulet and roll a 21.
DM: Nice.
Wellby: Uh, I'm-
Delwath: How many times can you use that?
Wellby: Once a day.
Delwath: One day.
Wellby: I'm blinding it again, so that's a DC 18 dex.
Delwath: I have one legendary resistance left.
Wellby: 18, 23, and 29 points of damage.
DM: Uh, DC what?
Wellby: 18.
DM: It's blinding.
Delwath: Oh, it doesn't burn a legendary resistance?
DM: It's gotta save its last one in case you try and banish it or something.
Delwath: Oh, yeah, that's a good point. Shit, it's blind, but I have advantage.
Wellby: Yep.
Delwath: Fucking suicide mission.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: It, it has disadvantage.
Delwath: Uh, how much damage does the wall of fire do?
DM: 5d8.
Seeker: Can I just like whoop, like give you the fire protection ring?
DM: No, 'cause it takes an hour to, to-
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: You got the 29 damage also.
DM: Uh, 29.
Delwath: What is the chances 5d8 will take me below 28 hit points?
Delwath: It's not very good, right?
DM: 20-
Delwath: Yeah, that's pretty decent
DM: ... 22 is the average.
Delwath: It's pretty risky.
Seeker: It could definitely happen.
Delwath: Yeah. Can-
Wellby: Oh, um, concentration save.
DM: Uh, yep.
Seeker: Can you bonus action another potion or something on the way over?
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: I could Dimension Door.
Delwath: It's when you-
DM: Uh, 19. It succeeds.
Delwath: Hold on, Tim. It's, it's when you...
Delwath: If I Dimension Door, when would I take the damage?
DM: End of your turn.
Delwath: Okay.
DM: If it's still alive.
Wellby: [laughs] I think that's what you should-
Kenzo: Dimension Door in. Fucking go cra- go, go balls to the, go nuts.
Seeker: Just, we need your smiting. Okay, so-
Delwath: [laughs] Okay.
Unknown: I think it's just gonna die.
Wellby: Del with loses his shit [laughs].
DM: It's using, it's using two of its actions.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: It's got disadvantage anyway.
DM: The whip strikes out, um, kind of at random towards Wellby.
DM: Um, that's a
DM: 21 to hit.
Wellby: That's a hit, yep.
DM: Um, so you take,
DM: uh-
Delwath: 20-
DM: ... 23 points of damage.
Delwath: Hold on. That's where it's touching the fire.
Unknown: Can you dodge?
DM: It's a 10-foot radius.
Delwath: Ah, from the wall.
DM: You can uncanny dodge and make a strength saving throw.
Delwath: Oh, you're gonna get thrown in the wall, huh?
Delwath: All right. I'm, I'm suicide running.
Wellby: I roll an 18.
Wellby: Is that good enough?
DM: It's a 24.
Wellby: I'll use my bardic inspiration.
Unknown: Hey.
Wellby: That's three, that's 12.
Delwath: Wait, do you get to roll bardic inspiration?
DM: No, no, you don't get to re-roll. You have to use your hero- inspiration to re-roll it.
Delwath: Wait, wait, wait.
DM: You only re-roll-
Delwath: Skill checks
DM: ... skill checks. You get 12...
DM: If you use your h- you should just use your hero inspiration.
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: I used my in-
DM: You get-
Unknown: You already did it
DM: ... you use on the bardic inspiration.
Wellby: Oh, on the bardic inspiration.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: 'Cause I attacked it.
DM: So you use, you succeed-
Wellby: On the bardic inspiration
DM: ... and you get 12 temporary hit points.
Delwath: Oh.
DM: So the whip sli- slashes out at Wellby and it te- tries to throw him into the wall.
Delwath: By the way,
Delwath: didn't I succeed?
DM: You suc- you didn't use inspiration.
DM: You used your-
Delwath: No, I used both.
DM: Oh, so then you also get temporary hit points.
Delwath: How many temporary hit points was it?
DM: Whatever you rolled on your bardic inspiration.
Delwath: I think I rolled like a...
Delwath: Oh, wait, it was... I can't remember.
DM: You failed.
Unknown: You failed.
DM: But you still get the... It was like four.
DM: It was like four, yeah.
DM: So just add four hit points.
Delwath: Okay.
DM: And take-
Wellby: And those still have been lost on your way to unconsciousness.
Seeker: Actually, that's true.
DM: It does. Oh, no. Yeah, no-
Unknown: You got hit way-
DM: ... 'cause they would've been lost anyway
Seeker: ... way below zero.
Delwath: I, I wasn't close enough that four would've made a difference.
DM: Made a difference.
Unknown: Yeah, no. You, you took like 27 damage all together.
DM: Um, so you, you resist.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: You do s- I already told you the damage, right?
DM: You s- you ha- you uncanny dodged it, so it was down to 11.
Delwath: Yep.
DM: I think it was 22 to start.
DM: And you are not moved.
Delwath: Oh, and by the way, the aid is gone 'cause I was unconscious.
Unknown: Oh, so the-
DM: But that does-
Seeker: ... the bonus hit points
DM: ... if you're only, if you're above your max-
Delwath: It doesn't matter.
Delwath: I mean, no, no, no, you go down, you lose.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: You're back to full health instead of...
DM: The whip is also gonna strike out somewhat randomly.
DM: Um,
DM: again towards Wellby.
DM: Ooh, that's a pretty bad roll.
DM: 19 to hit.
Wellby: AC is 19.
DM: So that hits.
DM: Um, so you take
DM: 25 points of damage and another strength saving throw.
Wellby: Uh, there's no way for me to make a strength saving throw.
DM: Okay. You are slammed into the wall.
DM: Um, wait, you're flying-
Wellby: I'm flying
DM: ... so it actually pulls you straight to the wall of fire and you're slammed into the wall above its head.
Delwath: Oh, okay.
DM: And because it can only pull it towards you, so it can't throw you into lava.
DM: But you also take-
Wellby: What's that, 4d8
DM: ... um, 10, 17,
DM: 20,
DM: 24 points of damage.
Delwath: But it's blinded, right? So I'm gonna have advantage.
DM: It's blinded.
Delwath: Okay.
DM: You're gonna have advantage. That ends its double legendary action.
DM: Delwath's turn.
Delwath: All right. I'm bonus action Dimension Dooring using...
Delwath: Hold on. I gotta tick this off.
Kenzo: It is exciting.
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: So I'm using a sorcery
Delwath: point, which I actually haven't used any sorcery points left, but I'm using two sorcery points to-
DM: No, you used subtle spell to cast Detect Thoughts.
Seeker: Oh, yeah. So I have to like cast Healing Word on Delwath, like pick them up off the ground and-
Unknown: And he just charges
DM: ... no, you used, used extended spell to cast Dimension Door to
DM: So this is probably it for Sorcerer's 1 last
Seeker: Delwath, I think you have a little bit of...
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: I just ignore, so I push Seeker away from dying.
Delwath: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Uh-
Unknown: Well, wait.
Delwath: You should still-
Delwath: So a bonus action cast Dimension Door to appear
Delwath: right there
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: We should do the AI like you, uh, you, you push Seeker away and then you draw the sword-
Delwath: And-
Unknown: ... and then you run at him
Delwath: ... and then I am attacking.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: So here's the question. Well, do I smite the fir- Well, let's see what happens.
Delwath: 14, 24, that hits.
DM: That hits.
Delwath: So do I smite now or do I hope for a crit that I might miss?
Wellby: Smite now.
Unknown: Smite now.
DM: You smite now 'cause you gotta kill it.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: And it's totally dead if you don't kill it.
Delwath: That is true.
Seeker: Yeah.
Delwath: So smite does... Oh, it falls prone when I smite it.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Six. So it's six.
DM: Wait, even if it's large?
Delwath: Large or smaller.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Uh, sorry, huge or smaller.
Delwath: Okay.
Delwath: So here's the first attack.
Delwath: It's a smite.
Seeker: We should go find more fiends.
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: Just, just to find them. [laughs]
Delwath: 12, 10-
Seeker: Just to smite them. [laughs]
Delwath: ...
Delwath: 20, uh, plus 16, 36-
Unknown: 40
Delwath: ... 40, 48.
Kenzo: 52.
Delwath: Uh, plus five. Oh.
DM: That's gonna be a really-
Unknown: 52
DM: ... hard concentration check to make.
Unknown: 52 plus 5?
Unknown: 52.
Wellby: 57 altogether, right?
Delwath: Uh, 57 altogether.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It's gonna be a tough-
Delwath: So yeah, that is a tough concentration check to make.
DM: What is the-
Delwath: It's half damage, so 25
DM: ... so it's 20-
Delwath: 20, 26
DM: ... it rolled a 22, so the wall of fire disappears.
Unknown: So thanks Kenza.
DM: It's not gonna use its last legendary resistance.
Delwath: Okay.
DM: It's like almost dead. It's holding up against the wall.
Delwath: Okay. I'm get three attacks.
Delwath: Next attack.
Delwath: That hits.
Unknown: That hits.
Delwath: There's nothing I can do except clink you at all.
Unknown: Oh, that's good though.
Delwath: 15, 20, uh, plus 5 is 20, 23.
DM: It slumps against the wall.
Kenzo: Finish him off, Delwath. That is double 17s.
Unknown: He only has two hit points left.
Unknown: He's dead.
Unknown: He's down. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] Delwath.
DM: Delwath's sword like flashes with this light as it just slices through this fiend
DM: and it vanishes when it dies.
Delwath: Chalthun just like slumps down to the ground like blood gushing for like 20-
Unknown: It turns into 1000 little swords
Unknown: ... it's all fire and product. It like, it's like covered in burns
DM: ... and burns.
Delwath: And...
Seeker: The, the clay construct is like all excited and bashing its head against the wall and-
Kenzo: Kenza, Kenza looks over at Delwath like, "All right.
Kenzo: That was badass." [laughs]
Delwath: Thank you, Kenza.
Kenzo: That was really fucking cool. [laughs] I enjoyed watching that.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: That was amazing.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Wow, that's...
Kenzo: Yeah, you get to fight all the fiends from here on out.
Kenzo: Uh, what can we do to make you less dead?
Unknown: Let's see.
Delwath: A long rest... I mean, a short rest is...
Delwath: I'm gonna cast Prayer of Healing right away.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: There anything we can put over the mirror?
Delwath: Yeah, let's... I mean-
Unknown: I mean, you can just have the-
Kenzo: Just destroy the mirror
Unknown: ... the, the ladder can smash it.
Unknown: I mean-
Delwath: Yeah
Delwath: ... Prayer of Healing doesn't require...
Unknown: I mean, you can do stuff.
Delwath: I-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... I command the ladder to smash the mirror.
DM: The ladder's like, "Yeah, you never let me hurt, get mirrors."
Delwath: [laughs]
DM: "I've never been able to hurt a mirror before."
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Or do we just keep the mirror in the hopes of getting the other mirror and then we take both mirrors?
DM: Wouldn't that be nice?
Delwath: No, no.
Unknown: Smash it.
DM: It's 15 feet. It doesn't fit in the portable hole.
Seeker: It's huge, yeah.
Delwath: It's big. Just, just destroy it.
Unknown: All right. Destroy it.
Delwath: Just des-
Unknown: The ladder's so excited.
DM: Oh, I was just so-
DM: It's like you constantly put me in this-
DM: Just to crash that mirror.
Wellby: It doesn't feel right though.
DM: What are you gonna do with it?
Seeker: Just smash the mirror, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Smash.
DM: Just so you know, the other end is a pool of acid in a lair.
DM: It's not-
Unknown: Ah, okay. All right.
DM: So you're not really...
DM: It's gonna-
Wellby: Ladder's gonna have seven years bad luck.
DM: No, the ladder's like so happy, just like, boom, boom, cracks appear, it like splits, and then there's just this like shatter of glass that falls down.
Unknown: Anyway, I have no spell slots left.
DM: It's just a bare wall behind that.
Delwath: Ah, so I, I have to cast Prayer of Healing with a sorcerer slot.
Delwath: Yeah, that's too bad.
Seeker: I shake the clay construct's hand, and then it turns back into a lump of clay.
DM: Well, it lasts for an hour.
Seeker: Oh.
DM: There's no reason to let it go.
Seeker: It can stick around. Okay.
Delwath: Yeah, they can both stick around.
DM: There's all sorts of things it might be able to do.
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: Can I look for secret doors while people are healing?
Kenzo: Yeah, what the hell's going on in this room? Yeah, serious.
Delwath: So-
Kenzo: I, I helped Seeker, so he gets advantage on the whole-
Delwath: Okay
Unknown: ... but that's-
Delwath: So everybody-
DM: While you're casting the spell-
Delwath: Yeah
DM: ... the ladder's smashing the mirror.
DM: You two are searching.
Kenzo: We're, we're searching. Yeah.
DM: What are you guys doing? Or sorry, what is Seeker doing?
Seeker: Um, I will-
Unknown: Nothing like really
Seeker: ... I guess Tremor Sense again because-
Seeker: So 20-
Unknown: ... there's...
Seeker: If there's a prison around here, we don't know where it is, so I wanted to find out-
Delwath: So everybody heals 2d-
Unknown: ... if anything's moving around
Delwath: ... or did anything take the... Oh, you took it.
DM: Everybody heal? Yeah?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I took 2d.
Delwath: Everybody who's-
Kenzo: Maximum hit points. Oh, do we get, do we get the extra 20 back for the-
Unknown: No.
Delwath: No, I'm not gonna cast Aid again.
Delwath: I need to, I need to spend a spell slot, which I don't have.
Unknown: All right.
Seeker: So yeah, just Tremor Sense again.
DM: Okay. Um-
Unknown: Although...
Seeker: Oh, and s- oh, and also Stone Sense to see about other...
Seeker: What's the shape of the other tunnels around here?
DM: Okay.
DM: Go ahead and make your perception check with advantage.
Wellby: 23 for perception.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Tim, I'm actually gonna recover two spell slots using my once a day, cast Aid and Agas- Armor of Agathys, and then do the 10-minute short rest.
Delwath: So we have 50 minutes to fight the dragon.
Delwath: Clock is counting.
Kenzo: Wait, do we get our, our max hit points back?
Delwath: Yeah, max hit points back, and I have 25 bonus hit points.
Delwath: 25 temp hit points for the next 50 minutes.
Seeker: Oh, so we get the 20 again.
Delwath: You get the 20 back.
DM: Okay. Um, so-
Delwath: Oh, actually I'm not gonna do Armor of Agathys.
Delwath: I'm gonna get, I'm gonna get Metamagic back instead.
DM: Okay.
DM: I mean, Armor of Agathys is a bonus action.
DM: It's pretty easy to cast it-
Delwath: I know
DM: ... in combat.
Delwath: Yes. It's, it's just the f-
DM: And getting the Metamagic back is really super.
DM: It's definitely better. Yeah.
DM: Um, okay, so this is like, uh, I will say with your
DM: Tremor Sense, it's maybe slightly outside the bounds of technically what you can sense, but there's something like vibrating inside the pool of lava.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Stone Sense doesn't... There's no other passages.
Seeker: No other chambers. Yeah.
DM: There's no other chambers here
Seeker: So that's the portal
Seeker: And a dolphin skull
Unknown: Maybe
Wellby: Can we get the lava out of it?
Wellby: Like can we, uh-
DM: Um, as you search around, so just to finish up, the, so, uh, one thing you notice, it looks like there's scorch marks, like this room has been burned several times.
DM: But for some reason, the 10 or so books that survive on the shelf seem to be immune to fire.
Unknown: Awesome.
Wellby: Grab the books.
Unknown: Grab the books, yeah.
DM: Um, they all have the same symbol on the cover, the, like, open book with a flame going up and the stars.
Wellby: Cool.
Seeker: Those are Drankhoren.
DM: Um,
DM: the mirror, of course, is gone.
DM: The
DM: fire demon is gone.
Unknown: Ugh.
Seeker: Oh, it had a whip.
DM: It had a giant... Well, the, everything in-
Unknown: It disintegrates forever
DM: ... everything, when you kill a fiend, it just goes back to the hell.
Delwath: So Tim, it's okay to take the short rest.
Delwath: We're not gonna be interrupted.
DM: You're not gonna be interrupted, yeah.
DM: Um, and there's also, um,
DM: i- so I forgot to mention this before, but in the center of the table where this hole is, there's like a, a large sort of heatless flame that burns, like a b- bonfire that's erupting
DM: out. It comes almost to the level of the table.
DM: But that does not give off any heat,
DM: but it's lighting the room with, like, flickering firelight.
DM: Um,
DM: so that's it. That's all you really find.
Unknown: All right.
Wellby: Did you say we short rested?
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: Okay. So how do we open up the portal inside the lava pit?
Kenzo: Or how do we get in there?
Seeker: I will, um, investigate the lava pit with my goggles.
Seeker: Not, I don't, well, I can identify it.
Kenzo: Oh, yeah, you need to spell magic on the, on the lava pit.
Seeker: Oh, maybe. Well, first I'll just-
DM: You should.
Unknown: I'll just-
DM: I mean, somebody could, Delwath could d- detect magic.
Delwath: Yeah, I can detect, yeah, I can detect magic.
DM: Okay. The stone that surrounds the lava is magical.
DM: The fire in the middle of the table is magical, and the books are magical.
Wellby: But the lava's just regular lava.
DM: The lava's just regular lava.
Kenzo: Coming from where?
Delwath: The stone that's magical.
Wellby: Dispel lava.
Unknown: Dispel-
Wellby: Teleport lava
Kenzo: ... dispel stone? The stone that's... Dispel the stone.
DM: Try to make,
DM: make an arcana check.
Seeker: That's, um, 24.
DM: Okay. Um, so what you notice when you're looking around, um, is that there are...
DM: So it's, I mean, it's hot. There's, like, waves of heat coming off the lava, and there's, like, right around the base of the stone, there's, like, tiny little script, like little runes that are
DM: magical script that's etched around the bottom of the stone.
DM: Um, and it seems to be something about transmutation magic
DM: and fire. Like, the runes are all, like, fire, fire, fire.
DM: Like, it's somehow the stone is heating up.
DM: It's like
DM: the basin is turning stone you put into it into lava.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: Don't forget to get a short rest and get your Bardic Inspiration back.
Seeker: Oh, oh, I didn't realize that.
Seeker: You said so, short rest.
DM: Um, anybody looking at the books?
Seeker: Shortly, I will be.
Wellby: Someone other than me-
Unknown: Seeker, look at the books
Wellby: ... I'll look, but I don't think I'm gonna get anything from them.
Kenzo: I mean, I'll look.
DM: They're written in Drankhoren.
Kenzo: I read Drankhoren.
Delwath: I read Drankhoren.
DM: They're-
Unknown: Oh, there you go
DM: ... they're the,
DM: uh,
DM: history and chronicles of the Concordia Pyrae,
DM: a secret Drankhoren society dedicated to understanding the magic of the Plane of Fire.
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: Oh, this is how we find your brother.
Delwath: Totally.
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: How we find, yep.
DM: Um-
Seeker: We studied in the psychic last time
DM: ... most, like-
Delwath: Eric, I have tons of charge. Do you want to just switch seats with me?
Seeker: Oh, um, I can just reach.
DM: Half of them-
Delwath: There's a, that should reach
DM: ... like-
Unknown: Sorry
DM: ... so there's 10 books.
DM: Most of them seem to be
DM: like research into the Plane of Fire, which is gonna take you some time to digest.
DM: Three of them are like a chronicle of events, right?
DM: They're like the records of this particular villa,
DM: and they kind of go, you sort of skim through them, and you get the vague, you know, you pick up some of the history you already know, right?
DM: Like
DM: Drankhoren, this was a big pilgrimage site in Dran Chor.
DM: Um, you know,
DM: it also became a place where p- where a lot of people, a lot of wizards went to sort of research and try to figure out the magic of Hkar and, you know, what was it that made
DM: the people of Hka- the wizards on Hkar so strong.
DM: And the last book is sort of chronicling the downfall of the island.
DM: Talks about how Apollyon forbid pilgrimage,
DM: and there was a lot of conflict with...
DM: It lists like a whole bunch of names of societies that seem to have been like pilgrimage aid groups and things like that.
DM: Um, and then it talks about,
DM: um, the
DM: war, but the start of the war between Apollyon and Cha'mutte
DM: over
DM: possession of the prisoner.
Seeker: Possession of the prisoner.
Delwath: Ah. It's totally Cloudspinner.
DM: And it talks about how everybody was...
DM: You know, the last entry is like, um, "We all must flee," you know.
DM: "The diviners say that the island will not survive for long.
DM: Um,
DM: Apollyon has the cloak,
DM: but Cha'mutte has the prisoner."
DM: And then that's it, dot, dot, dot, we leave.
DM: The implication being Cha'mutte, like, killed them all and took over the base.
Unknown: And left the books behind.
Seeker: And then the last line is, "Aah."
DM: Yeah. [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs] I'm being stabbed.
DM: I mean, like, y- your feeling is-
Unknown: There's a lot of spiders
DM: ... like they were surpri- I mean, yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: They were surprised here. They were killed before they could leave.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Anything that wasn't immune to fire damage was destroyed.
Kenzo: Dispel Magic on the stone?
Seeker: Right. I think that makes sense.
Delwath: Right.
Seeker: Turn off the lava.
Delwath: Wait, do we know where the portal is?
Delwath: Do we think it's inside the fire thing?
Seeker: I used the wand already.
Kenzo: You said that there was a tre- there was a tremor inside the...
DM: Seeker felt something vibrating-
Delwath: In the-
DM: ... under, in the lava pool.
Delwath: Yeah
DM: Like underneath the lava.
Seeker: So, okay.
DM: It was trembling
Seeker: So I'll try to dis- I'll u- I'll cast Dispel Magic.
Seeker: What can, what level can we do that at?
Delwath: Highest one probably.
Delwath: I mean, you're probably, you're probably-
Seeker: The highest one that doesn't burn my Teleports slots.
Delwath: Yes. [laughs]
Delwath: Yeah. You're, you burned a lot of slots.
Delwath: We gotta fight the dragon before your constructs go away 'cause you're-
Delwath: Or not. Or not
Unknown: ...
DM: Or we can run away
Kenzo: ... we've achieved everything that we wanted.
Seeker: We could run away.
DM: So.
Delwath: Wow, I mean, that's true. Why don't we just-
Wellby: Or Cloudspinner kills the dragon for us.
Unknown: There you go.
Kenzo: We just need to get the Cloudspinner out.
Seeker: Um, so I'm gonna use-
Delwath: I like your plan. [laughs]
Kenzo: Yeah, that's what we're doing. So, so spend the s- you know, not the teleport, but...
Seeker: I'll try Dispel Magic at fourth level.
DM: Okay.
DM: It works.
DM: [sighs] Huh.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: I mean, the lava's still lava.
DM: I, I looked it up. It takes months for lava to cool.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: Uh.
Seeker: Wait, am I totally immune to fire damage with the ring?
DM: No, just resistant.
Delwath: Is mage hand gonna put it out?
Unknown: So I can't just like [whooshes] like...
Seeker: So we could shovel-
DM: Eh
Seeker: ... the lava out of there or something.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Shovel it with, shovel it with-
Seeker: Just wait, wait. The clay, clay construct can just shovel the lava.
Seeker: Oh, no, it'll burn. It'll get burned, right?
DM: It's not immune to fire damage.
Wellby: So we have clay constructs.
Wellby: Can you Performance of Creation a thing that is immune to fire damage that the clay golem can use to...
Kenzo: Oh, nice. Make a shovel. A, a, a lava shovel.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Unless we, somebody just has a shovel.
Kenzo: That, w- can survive lava?
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: Okay.
DM: I mean...
Seeker: No, it's, I think Performance Creation of a shovel does make sense.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah. That's good.
Delwath: That's great.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Make a-
Delwath: Lava shovel
Wellby: ... diamond shovel or something.
Unknown: I mean-
DM: There's no restrictions on the value, uh, that it can be.
Unknown: It'll be a-
DM: So you could make a diamond shovel
Unknown: ... adam-
DM: Does it have adamantium?
Seeker: Adam- adamantium shovel
Wellby: ... adamantium scoop.
Kenzo: That way, then that, that's resistant to fi- that thing's resistant to lava
DM: It is gonna take some time to shovel lava.
DM: I mean, this is a, this is a 15-foot fool.
DM: It's like 10 feet deep.
DM: That's a pretty big volume of lava.
Kenzo: Can you just move the lava?
Seeker: I can do two shovels, right, with Performance of Creation?
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: And so I'll make one for the-
Delwath: The ladder?
Seeker: ... for the clay construct and one for the ladder.
Kenzo: This is a great scene.
Unknown: Shoveling lava.
Kenzo: Shoveling lava out of the t- [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um.
Wellby: Do we have any other way to get it out faster?
Seeker: Telekinesis.
Delwath: Telekinesis.
DM: I mean, telekinesis would work much better if it were solidified.
Unknown: Right.
DM: You don't... I mean, maybe you have a way to solidify it.
Unknown: Ah.
Wellby: Use the alchemy jug to pour some water on it.
Delwath: Yeah.
Seeker: Drill a hole in the bottom so it leaks out the side.
Delwath: Wait, what about just pouring water on it?
DM: How much water can we make?
Wellby: It's only like 10 gallons or something.
Seeker: Of the alchem- chemicals.
Delwath: I almost just...
Seeker: So how long is it gonna take with the two?
DM: Uh, um, let me just check.
DM: There are, like, actually technically rules for shovels now.
Wellby: Do we, are we gonna have to, like, heat or cool objects?
Unknown: Sorry.
Wellby: No.
Wellby: Create water.
Seeker: Oh, watery sphere.
Unknown: That's-
DM: But you unattune from that.
Unknown: Yeah, I can't do it.
DM: [laughs] That might be good though.
DM: That would... That creates a lot of water.
Unknown: Wait, I think-
DM: Nobody has a create water spell?
Seeker: Didn't we give me, um, mold-
Delwath: I was gonna take create water, but I couldn't because divine soul is now third level
Seeker: ... Oh. I, I thought we gave me mold water in addition to mold earth.
DM: Oh, shape water.
Unknown: Shape water.
DM: But that doesn't... That, you have to have water already.
DM: It doesn't summon water.
Seeker: Ah. I'm doing so, so doing that.
Delwath: What about-
Unknown: I see it on my thing.
DM: I mean, I, I think realistically it's gonna take a couple of hours to clear out the lava.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: [sighs]
DM: I mean, working with a shovel in dirt, you could do, like, an hour to do a five-foot cube,
DM: and this is... I mean, let's say golems can work more efficiently-
Unknown: Wait
DM: ... than a normal human.
Seeker: Is, is lava susceptible to mold earth?
DM: No, it's not earth.
Seeker: But I mean, it, it's just hot.
Wellby: True.
Unknown: Like, clearly.
DM: I mean, it's lava.
Unknown: It's lava.
DM: It's not earth. [laughs] Those are different things.
Delwath: Well, let's think about this 'cause if we, if we are gonna just, like, let them shovel for a long time,
Delwath: the problem is then we're...
Delwath: They're gonna, they're not gonna la... I mean, they only last an hour, right?
Seeker: Yeah. Oh, that's true.
DM: Yeah. They won't get all the lava out in an hour.
Unknown: How the fuck do we get all this lava out?
Delwath: Which means if our goal is to get all the lava out...
Kenzo: Well, we just need to get out enough lava to, like, see the portal or whatever the fuck is tremoring underneath.
Delwath: Right. But if we don't have a spell [clears throat], it's hard to see what we would do that's gonna be ni-
Unknown: I have a scroll of Passwall.
Unknown: That's not really what we need.
Wellby: Can you look through the lava?
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: See what's underneath?
Delwath: Oh, I could ghostly gaze.
Wellby: There you go.
Kenzo: Yeah. Let's have a look.
Kenzo: Look in the lava.
Wellby: Do you recover that when Charus-
DM: Oh, sorry. I forgot. There's a crucial detail I forgot to mention.
DM: Sorry. When the devil dies, the only thing left behind is a large black iron key that looks extremely similar
DM: to the black iron rod you found, like, the same kind of metal as that black iron rod you found, like, many, many, many years ago.
DM: In-
Delwath: In Raven's Hold?
DM: No, in the very first adventure that had Shamut's holy symbol on it.
Delwath: What?
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: Wait, the very first adventure of-
Wellby: Oh, the dark wind.
Unknown: The, yeah, yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: The dark wind.
DM: The dark, the necromancy Shamut.
DM: Just to point out, it's a, it's a key made by Shamut.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: Yep.
DM: Um,
DM: and when you ghostly gaze through the lava, there is a...
DM: There's, like, a locked circular-
Delwath: Right
DM: ... uh, trapdoor that seems to be, like, vibrating with some kind of intense magical energy.
Wellby: Can you look through that?
DM: Nothing on the other side, just darkness.
Delwath: It's a dimension. That's the portal.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. That's the portal.
Wellby: All right. So we really do have to empty out the lava.
Delwath: So we either...
Delwath: We have three choices. We either return to the surface and try and kill the dragon now-
Delwath: Or we [sighs] use...
Wellby: I have a quick thought.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: How much of the pool is below the level of the floor versus above the level of the floor?
DM: It's about half.
Wellby: 'Cause we could just-
DM: Actually, like, two-thirds is below the floor.
Wellby: All right.
DM: It's like 10 feet deep.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: It's like the rim of the, of the,
DM: of the stone that's magic and turns the-
Wellby: I mean, it's like we could-
DM: ... lava comes up
Wellby: ... put a floor level hole in the stone at least about a third of the way.
Delwath: How much damage does the lava do?
DM: 5D6 a turn, or sorry, 8D6 a turn.
DM: Could just swim through it.
Wellby: Could be 46 with the ring.
Delwath: It's half with the ring.
Unknown: I don't... But who-
DM: Seeker does 10 maybe.
Wellby: I, this seems like a bad idea.
Kenzo: [laughs] But the, can the construct?
Delwath: I mean, Seeker would be the best place to do it, 'cause he's resistant to fire damage.
Unknown: So you're saying-
Unknown: Oh, you took a short rest. You could switch your tune in-
Delwath: Oh, that's true
DM: ... to fire resistance if you wanted to during that short rest.
Unknown: I'm saying-
Kenzo: Wait, wait, wait, but how, how far to swim down?
DM: It's only 10 feet.
Delwath: Like, it's probably like...
DM: It's probably two... It's probably gonna be two...
DM: It would probably take you... One person, it would take two turns to go down,
DM: like-
Kenzo: Put the key in
DM: ... k- put the key in, open the portal.
DM: Anybody else could jump through in one turn.
Kenzo: What? Any, what do you mean anybody?
DM: Well, anybody else who wants to go through the portal, they could go through in one turn.
Kenzo: Oh, to go thr- Oh, fuck, 'cause we don't know unless on the other side of the portal, max.
Wellby: What would be a way, like, to shape stone?
DM: I mean, you have-
Seeker: Moltar is here
DM: ... you have wall of stone too.
Delwath: Right. But that doesn't let you change existing stone.
Wellby: You could displace it.
Wellby: Can you cast the wall of...
Wellby: Like, could you put a wall of stone-
Unknown: Oh, nice
Wellby: ... in a pool of water and then displace the lava?
Delwath: And then displ- Seeker's almost out of slots.
Wellby: So you could wall of stone.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: In the lava, it would displace the lava.
Kenzo: Displace the lava, now it's stone that we can-
Wellby: And then the stone-
Unknown: ... dispel
Wellby: ... wall of stone disappears at the end of the spell.
Unknown: Love that. Love that.
DM: Does it, would that work?
DM: I mean, a wall of stone is pretty big.
DM: If you drop it, I mean, you're gonna have to be careful 'cause lava's gonna splash all over the room.
Wellby: But there's a certain amount of distance.
DM: There's some distance.
Unknown: There's some distance.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Like, we could just mo- mostly go to the other room.
DM: What's the range of... Well, then you'd have to open the secret door with the Eye of Cha'mutte, which seems like-
Unknown: Yeah, that's, we have
DM: ... not a thing.
Seeker: Oh, right, I forgot.
DM: Uh, how far, what's the range of wall of stone?
Seeker: I think it's long.
Kenzo: Oh, this is a great idea.
Wellby: Oh, you could also use wall of stone to kind of create a coffer dam just down to the size of the, um, trap door.
DM: It's what?
Wellby: So then you'd only have to empty that much lava out.
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah. You could all stand on the back wall.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You could just drop a giant wall of stone in it, so w- most of the lava is gonna splash out.
DM: I mean, it's-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... it, but it obeys physics, right?
DM: Like-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... drop, yeah.
Kenzo: Do it. That's great.
DM: Do it.
Seeker: That's great. All right, so I cast wall of stone for another 10-
DM: This is gonna, like, it's, you-
Unknown: ... hit points
DM: ... you're all standing on the back wall.
DM: This, like, giant wa- this giant stone thing just, like, falls in, and lava just splashes over this,
DM: uh, this r- rim and, like, sprays, like, 15 feet in every direction, landing on the floor, like, landing, you know, everywhere.
Kenzo: Um, as soon as it goes, um, fucking just fly over and/or...
Seeker: So, so then I can dismiss it again.
DM: And then you can dismiss it,
DM: and there's-
Seeker: Oh, that causes the construct to go away 'cause they're both-
DM: Yeah, that causes the construct to go away.
Seeker: That's fine. That's fine.
DM: And then you see there's, like, this, I mean, there's, like, a thin layer of...
DM: There's a little bit of lava left.
Unknown: Whatever.
DM: You take 2D6 fire damage.
Kenzo: That's fine. Let's go unlock it. Uh, do you wanna investigate the portal thing, or is it, like-
Wellby: Yeah, check, like, check door for traps, for keys, for magic.
DM: Um, make a, make an investigation roll.
Wellby: That's, uh...
Delwath: I'm gonna cast Guidance.
Wellby: 21.
DM: Guidance, so add a D4.
Unknown: Nice one. D4.
Wellby: 21.
DM: Um, it is locked,
DM: obviously, with a key.
DM: It's, I mean, it's pretty obvious the lava was the protection.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: And the demon.
DM: There's no traps.
Unknown: Open it.
Wellby: This feels like a thing that Delwath should probably do.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: I mean, I can open it. [coughs]
Unknown: Takes a lot of damage.
DM: Okay. You open it.
DM: There's just a thin film of darkness below.
Delwath: Can I see through it?
DM: Nope. It's a portal.
Unknown: Ah.
Unknown: It's a portal.
Wellby: I think you should...
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: I'll shut it down in fey.
Wellby: Um-
DM: Okay, so you take six points of fire damage.
DM: And you take
DM: eight points of fire damage.
Wellby: So we're here to rescue you,
Wellby: and you can come out, or we can come down, but let's not, like, kill each other in the process.
Unknown: We can't.
Wellby: Sound good?
DM: Yeah, but you don't know if sound even carries through the portal.
Delwath: I might go through.
DM: Um, you have,
DM: um,
DM: an immediate
DM: terrifying sense of being back
DM: in the shadow dimension you were trapped in.
Unknown: Ooh.
Wellby: Uh, this is a Cha'mutte thing.
Unknown: Uh, but-
DM: You look around, and you can see it's a small room.
DM: Um, it's a room maybe-
Unknown: Do you still have Telepathy?
DM: ... 15 feet by 15 feet.
Wellby: No, it doesn't cross dimension.
DM: Um, n- no, I think it...
DM: Does it?
Delwath: I don't know. Does it?
DM: Check the spell.
Wellby: Oh, uh, uh, I assume-
DM: You don't cross dimensions.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: But the telepathic bond, I think, is anywhere.
DM: It doesn't say it doesn't cross planes.
Seeker: Uh, it says it cannot cross planes.
DM: Okay, so you can't telepath with Delwath.
DM: Um,
DM: it's a small room, maybe
DM: 20 feet by 20 feet square.
DM: The walls are made of shadow that are constantly shifting and ...
DM: like twisting and writhing.
DM: And there's four,
DM: like, ropes of shadow that hang from the corners, holding in the center of the chamber a pale gray smoky crystal.
DM: Through it you can dimly see a naked woman, her long hair a brilliant tangle of reds and orange-
DM: Yeah, that's what I thought it was
DM: ... that can cr- contrasts with the almost silvery gray tint of her skin.
DM: She seems still, unmoving, as if she's in some kind of suspended state, but every now and then you can see her chest slowly rising and falling.
Unknown: Does my sword cut through the shadow bonds?
Seeker: She's, she's inside a crystal.
Unknown: Uh, you can try and attack it.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Inside a crystal.
Unknown: In a crystal in a dimension.
DM: You can make an attack roll.
Kenzo: Uh, should we all go in there or-
Delwath: Yeah, probably. Deluth's just on, you know,
Delwath: uh, 25.
DM: Um, that hits.
Delwath: Might attack me back. You might want to come down here.
DM: I might have started something.
Kenzo: Or should we be rolling for initiative or-
Wellby: I think we should not all go into the other-
DM: No, not rolling for initiative
Wellby: ... dimensional prison, but
Unknown: I'll put my head in.
DM: Um, roll damage.
Delwath: Against fiends or regular?
DM: Regular.
Unknown: Who, who are you fighting?
DM: A shadow.
Delwath: Oh, shit. The shadow rope. Uh, eight.
DM: Eight total?
DM: Yeah.
DM: Um, I mean, you, you
DM: hack at it and you cut into it.
Unknown: Uh, fuck it, man.
Delwath: It's gonna take some work to cut through these shadows.
Unknown: I'll go in. I'll go in.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: I, I gotta go in.
Kenzo: What's going on your Deluth?
Kenzo: Hacking at things?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: All right.
Delwath: I mean, I'll try again. Okay.
Unknown: Yeah, I'll, I'll do it too.
DM: Keep trying.
Seeker: Is Wellby inside?
Wellby: No. Wellby doesn't like the idea of deliberately going into a prison.
DM: 18 and-
Unknown: Uh, 17
Seeker: ... so we're kind of like looking at each other like, "To do it."
DM: Uh, 17 hits.
Seeker: I think they got this.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, this is bludgeoning
DM: damage.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Does nothing to the shadows.
Kenzo: Bludgeoning damage does n-
DM: Your fist just goes straight through.
Kenzo: The, my staff?
DM: Your staff does bludgeoning damage, it just goes straight through the shadows.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: Uh, I did another seven, 15 or 13.
Wellby: I'll hand you a short sword.
Delwath: Does a 17 hit?
DM: 17 hits.
Unknown: Another six, 11.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Does a 15 hit? If I hit it with a short sword, does it do stuff?
DM: You can hit it with a short sword.
Unknown: Okay, that hits, 18 plus whatever.
DM: Uh, 18 hits. Uh, you hacked through one.
DM: Make a wisdom saving throw.
Unknown: 20.
Delwath: Uh, plus five, 25.
DM: Um,
DM: you take one level of exhaustion.
Unknown: Oof.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: All right.
Kenzo: Uh, should I keep hacking at it with short, short, short sword?
Wellby: Conditions.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, find it.
Kenzo: You got a 20... You rolled a 25 on your wisdom save and you, it's, it did a-
DM: Well, that's what happens if you fail the save
Unknown: ... if you succeed a save, I mean.
Unknown: It's... Yeah, that's what happens if you succeed the save.
DM: If you fail the save, it's worse.
Unknown: Fuck.
Kenzo: Fuck. What's the level of exhaustion do?
Delwath: Minus two to everything.
Kenzo: How do you get the exha- the level of exhaustion back?
Delwath: Oh, that's bad actually. Lots of exhaustion is quite tough if we're gonna fight a dragon.
Kenzo: Yeah, but how do you-
Unknown: You got a long rest
DM: ... you long rest.
DM: You got a long rest.
Kenzo: Um, should I-
DM: Or, um-
Kenzo: Should I keep hacking at it?
Delwath: ... greater restoration I think fixes it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But Rizwood's not here.
Kenzo: Should I keep, should I also hack at it too?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: All right. I'm, I'm doing...
DM: Yeah. So one is cut through.
Kenzo: I keep rolling twos. These are all not helpful.
Unknown: 12.
DM: I just have a fan- general sense of how many rolls you've made.
Unknown: Uh, 19.
DM: Okay, that hits.
Kenzo: Oh, actually, I have no idea what my proficiency is.
Unknown: Do I get plus 10 on that-
DM: Yes
Unknown: ... on this sword?
DM: Same as your, it's the same as your punch.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: It's a monk weapon.
Kenzo: Okay. Short sword's a monk weapon?
DM: I think so.
DM: Is it?
Kenzo: I have no idea.
Unknown: Simple weapons.
DM: Oh, no.
Unknown: Yeah, a short sword's a simple weapon.
Wellby: Short, no, short... You specifically have short sword proficiency.
Unknown: Oh, I do have short sword.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. Look at that. Scimitar, short...
Kenzo: Okay, cool. Uh, how much damage does a short sword do?
DM: Uh, it's just your monk damage.
DM: It's the same as your unarmed strike.
Unknown: Oh, really? Okay.
DM: Yeah.
DM: Just tell me how many rolls it takes you to do 40 damage.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Okay. That was one, two,
Unknown: three.
Unknown: Great.
Delwath: Oh, sorry, four rolls to do 40 damage.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: So-
DM: Kenzo's hacking at a different one?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: Okay. Make another wisdom save.
Delwath: Uh, 23.
DM: Um.
Unknown: Oh, that's, uh, 15.
DM: Take another level of exhaustion.
Kenzo: Ugh. Uh, five.
Unknown: Five.
DM: Make a wisdom save.
DM: What you're, what you feel when you take exhaustion-
Kenzo: Uh, 23
DM: ... take a level of exhaustion.
Delwath: I'm gonna let you hack through the other one
DM: ... is the sh- the weight of the sh- like you, you feel as if there's, like you can never see sunlight again.
DM: It's like everything is dark,
DM: impossible to see.
Kenzo: How do I take a level of exhaustion?
Delwath: Click on active condi- click on conditions.
DM: Um, you've now been both hacking long enough.
Unknown: Just under equipment.
DM: Both of you make another wisdom save.
Unknown: Top right.
Unknown: Huh? Uh, 18.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: 19.
DM: Um,
DM: that both fails. Do you want to re-roll?
Kenzo: Uh, I'll, I'll do my bardic inspiration.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: That's 12, right? 12.
DM: Yeah. Um, your strength and dex are both reduced by five.
Unknown: Yeah. Um, 30.
Unknown: I'll, I'll
Unknown: 30.
DM: You succeed. You take another level of exhaustion.
Delwath: Uh, 20, uh, 20.
DM: Okay, that succeeds. So your d- your scores are not...
DM: No, th- this-
Delwath: Actually, I'd be better off with strength and dex reduced
DM: ... well, you'd also take exhaustion. This isn't, you don't need a long rest.
DM: You just need a short rest in daylight to heal this exhaustion.
Kenzo: Okay. All right, so I've got two levels of exhaustion.
DM: But if you get to six, you die.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Hold on.
Kenzo: Uh, wait, wait, wait. So there's-
Unknown: But-
Kenzo: I've hacked off one.
Delwath: You've hacked off two.
DM: You really don't want to fail because it reduces your strength and dex by five if you fail a saving throw.
Kenzo: Should, can somebody else fucking help here with this, like, situation?
Unknown: Uh, I guess I should be hacking.
Unknown: Do you want to help?
Delwath: No, I'm gonna be hacking at the other one too.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: All right. There, there's only one more left.
DM: Yeah, it's got-
Wellby: There are four all together?
DM: Yeah, four all together.
Kenzo: You've only defeated one.
Unknown: I've done one.
Delwath: Well, I crit it.
Delwath: I assume I can crit this?
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Does anyone else want to help, help here and not take levels of exhaustion so we're just like the two melee guys are like, you know?
Wellby: Come, come out and ask, man. You're in another dimension.
Delwath: 10, 15, yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, we get to see what's happening.
Kenzo: Yeah, come, I, I come out. Come in. Help, help, help.
Delwath: Okay. Okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: 15, 20, 30.
Kenzo: I give the short sword to one of you guys.
Kenzo: Take the short sword.
Delwath: Uh, 19, 21.
Delwath: Um-
Unknown: Okay
Delwath: ... we probably got 40 on this.
DM: Are you both on the same one?
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: I just left.
Delwath: Oh. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: But, but Wellby just showed up.
Delwath: Quietly, yeah.
Wellby: But you want a hand with this magical shadow prison?
Kenzo: Yes, hack the thing.
DM: Well, we can, well we can hack it.
Unknown: Probably, yeah.
Wellby: Can I get, um, sneak attack since it's next to an alley?
Delwath: Sure.
DM: I mean, normally you can't sneak it. I mean, you don't need much so you can cut through it, but make a wisdom saving throw.
Unknown: Uh, wisdom saving throw-
Delwath: Nice
Wellby: ... is 23.
DM: Okay, you take one level of exhaustion.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: As the last one falls and
DM: this giant
DM: eight foot by three foot by three foot
DM: crystal structure just floats in the air.
Delwath: Can we, can we...
Delwath: Does it move if I touch it?
DM: Mm, it's pretty heavy.
Wellby: I, I'll, I'll just give it a few knocks.
DM: See what happens.
Unknown: Hm.
Unknown: Um, we can, we can move it? I don't know.
Delwath: Does it, I mean, can I...
Delwath: Is it, it's floating.
Unknown: It's suspended.
Delwath: So like, does-
DM: But it's like you push, it's very heavy.
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: Rainbow bridge?
Delwath: How would that help us?
Kenzo: And then fucking take this thing right back onto the ship.
Delwath: We can't carry it.
Unknown: Too heavy?
Delwath: Super heavy. So-
Kenzo: Can we change ourselves into elephants?
Wellby: Well, can we dispel magic it?
Delwath: Yes.
Wellby: Can we-
Seeker: So Seeker will take a close look at this crystal and-
Unknown: Take a look, yeah.
DM: You're jumping down in as well?
Wellby: Wellby's rotating-
Seeker: I, I come in, yes
Wellby: ... back out again with Kenzo
Unknown: ... I came in with Wellby.
DM: Okay, so who's in right now?
Kenzo: Everybody except Kenzo. I'm outside.
Wellby: No, no, I'm coming back out again.
Seeker: All right. Seeker and Delwath are in.
Delwath: I don't like being in here. Yeah, I don't like being in here either, but like we gotta like, you know, help.
DM: You can jump out.
DM: I mean, you can keep moving in and out.
Delwath: Yeah. Okay. Uh, I'll-
DM: Okay. Seeker, make a wisdom saving throw.
Seeker: What's my wisdom save?
Seeker: Uh, plus zero. Great.
Seeker: 14.
DM: Uh, you take a level of exhaustion and your strength and dexterity are both reduced by five.
Delwath: Uh, you can't do another one of those or you're dead.
Kenzo: You want to do a bardic inspiration on yourself?
Seeker: Cannot do that.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Do a heroic inspiration.
Delwath: Do you still have a heroic inspiration?
Seeker: I do have a heroic inspiration.
Delwath: Use that.
Kenzo: Wait, but that's not gonna be helpful 'cause the, the, it, he needs a 20, I think, to-
DM: He needs a n- he needs a 20.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: 19 failed.
DM: So that's not gonna be useful.
DM: 21 succeeded, so presumably a 20.
Kenzo: Yeah. It's not gonna be.
Delwath: Oof, that's a really hard thing-
Kenzo: It's not gonna, like, work worth it for you to do
Delwath: ... for you to do.
DM: Cha'mut doesn't want people breaking into his prison.
Delwath: Yeah. Uh, let's regroup out of the prison for a moment.
Unknown: But you still get your investigation.
Delwath: Investigation, yeah.
DM: Before you get the exhaustion we'll-
Delwath: Please, please
Unknown: ... arcana.
Kenzo: Do investigate, yeah, arcana the fuck out of it.
DM: Or invest- uh, it's the same plus for you for...
Delwath: Okay, that you can use heroic inspiration on.
Seeker: So that's a natural one.
Kenzo: Yes, definitely.
Seeker: I use my heroic inspiration.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: I'm gonna roll it.
Unknown: 13 plus 15, yeah, 28.
Delwath: 28, okay.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: so
DM: the, the thing... So you, you, you sort of, well, while the saddows are, shadows are sapping your strength and you're feeling this, like, sense of the sun
DM: just vanishing from the world.
Delwath: Hm.
DM: And feeling your limbs grow heavy with weariness and oppressive slowness
DM: in this shadow world.
DM: You look at this thing and it seems, so it's, uh, uh, it, it seems as if almost it's just, uh, it's unaffected by
DM: gravity. So it still has mass.
Delwath: Hm.
DM: You could push it in any direction, but you still need to overcome the inertia of the thing.
Wellby: So push it out?
DM: You could pu- I mean, you could probably pull it out onto the bottom if you had a way to move 1,000 pounds.
Delwath: Right. I'm not the strongest.
Wellby: Do something strong for a sec.
Delwath: No.
Delwath: That's gone.
Seeker: Animal Shapes is down. I could polymorph myself
Seeker: right now burning one of my very rema- few remaining [laughs] spell slots.
Seeker: Um.
Wellby: Is the ladder still around? How much can the ladder...?
Kenzo: Ladder's gone. Wall her.
DM: Ladder's, ladder...
Seeker: Uh, the construct-
Unknown: No, the construct's gone. The ladder's still around
Seeker: ... the ladder is still up.
Seeker: So I could poke my head out, call the ladder in, and have it push this thing out.
Wellby: How much can the ladder lift?
DM: The ladder can prob- It's large, right?
DM: And it has an 18 strength.
Seeker: It has an 18 strength.
DM: So it can, it can pull...
Delwath: I mean, there are technically rules for how much you can-
Unknown: Yeah, that's what I'm looking up.
Kenzo: Can we all, uh, help the ladder and just like, you know, pull, like pull the ladder as a ladder?
Delwath: You can-
Seeker: I mean, it's very easy to grab the ladder.
Unknown: It is a ladder.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. [laughs]
Delwath: 30 times your strength score.
Seeker: For large?
Unknown: The ladder can wrap itself around it.
Unknown: Large, uh-
Kenzo: And have the ladder bridge the dimensions.
Delwath: Double it. So-
Kenzo: And then we're on the other side.
Delwath: So twice that.
DM: Yeah. The ladder can, the, the ladder can do it.
DM: The ladder can pull 1,000 pounds.
Kenzo: Amazing. Let's fucking do this shit.
Wellby: Does the mirror of soul trapping require the subject to be awake?
DM: Yes. The subject has to see its reflection.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: That was a good idea, though.
Seeker: All right. So we see, um-
Wellby: Maybe we can wake her up
Unknown: ... Seeker's-
Wellby: It's even inside the crystal
Seeker: ... arm come out over the, over the edge, pull himself out.
Seeker: He beckons the ladder to dive through the portal.
Seeker: It wraps itself around the crystal and slowly begins to-
Unknown: Drags it out
Unknown: ... drag it out.
DM: Which is what I was gonna say for the ladder.
Seeker: Oh, yeah. So the ladder's [laughs] gonna get exhausted too.
Seeker: So that's, uh,
Seeker: 16.
Seeker: Uh, it has plus zero wisdom.
DM: The ladder manages-
Delwath: It's immune to exhaustion.
DM: Oh. Even better.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: So the ladder is unaffected.
Unknown: Amazing.
Unknown: Um-
Unknown: I'm gonna be calling it
Unknown: ...
DM: the ladder manages to drag this crystal out and, like, collapse
DM: onto the,
Unknown: um,
DM: onto the floor of the,
DM: of the chamber,
DM: and you can all now see this, like, grayish crystal with somebody trapped inside.
Delwath: How do we get her out?
Wellby: I'm gonna bonk on her a bunch and see if we can just wake her up.
Delwath: Seems...
Kenzo: Can we just teleport now out of here?
Delwath: I mean, should we just leave with the thing?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Like, I mean-
Seeker: Can you carry the crystal and teleport?
Seeker: That's interesting.
Delwath: No.
Kenzo: I thought you could teleport an object.
Delwath: Can you teleport the ladder?
Delwath: How many creatures can you teleport?
Wellby: You can teleport an object or creatures.
Seeker: Eight willing... Up to eight willing creatures
Seeker: or a single object.
Delwath: Like...
Delwath: Oh, but can the ladder carry...
Delwath: The ladder probably can't actually lift.
Delwath: What's your lift?
DM: I don't think the ladder can actually pick it up.
DM: The ladder can just, like, drag it.
DM: Although, actually, now that it's here, it's just kind of floating, right?
Delwath: It's not exactly like, dragging.
Seeker: We have to release it from this crystal.
Wellby: Uh, l- inspect it closely, investigate and use all your powers of Arcana to think about how would it have been constructed.
Delwath: Yeah. Yeah.
Wellby: How do you reverse engineer it? Are there...
DM: Um, make an Arcana check.
Seeker: Nice. Yeah, that's...
Unknown: [dice clattering] 20.
DM: I mean,
DM: trapping a
Delwath: powerful
DM: archfey... [sighs] You have no idea how you might be able to break this.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: The best you might be able to do is get her out of here.
Delwath: [thud]
Unknown: In the crystal.
DM: In the crystal.
Unknown: But even that-
Delwath: Add that to the side quest list.
Seeker: We could put the crystal into the portable hole.
Unknown: Although it's-
Delwath: We could
Seeker: ... it's pretty big.
DM: It's, it's just about the same size-
Unknown: Oh
Delwath: ... as the throne, which we have conveniently-
Unknown: We've already-
DM: ... already given to...
Seeker: We took the throne out already.
Seeker: Plenty of room in there.
Delwath: I mean,
Delwath: yeah, why don't we just...
Delwath: What exactly is the downside in just sticking...
Wellby: 'Cause it'd be nice to have her kill the dragon for us.
Kenzo: I mean, it feels a little, like, like, as Arcana, I'd like to not fight the dragon.
Delwath: It does a little bit.
Seeker: But we might... Uh, that could be what happens anyway.
Unknown: I mean, how are you planning to escape without fighting the dragon?
Wellby: Teleport.
Delwath: To where?
Seeker: Teleport up to the top of the mountain.
Wellby: Fly the boat-
Delwath: Yeah
Wellby: ... sail through the storm.
Delwath: You'd have to sleep to fly the boat.
Wellby: Ah, we'd have to f- we'd have to sleep.
Seeker: I can animal shapes again.
Delwath: So you sleep.
Kenzo: Okay, as long as Lumece fights the dragon there.
Delwath: I mean, we could still teleport to the top of the mountain.
Delwath: Yep. The dragon might come after us.
Seeker: We just can't... Oh, we c- okay.
Seeker: So we're gonna put Cloudspinner in the hole.
Delwath: Okay.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: I think that's the right call.
Unknown: Yeah. Crystal-
Delwath: Ladder drags Cloudspinner into the...
Delwath: I mean, would, would that... Would now be a good time to-
Wellby: Man, this means we won't be able to take the throne with us, though.
Kenzo: Take the what with us?
Wellby: The throne.
Seeker: Oh, you wanted to, to take back the throne.
Wellby: Oh.
Delwath: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh. Wait, wait, wait.
Wellby: This is better than the throne.
Kenzo: We can still take the throne back with us.
Delwath: I don't have space for both Cloudspinner and-
Wellby: 'Cause the cry- the giant crystal
DM: ... you can't fit both the crystal and the throne in the portable hole.
Kenzo: [sighs] We can't fit the crystal and the throne in the portable hole.
Delwath: No, we'll-
Unknown: Can we, uh-
Delwath: We'll give the throne to, like, um, Ghesh
Unknown: Y-
Delwath: Why wouldn't you give it to Dimitar?
Delwath: Or Dimitar. Dimi- Dimita- does Dimitar want the throne?
Delwath: Maybe.
Delwath: He might want the throne.
DM: I don't know. Would Dimitar want a giant Gemin crystal throne?
Wellby: [sneezes] I mean...
Kenzo: Not to sit on, but to like, you know,
Kenzo: incorporate into some, like...
Kenzo: Like... Oh, it would be like the Wizard of Oz.
DM: It would replace the wizard. It would be The Wizard of Oz.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: He would 100% use it as The Wizard of Oz.
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah.
Unknown: Exactly.
Delwath: Um,
Delwath: I mean, right.
Delwath: The other way we could get out of here for sure
Delwath: would be to go back down into Cha'mutte's dimension in Rainbow Bridge.
Wellby: But we abandon Milo if we do that.
Delwath: No, he's gonna run away in two days.
Delwath: We send him a link message.
Seeker: That... We have the opportunity right now to do that.
Delwath: Like, there's no reason-
Kenzo: Actually, yeah, just fucking sail out and then we'll pick him up on the other side of the storm.
Delwath: I could send the links message to say flee now.
Delwath: Yeah, but we have to fight the dragon.
Delwath: We all want to fight the... I know. We all want to fight the dragon.
Seeker: Well, and we still have plenty of time on Apollyon, so we don't need to just, like, rush out of here.
Delwath: The main thing is do we try and fight the dragon without long resting?
Wellby: No, we're definitely long rest.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: You're not getting a spell.
Delwath: But then-
Unknown: Um, I need to-
Delwath: ... what, do we just hope that the dragon hangs around until the morning?
Delwath: I mean, maybe the dragon can't come down here.
Wellby: Dragon can probably teleport itself.
Seeker: How, how long is, how long have we been down here?
Kenzo: Teleport from here to, to Dimitar's place.
Unknown: But why would the-
DM: You haven't been d- you've been barely down here for-
Unknown: We've been down here for, like, 20 minutes
Delwath: ... 15 minutes.
Seeker: Right. But-
DM: Like, if... You might not want to linger for too long.
Seeker: If she, if she knew how to get, get in...
Unknown: If she could get in, then she would get in.
Unknown: If she could teleport in here, she would be here.
DM: But it's probably not a safe place to take a short rest, 'cause you know she has minions that are smaller than she is.
Kenzo: No, why don't we teleport from here to, like, you know, back to Dimitar's place?
Unknown: Long rest.
Delwath: I mean, do we think she wouldn't just come after us there?
DM: She might interrupt your long rest.
Delwath: There, she might come after us there.
Delwath: We don't know.
Wellby: Would she come after us-
Delwath: Yeah, we-
Wellby: ... if we rested at Apollyon's Tower this time?
Seeker: That's what I was gonna say. We could teleport there instead.
Delwath: I like that.
Wellby: We could.
Wellby: Do we want a long rest at Apollyon's T- I have bad vibes from that place.
Delwath: I know.
Unknown: As far as we know, we cleared it out, but...
Kenzo: Throw those back down to Dimitar's tower.
Kenzo: There's the belfry. It's the tallest point on the whole fucking island.
Delwath: Like, we'll see her coming from miles away-
Seeker: Mm. That's an important point
Delwath: ... from any direction away.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: We can rotate watches in a long rest, right?
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: I mean, if she sends her full force, it's gonna be all the dragonets, the four chimera things, and herself, so it'll be like...
Wellby: If she sends just the dragonets, maybe Dimitar can-
Delwath: Yeah, she can handle them
Wellby: ... seize control of them, or, or we can kill them And if she's coming to us there, that's great because then she's not in her lair.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: It's great for us.
Kenzo: No matter what, we're gonna fight her not in the lair 'cause she's gonna come chase after us.
Kenzo: Like, there's zero reason there to go in her lair.
Delwath: Right. I mean, why would we go in her lair?
Kenzo: Only at the very end to loot it.
Delwath: Yeah. But, like, there's no reason for us to go in her lair, right?
Delwath: Like-
Unknown: Yeah. No, no, no, no, no. The... We are-
Kenzo: We liberated ourselves from that
Delwath: ... we should certainly...
Delwath: I mean, logically, yes, I guess we should...
Delwath: We could go long rest on the thing and then-
Kenzo: On the thing?
Delwath: On the tower.
Unknown: Yeah, the tower.
Wellby: I think that's the smart thing to do.
Delwath: And then if she sends people after us, well...
Delwath: But in theory, what we do is in the morning, if she hasn't sent anybody after us,
Delwath: why wouldn't we just turn into birds and fly out to Milo and get out of here, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Isn't that the plan?
Unknown: Cool.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Awesome.
Kenzo: But the hope is that she comes after us so we can fight her.
Delwath: Right.
Unknown: And kill her.
Delwath: But... Right.
Delwath: Right.
DM: So which... Where are you teleporting to?
Wellby: I think the tower, right?
Wellby: Tower.
Delwath: Apollyon's Tower?
Unknown: No, no, no, no. Dimitar's.
Delwath: Oh, okay. Dimitar's.
Unknown: And, and that-
Delwath: Wait. I thought we were gonna go to Apollyon's Tower.
Kenzo: I like Dimitar's tower.
Unknown: I don't really know. I'd go to Apollyon's Tower.
Seeker: I, I feel safest at the top of the mountain.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah, top is... It's the, it's the highest point on the whole island.
Kenzo: We get a fucking view of everything, you know?
Delwath: Yeah. I just... Why wouldn't... If she's really pissed enough, she's probably gonna come after us.
Unknown: Yeah. That's- she'll fucking fly towards the, the, there.
Delwath: Well, she'll get there before we're done with the long rest.
Unknown: That's o-
Delwath: I mean, that's fine, I guess.
Delwath: Seeker just has no spells left whatsoever, right?
Kenzo: I mean, the other options are what?
Kenzo: I mean, what other options do we have?
Kenzo: I guess we could fly, or we could teleport to, like, a point that's, like s- Like, how, how fast, how fast do dragons fly?
Wellby: Why...
Wellby: How's she gonna find us?
Wellby: She could probably scry on us.
Delwath: Mm.
Unknown: Maybe. I don't know.
Wellby: She's probably somewhere flying.
Delwath: I mean, it's a good question.
DM: I mean, it's a very open, visible spot.
Delwath: I mean, the other idea would be to, like, go somewhere in the forest.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, we could go to fucking Gresh's tower.
Delwath: That was my other thought.
Seeker: We could long rest right here.
Seeker: Go Gresh's tower.
Delwath: She'll probably-
Wellby: Some- someone's gonna come down to check on us
Delwath: ... so the theory is that she's...
Delwath: She knows we're here 'cause she saw the scragmir, but she doesn't know what's going on 'cause we smashed the scragmir.
Delwath: And so she's gonna send little dragonettes or something to come see what's going on pretty soon.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: And then...
Delwath: But, I mean, there's also the bit of, well,
Delwath: what can she actually send?
Delwath: Like, does she know... Do her dragonettes even know how to get through the secret door?
Kenzo: Like, are you seriously thinking about long resting here?
Delwath: Yeah.
Seeker: That's right. We're in the sealed chamber.
Delwath: We're in a sealed chamber.
Kenzo: This feels... I, I don't know.
Unknown: Does it feel a little, a little-
DM: Decide where, let's decide where you want to long rest, and then we'll break for a hike.
Kenzo: Wait. Why would we, why would we do it here versus the Dimitar's place?
Delwath: Okay. So
Delwath: pro of Apo- Apollyon's Tower, she's very unlikely to come there.
Delwath: Con, it's creepy and weird, and there's probably something terrible that will happen
Seeker: [knocking] It's almost in the tooth.
DM: What's what?
Seeker: Contribution of the pilot lights.
DM: [coughs] I don't know.
Unknown: Probably small.
DM: Compared to like gas leaks, it's gotta be pretty small.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Okay. So we pick up
DM: as you
DM: all collapse into the late afternoon sun
DM: on the summit of the mountain in the middle of the circular island.
DM: Um,
DM: sitting in the sunshine, you begin to forget the
DM: webs of shadow that have reduced Seeker to being like somebody else has to carry your backpack 'cause you can barely even lift your arm with a three strength,
DM: and
DM: reduced many of you to quite a high level of exhaustion.
DM: And as you... So it's only been now, at this point,
DM: something like
DM: 15 minutes since, or maybe 20 minutes since you left the company of Ra'ghemdros,
DM: made your way through the Cloudspinner's prison, and managed to rescue her now, her now in your portable hole.
Seeker: [clears throat] After defeating the fiend.
DM: After defeating the fiend.
DM: So at this point, you know, things seem quiet on the island, although there must be some activity down in the...
DM: Oh, actually you'd probably be able to see, it's only like six or seven miles away.
DM: You can see the,
DM: um,
DM: the circ- the shape of the, of Ra'ghemdros kind of flying around agitatedly, seemingly
DM: talking to, you know, stopping occasionally, like talking to some people,
DM: talking to the chimeras maybe, and then disappears back into her lair.
Unknown: We should, [clears throat] get under cover sooner rather than later.
DM: Yeah. You-
Delwath: Go into the temple
DM: ... go into the temple.
DM: Um-
Seeker: We teleported
DM: ... or you teleported into the temple.
Seeker: Directly inside the temple.
DM: Okay. So you're in the temple.
DM: [clicks tongue] Um, Dimitar,
DM: you hear the start of a, "Who dares..."
DM: Oh, wait. And he steps out from behind the statue.
DM: It's you. [clears throat]
Unknown: We've, um, we've stirred up some trouble, Dimitar.
Unknown: A little bit.
Unknown: But it's good for you in the long run.
Wellby: I think you're gonna like it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Not in the short run. You're gonna like it.
DM: Uh,
DM: tell me more.
Unknown: Well, well, we, we
Delwath: broke, um,
Unknown: Ra'ghemdros.
Unknown: Well, first of all, we made a deal. We made...
Kenzo: We, we, we broke like a, like 100-year-old, uh, f- uh, curse and prison thing.
Delwath: It, Ra'ghemdros is quite matted and is probably looking for us to try to kill us.
DM: And you came here because?
Unknown: It felt safe and cozy and home-like.
Wellby: You could protect us.
Delwath: And we thought maybe your fireballs would be helpful.
Kenzo: Hey, great news.
DM: I think you've misjudged the situation.
Kenzo: Dimitar, great news.
Kenzo: And, uh, Kenzo pulls out the staff.
Unknown: We got the last piece of jade. Rise hand.
Unknown: Isn't that great?
DM: Oh, that's nice.
DM: Uh,
DM: it would be more useful if you weren't bringing death down upon us.
Kenzo: That's just like a minor detail.
Wellby: You've lived with your death for a long time.
DM: She's never had a reason to scry me.
DM: She's gonna scry the entire island now.
Wellby: Oh, fuck. Top. [laughs] Urgently pulls it out and starts spinning it.
DM: Di- Dimitar's staring at it and it's spinning.
DM: What's that?
Wellby: It's a top.
Delwath: Um, hey, Dim. By the way...
Unknown: Wait, did I do see invisible?
Unknown: Did I do see invisible?
Seeker: When?
Unknown: Like,
Delwath: uh, when we started combat.
Delwath: No, I didn't. I'm gonna say it wasn't.
DM: You did it with the... You only did it in the-
Unknown: I mean-
Unknown: ... vests
Delwath: ... it only lasts for an hour,
Unknown: but I can see a scrying sensor.
Seeker: Oh, I didn't know that that was a thing.
Unknown: Yeah. It's just a, it's like a eye.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: It's just an invisible eye. If you can see invisible, you can see the scrying sensor.
Unknown: Wait, does the top still spin?
Unknown: Yeah, I'm gonna, I'm gonna see invisible.
Kenzo: Is the top still spinning?
DM: Dimitar's looking at it.
Unknown: Is there a-
DM: What's it supposed to do?
Unknown: Is there an eye?
DM: No, there's not an eye.
Unknown: Wait, wait. It's supposed to
Wellby: s- spin if we're being watched?
Unknown: It spins if anybody's watching.
DM: It spins if it's being watched, but everybody has to turn their back and wait for it to fall down.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: Dimitar doesn't quite get the picture.
Wellby: Y- you gotta clo- close your eyes, Dimitar.
Wellby: It, it detects if we're being scried.
DM: Wait, why? It seems like it spins on its own.
DM: I'd call it something like a always spinning top.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah, but only if you look at it.
Delwath: If you walk away, it'll fall over unless somebody else is looking.
Seeker: If anybody's looking at it, it keeps spinning.
DM: Okay, let's all do a test.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Everybody turn their back. I'll close my eyes and we'll see what happens.
DM: Listen for it.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It keeps spinning.
Wellby: Are your eyes really closed, Dimitar?
DM: No. [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah, they were.
Wellby: Yeah, Dimitar, actually close your eyes this time.
DM: He closes his eyes. It falls down.
Unknown: No, all, all the way.
DM: It falls down.
Delwath: But I can see there's no scrying sensor.
DM: Then he opens his eyes a peek.
DM: Oh, wow. It stands up on its own.
DM: Do, do, do you need this?
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah.
DM: Really?
Kenzo: We'll give it to you later after we kill Apollyon.
Kenzo: It's yours. Promise.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: We've, we've been spies for so long.
Wellby: He's not in power to make this deal-
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: ... on behalf of all of us.
Unknown: After we kill Apollyon.
DM: Why not? He looks like the strong one.
Unknown: Uh.
DM: Or maybe him.
Unknown: I mean
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Huh. Huh.
Unknown: I think Kenzo deserves to make decisions about the top.
Kenzo: Look, the point is, Dimitar, we were successful in bringing together the hand of your former friend and ally.
Kenzo: Um, we completed a very, very complex quest to get this thing done.
Unknown: Also-
DM: That seems awesome for you.
Unknown: Huh?
DM: I said that seems awesome for you.
Kenzo: For us. For us collectively, as you share in a similar goal and vision.
Kenzo: Uh, also, um,
Kenzo: we, uh, we, we freed, uh, or we, we have a, a giant crystal with a, uh
Unknown: Cloudspinner person inside. Yeah, an ancient archfey.
Wellby: Yeah. Who's been imprisoned for millennium.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Oh.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: What?
DM: That makes sense now.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, she's here.
DM: Oh, she's gonna be so pissed.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. But she's here. Remember when we...
Unknown: Weren't you listening earlier?
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
DM: You didn't know about the Cloudspinner earlier.
Unknown: No, no, no, no. When we came here, starting by saying the dragon is really bad.
DM: Oh, yeah. Ha ha, this guy gets it.
Delwath: Um, here, uh,
Delwath: I'm gonna scry Ragemptus.
DM: Uh, it doesn't work.
DM: She went into her lair.
DM: Scrying across planes.
Unknown: But how can she scry across planes?
DM: Her lair is magic.
Unknown: [snapping fingers] Anyways, uh, so there's probably
Kenzo: like monsters, maybe hordes of monsters headed here.
Unknown: Um...
DM: I mean, it's not gonna be instantaneous.
Kenzo: Yeah. We're, that's... We're gonna rest, right?
DM: She's gotta scry the whole island.
DM: She can't just see it all at once.
Kenzo: Exactly. So we have time.
Seeker: Should keep an eye out through the window just in case the chimeras do fly straight for us at some point.
DM: Um...
DM: What's like maybe highest?
DM: I'm gonna suggest maybe sleeping in the tunnels.
Unknown: I like this idea. That's a great idea.
DM: I mean, I never sleep out in the open.
DM: Only fools do that.
Kenzo: [laughs] Yeah, we weren't thinking about doing that.
Kenzo: Um, [clears throat] that's a great idea.
Unknown: Why don't we go do that?
DM: It's a little tight.
DM: You'll, you two will be fine.
DM: How do you feel about tight spaces?
DM: Any claustrophobia?
Unknown: It's fine.
DM: Okay.
DM: Um-
Kenzo: As long as I don't have to cuddle with the elf, I'm fine.
DM: Oh, no. You can all be in a row.
Unknown: All right.
DM: But, uh,
DM: hmm.
Unknown: Where's the entrance to these tunnels?
DM: This is the trap door behind the statue.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Should someone be keeping lookout?
Delwath: I might wait out here.
Delwath: A, I don't actually need a long rest.
Delwath: And B, I only need four hours to get a long rest.
Unknown: Awesome. Whatever you like.
DM: It's up to you.
Delwath: I mean, it's a little tight, right?
DM: I mean,
DM: yeah, but when she scrys you,
DM: what do you think she's gonna do?
Unknown: But can she not scry in the tunnels?
Kenzo: But when she does, she just sees a bunch of tunnels.
Unknown: Unless she-
DM: I mean...
Delwath: If she can scry us physically, specifically us, it's not gonna take her any time.
DM: Uh, no, she can scry the island.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. That's what I said.
DM: Any location on the island.
Unknown: But can she scry-
DM: That was what Dimitar was saying.
Delwath: Yeah, no, I got that. But can she scry inside the temple?
DM: I mean,
Unknown: probably. She's aware of it.
Unknown: So, so-
DM: She might not be aware... Dimitar doesn't think she's aware of its tunnels.
Delwath: So she probably can't scry inside the tunnel.
Unknown: Let's all go in the tunnels.
DM: Yeah, let's go in the tunnels.
Kenzo: I like it. Yeah. [clears throat] That feels like a great thing to do.
Kenzo: Hey, you seem to say, seem to know something about the person, uh, trapped inside the, uh-
DM: No, I don't, but it all clicked into place.
DM: I knew the story.
Unknown: Which story?
DM: That Shemut
DM: captured some powerful archfey who refused to give him the secrets of divinity that he wanted to use to
DM: kill the gods, and that Apollyon wanted to use to become a god.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: And they fought over what it, whoever this was,
DM: and Shemut won,
DM: but Apollyon got away with some magic item.
DM: I don't know what it was.
DM: That must have been what
DM: Ragemptus has been guarding this whole time, the thing that
DM: Shemut was trying to use to learn how to kill the gods.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: What did you say? Who did you say it was?
Unknown: Cloudspinner.
DM: I don't know who that is.
Delwath: Who it was. It's the person.
Delwath: It's her name.
DM: That's her name. Ah, okay.
DM: That's a good fey name.
Kenzo: So why did Ragemptus use Cloudspinner for herself?
Kenzo: I mean, Shemut's been dead for hundreds of years.
Kenzo: Like, why is she still, why is she still, why she been still guarding it this whole time?
Kenzo: For what purpose?
DM: I don't know.
Seeker: Perhaps it's a curse upon her.
DM: I mean-
Kenzo: I can ask her when she, she shows up.
DM: Maybe she is unable to disobey Shemut's command.
Delwath: Oh, that's interesting. What's the theory of why we would be here when she shows up exactly?
Unknown: What do you mean?
Delwath: Like, why wouldn't we just teleport away?
DM: After you long rest?
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
DM: Wait, you're gonna leave me to be slaughtered by a dragon?
Kenzo: You're coming with us. You're coming with us.
DM: You're gonna leave the dragonets to be slaughtered by a dragon?
Unknown: Why would she kill them?
Wellby: 'Cause they brought us to her and like vouched for us and-
DM: Have you never fought like a dragon before?
DM: She's gonna kill everybody on this island if she doesn't get the Cloudspinner back.
Unknown: Uh.
Delwath: Uh. [sighs] I guess we have to be heroes.
DM: I mean, how many people can you teleport?
Unknown: Eight.
DM: Oh, well, that's useless.
Unknown: Why is that?
DM: I mean, there's at least
DM: 50 I'd wanna rescue.
Kenzo: [clears throat] This is gonna make the airship really fun later.
DM: There's a, there's a-
Unknown: Well, not if we kill the dragon today
DM: ... there's like 100 we could just let die.
DM: That'd be fine.
Kenzo: Wait, but what about the ones that are loyal to her?
Unknown: She's gonna kill them too?
DM: She might. Have you ever seen a really, truly pissed dragon?
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: I mean, yeah.
Unknown: We've killed a couple.
DM: Oh, that's great, actually. Then you're definitely staying.
Seeker: [sighs] [clears throat] Smaller ones.
Seeker: We've killed mostly slightly smaller ones.
Kenzo: Where do you think we should fight her?
DM: Well,
DM: it's always time to step up in the world, right?
Kenzo: So Dimitar, where do you think we should fight her?
Kenzo: We meaning the four, the five of us together.
DM: Wait, can you fly?
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: All of you?
Wellby: Yep.
Unknown: Ish. Sort of.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Close enough.
DM: Um, 'cause, you know,
DM: she's probably not gonna land.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Air combat, huh?
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Oh, I have a rules question, Tim.
Seeker: I thought I saw something about
Seeker: long rest while waking, while being able to do things that require being awake,
Seeker: like a special ability.
DM: Like what?
Seeker: That I could have a long rest while being awake.
Unknown: Oh, simulacrum.
DM: Oh. Um, no, you can't have a long rest unless...
DM: What special ability is this?
Seeker: Something that I was reading a lot of stuff on my character sheet, and I remember seeing that, but maybe that was a spell.
DM: I don't know.
Delwath: You might have a potion or something that lets you do that.
Delwath: Oh, you... I think you might have.
Unknown: Go check your, check your character sheet.
Delwath: Tim might have something there as a-
DM: You have a potion of watchful rest.
Unknown: That's what it is.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah. But simulacrum takes 12 hours.
DM: [chuckles]
Unknown: How long is a long rest?
DM: Eight hour... I mean, if you start right now, you might have a chance.
Seeker: That's why I wanna raise the question, might be useful thinking about this upcoming conflict to have another
Seeker: one of us or something.
Unknown: I can make another dimitar. That's not a good-
Unknown: No. Making the simulacrum cast spells?
DM: Yep.
Delwath: And it can't, but it can't regain slots, right?
DM: It can't re-- it, it can't benefit from a rest.
Seeker: So like if we had another, what would it be?
Seeker: Delwath 'cause it can cast fly on itself.
Delwath: It could cast fly on it and me and you.
Seeker: And it could then also cast some attack spells that are things that the dragon might be vulnerable to.
Delwath: I mean, it's tough to do
Delwath: concentration, like fly is a concentration spell, so it cuts into ability to do other concentration spells.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: But there's other spells.
Unknown: I mean...
Seeker: Or would it be better to have another Kenzo or Wellby?
Delwath: But another Kenzo or Wellby would have a hard time flying.
DM: They'd have a hard time flying 'cause they can't duplicate magic items.
Kenzo: Can you make a resilient?
DM: No, they have to be there.
Unknown: I mean, I think a du- Delwath would be pretty useful.
Delwath: Like it could just rain...
Unknown: It could, it
Unknown: could-
DM: I mean, really what it should do is cast fly and then hide.
Unknown: That's what I was gonna say.
Seeker: I guess if only we had another ladder.
Seeker: If we had another, [chuckles] if we had another Seeker.
DM: You could make another-
Seeker: It could do another animated-
DM: Seeker could make another ladder, that's true
Unknown: ... it could do its own animated performance and ride that ladder.
Delwath: No, but honestly-
Seeker: It's just really slow. It's a 30 foot ladder
Delwath: ... casting fly
Unknown: on-
Seeker: Well, what's fly speed for a cast of fly?
DM: 60.
Seeker: 60. Yeah, so
Unknown: that might be better.
Delwath: But the nice thing about casting fly and, uh, simulacrum Delwath who casts fly and then tries to stay out of combat, try and stay far away, and uses,
Unknown: um,
Delwath: metamagic to cast 240 foot range eldritch blasts or something like that.
Unknown: It would have to drag, I think if it wants to do-
Unknown: Yeah, no, I can, I can drag Delwath.
Seeker: Delwath Prime.
DM: Well, I mean, there's no guarantee you're, you're gonna have 12 hours.
DM: That's the only problem.
Seeker: And it, it burns a high level spell slot if it casts it.
DM: It burns your seventh level slot, and if you,
DM: if you get interrupted in the middle of casting, it's just wasted.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: It'd be super useful, but I don't think we know the timeline with enough confidence.
Delwath: But when are you gonna use just that level spot slot in combat form anyway?
Wellby: You also wouldn't be able to-
Unknown: 'Cause, because it doesn't...
Delwath: I mean, you're not gonna use your eighth level slot on animal shapes.
Unknown: You have no other eighth level spells for you.
DM: Unless... Right. All it means is you would have to-
Unknown: Sure
DM: ... like even if, instead of what you...
DM: You would have to save your eighth level slot-
Unknown: For teleport
DM: ... for teleport because you don't wanna take another long rest on the island.
Unknown: But we don't have to teleport to get off the island.
DM: Oh, that's true. You can just sail.
Delwath: I mean, I'm gonna send a message to, to our, to Milo again.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: To say, um-
Kenzo: Yeah, stay here now. [laughs]
Delwath: Right. Uh, imminent danger.
Unknown: Uh,
Delwath: expect us to be,
Unknown: um-
DM: Do you tell him what the imminent danger is?
Delwath: Yeah. Dragon, imminent danger.
Delwath: Dragon,
Delwath: uh, rampaging on island.
Delwath: But I'm gonna tell him... I don't need to do...
Delwath: 'Cause it's not, it's not Sunday.
Unknown: I don't need to-
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Um, there's a dragon that we've, um, angered who is ranging, uh, raging across the island.
Delwath: We have agreed to stay to kill it or, um, die trying.
Delwath: Expect, we expect this will be resolved shortly after dawn at the latest Um, be prepared to keep an eye on things.
Delwath: We're probably doing this in the air, so you might even be able to see it.
Unknown: Um, if you see the dragon dive, come to shore and be prepared to board us.
Delwath: Uh, if the dragon seems to not dive, flee.
Wellby: Isn't the dragon gonna spot [clears throat] Milo in the boat and kill them
Wellby: as it flies around the island?
Unknown: Mm. [clears throat]
Unknown: Oh, my computer wasn't charging.
Delwath: They gotta, yeah, yeah, I mean, they gotta hide, yeah, but they gotta get somewhere.
Wellby: I think they gotta hide.
Kenzo: They gotta hide. Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: I'll send them a warning. What?
Delwath: I'll send them a warning. I'll tell them our plan is we're probably gonna fight the dragon at dawn,
Delwath: and it's raging in Cross Island and is pretty pissed, and stay away until,
Unknown: like,
Unknown: noon.
Seeker: So I do have the potion of water walking.
Wellby: We could also just tell them to sail out 'cause we can-
Unknown: Ah
Wellby: ... rainbow bridge from the prison or the lair.
Delwath: Oh, that's an interesting idea.
Delwath: We could just tell them to leave.
Unknown: But we...
Delwath: Oh, no, we're pretty confident that rainbow bridge will work from an extra-dimensional space.
Delwath: The problem is my, my messengers can't cross
Unknown: water.
Seeker: We've used it from other dimensions before.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Okay, let's tell Milo to just flee.
Unknown: I think that's safer.
Kenzo: Wait, but then what if the extra-dimensional thing doesn't work?
Unknown: Then we're stuck.
Wellby: Yep.
Kenzo: If we can't rainbow bridge out of here, then there's no way out.
Unknown: Why don't we just have him wait? 'Cause we're worried the dragon's gonna kill him.
Wellby: 'Cause I think the dragon's gonna... Yeah.
Wellby: I think the dragon's gonna kill him.
Unknown: Even if he hides?
Unknown: Where would he hide, though, in the open ocean?
Delwath: I mean, he could sail far away.
Delwath: I think we should just tell him to leave. I think that's safer.
Delwath: We don't even...
Unknown: Yeah, I, that just feels safer.
Wellby: Well, he could hide, like, in one of the temple complexes at one of the statues,
Wellby: but that's, like, a numbers game because if the dragon is systematically, like, looking everywhere on the whole island through scrying...
Kenzo: But aren't his, aren't the dragon's dragonette, like, uh, hen- henchlings gonna, like, see a fucking boat, like, out in the ocean and-
Unknown: Probably
Kenzo: ... immediately wanna go kill it?
Wellby: I mean, are they on the ocean right now?
Unknown: I don't know where he is right now.
Unknown: You don't know where he is right now.
Unknown: Uh-
DM: You don't see him at the moment.
Delwath: I'm gonna send a message.
Delwath: Tell him... I'm just gonna tell him what's coming down and, and-
Wellby: Good luck
Unknown: ... he can respond to the message.
Kenzo: Yeah, they can decide for themselves. I mean-
Delwath: Yeah, he can decide for himself, right? Like-
Kenzo: Like, open ocean is likely death, but, you know.
Delwath: I will te- I will send, I will send the links to him-
Unknown: Okay
Delwath: ... with a letter explaining that the dr- that we've pissed off a dragon, we've agreed to stay and kill the dragon.
Delwath: We expect this will be no later than tomorrow morning.
Delwath: The dragon is looking to kill anything and everything, so keep yourself safe.
Kenzo: Yeah, either flee to the mainland or hide.
Delwath: Don't worry about us. If you think the wisest thing to do is just flee, do it.
Delwath: Like, we'll be okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Flee or hide.
DM: Um, shortly, the message comes back and says, "Message received.
DM: Crew are hiding.
DM: We're coming to hunt a dragon."
Unknown: Oh. [laughs] Okay.
Wellby: Awesome.
Kenzo: Dude, they're fucking badass.
Seeker: They've got... They've, they've taken things, matters into their own hands.
Unknown: I like it.
Unknown: They're like, "This is the way."
Delwath: Um, I didn't tell them... I guess I would have said what...
Unknown: I guess I should [clears throat] I guess I should send the bad things back to say, um-
Unknown: Wait, how many times can I... Can I use this as many times as I want?
DM: No, I think it's... I don't know, but I don't think it's unlimited.
Delwath: I thought it might have just been limited by,
Delwath: by the fact that it can't go that often, that it can't go that fast.
DM: But the fast speed is only once a day.
Delwath: I thought it could go up to two hours.
DM: Well, whatever. It doesn't matter.
Unknown: I don't know.
DM: You could have, you can have told them where you are.
Unknown: Fine.
Unknown: It's fine.
Kenzo: So, Dimitar, where do we want to fight these guys, fight the dragon?
Kenzo: Is there any way to get, get it closer to ground?
Delwath: So I think the simulacrum is potentially worth the risk.
Seeker: What time of day is it right now?
Delwath: It's like, what, 4:00 in the afternoon?
DM: Like 5:00. It's like the hour before sunset.
Seeker: So I could have it ready by dawn.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Do black dragons like to attack in the middle of the night?
Unknown: Probably.
Wellby: Can we do it from inside a tomb?
Seeker: So I need to be near Delwath all, the entire time.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: I need a pile of snow.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Snow?
Seeker: And a lot of rubies.
DM: You need a lot of rubies. Do you have any rubies?
Seeker: Oh, I thought we still had a bunch
Seeker: in the hole, don't we?
Unknown: Uh, we can go check.
Seeker: I believe that we determined that we're gonna be able to do simulacrum at least one more time.
Unknown: I think you're right.
Unknown: And I do have the-
DM: But, but you also tried to restock on rubies and couldn't because the, uh-
Seeker: We had consumed all available rubies.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Because Rizvan had consumed all available rubies.
Unknown: Oh, Rizvan had.
Delwath: Remember to make, to make Uz-Kakar
Unknown: forever safe from undead.
Seeker: Right.
Seeker: There should be giant statues of us in that city, or at least of Rizvan.
DM: There's a giant... There is a giant statue of Rizvan.
Unknown: Yeah, they built one. Oh, right.
Seeker: That's good and appropriate.
Delwath: But the dragon will probably have some rubies
Delwath: once we kill it. We can restock here.
DM: Oh, yeah. No, that's right. You have-
Wellby: And then go back in time and create the simulacrum.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: You have the rubies from the elemental forge.
Seeker: Amazing.
Delwath: None of the materials in the divine forge were useful for this kind of-
DM: No, it was all metal.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: S- So
Unknown: And purely out of
Seeker: strategic concern for our own future wellbeing and not out of vanity, Delwath, you think it is a good idea to make another Delwath?
Delwath: Yeah. 'Cause Fly, I mean, honestly, just having a Delwath literally doing nothing except casting Fly and hiding is very
Delwath: useful because the problem with...
Delwath: When I cast Fly, that's fine, but if I fail a concentration check, we plummet to the ground.
Seeker: Everybody. Wellby and you at least.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: And these guys-
Delwath: They can fly on their own
Seeker: ... have endless flying.
Delwath: Yeah. But also by not, if I'm not using
Unknown: Fly to fl- if I'm not using my concentration to fly, I can use my concentration to do other stuff.
Seeker: And Fly affects-
Delwath: If I cast at 5th level, it's three people.
Seeker: 'Cause then we could get the, um, construct flying too, which would be pretty cool.
Delwath: Either the construct or the...
Delwath: I mean, the other thing is the, the second Delwath could cast Fly on himself,
Delwath: Delwath Prime and Seeker,
Delwath: and then could-
Seeker: It gives us some options, basically.
Delwath: Right. But also could throw spells from long range.
Seeker: Which might even be more important.
Delwath: Right. But to, to stay away so that, like, the dragon doesn't...
Seeker: There needs to be a way to position these, the character figurines.
Delwath: Oh, man. A second Delwath could cast Scatter also.
Seeker: Cast what?
Unknown: Scatter.
Unknown: Ooh, yeah.
Unknown: Two Scatters.
Seeker: Yeah. [clears throat] All right, we should get to work on that.
Delwath: Let's do it. I mean, you can't make one of yourself, can you?
Seeker: I could-- I can, it's just not obviously better than the Delwath version.
Delwath: Yeah, I think Delwath, I think the Delwath version is good, is a good plan.
Seeker: Just because of the Fly spell.
Unknown: That's what-
Delwath: Yeah, I think Fly plus Scatter is pretty useful.
Seeker: So the one remaining question being
Seeker: if Dimitar has an ice machine anywhere.
DM: Uh, Shape Water can freeze water.
Seeker: Oh. Oh, oh, I can... Yeah, yeah.
DM: Yeah, you have an ice machine.
Unknown: On top of the canter. I am an ice machine.
Unknown: Ice water. [chuckles] Shape Water.
Seeker: We only need to run it-
DM: Eat a little bit on the side.
Unknown: What's that?
Seeker: [chuckles] Snow cone, yeah.
Unknown: Delicious.
Seeker: All right, so...
Delwath: I, I think we hide in the tunnel.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Let's try it. I mean,
Delwath: if we get attacked at 3:00 AM before the simulacrum is ready, then we do.
Seeker: Yeah. It's worth a try.
Delwath: But also, like,
Unknown: it's unclear exactly what the mechanism of...
Unknown: What's she gonna do? Can she even fit in the temple to sit?
DM: She could probably crack the roof.
Seeker: Right. Or flood the tunnel with acid or something.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: But she won't be able to get by the ladder.
DM: She's quite a bit bigger than the ladder.
Unknown: That's true.
DM: Be a little bit less of a-
Seeker: Right. [chuckles] Um, all right.
Unknown: So Seeker
Seeker: begin-- drinks the potion of watchful rest.
DM: Yep.
Unknown: Begins the process of...
Seeker: Oh, that's interesting.
Seeker: There's this sort of like
Seeker: rules situation here.
Seeker: Do I have a spell slot that I can use to cast simula- simulacrum?
DM: Oh-
Unknown: Or the-
DM: Oh no, you don't have any spell slots.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: You don't have a 7th or 8th level slot, do you?
DM: No, you don't.
Seeker: Circle of Power can't fix that, can it?
DM: No, it can't.
Unknown: No, we can't do this.
Unknown: Fuck.
Seeker: It was such a good idea.
DM: You used it for Teleport, so y-
Seeker: Oh, I was like, "I have a 7th level slot."
Seeker: No, we just teleported.
DM: You used it to teleport.
Unknown: We just teleported.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So that doesn't work, unfortunately.
Unknown: Ah.
Seeker: No Delwath Prime. Sorry, buddy.
Unknown: That's all right.
Wellby: I think we should long rest, like, immediately.
Unknown: Yeah, that's probably-
Unknown: So we're ready to go at 3:00 AM.
Unknown: Yeah, I think you're right.
DM: Okay.
DM: You all go to sleep.
Wellby: Vision, Jay, Han.
DM: Take... Yep. Take turns-
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Take turns watching.
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: I'm gonna set, um, my links out too.
DM: Oh, yeah. Just set your links to guard instead of you actually watching so she doesn't see anything.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Maybe.
Wellby: It's awesome.
DM: So close.
Unknown: It does. It's so good.
DM: Keep it in mind for another time, maybe for the Apollyon fight.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Or-
Seeker: The thing is,
Seeker: do one that wander around the ship.
Seeker: The simulacrum can just hang out.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: It doesn't like-
DM: Right. But it doesn't heal, so it...
DM: And it can't really gain spell slots, so you gotta, like, be judicious about when you actually use it.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Yeah, but you could prep- prepare one on the ship and...
DM: Yeah.
DM: Okay, so as you drift off to sleep, um, you all find yourself in a shared dream.
DM: Um, you are,
DM: uh... The first thing you see is something you've seen before.
DM: It's the,
DM: um,
DM: standing on top of a high mountain pass, this massive shadow dragon above you, and then Rai, like, everybody fighting.
DM: I don't remember what everybody was doing.
DM: Bar- Beryl had a quarterstaff, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay.
DM: You know, Beryl's fighting with a quarterstaff.
DM: I, I think Aaron had, like, some weird shadow dagger.
DM: Something like that.
DM: Um,
DM: and then the moment when Shamut dies and there's this, like, silent flash that goes across the world, and then suddenly you're yanked
DM: as Rai teleports to Drankor.
DM: And you see what you haven't seen before, which is that, um,
DM: standing right outside this, there's this elaborate tomb,
DM: a structure, um, in which you gather Apollyon is buried, and there's a dagger flying towards the door.
DM: And Rai
DM: grabs it in his hand moments before it strikes the door
DM: and stands there.
DM: And time flashes forward, and you are
DM: in Rai's mind as he probes these bindings, trying to understand what he's grabbed onto.
DM: And he reaches through the various tangles and twists and knots of Cha'mutte's magic,
DM: of
DM: the essence of the plane of Limbo, the plane of chaos that Cha'mutte was close to,
DM: woven in knots into a net
DM: that hel- that holds
DM: Apollyon in place.
Seeker: This is like one moment that Kong should not be asleep.
DM: Are you good?
Unknown: I'm still awake.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: All right.
DM: Um,
DM: and this net wraps all the way around the tomb, and it's woven tightly, but there are,
DM: uh, still small holes where
DM: something could, could pierce through and could penetrate.
DM: But Rai realizes as long as the dagger is held,
DM: Apollyon has no power to do anything.
DM: And time passes, and Apollyon seems to grow weaker every year in which he cannot
DM: feed on souls, cannot strengthen himself with his dagger.
DM: He must have been-
Kenzo: And Rai's just standing there outside of Holian?
DM: Yeah, so far. He must have been weak to begin with and grows weaker and weaker.
DM: [laughs] I have to look at that later.
DM: Isaac just texted me, "Our session notes are better than yours."
Seeker: Oh, geez.
DM: Um,
DM: grows--
DM: feels him grow weaker and weaker as the,
DM: um, as he grows, the years pass and the connection to
DM: the souls trapped in this dagger grows dimmer and dimmer over decades, until Rai eventually decides
DM: standing here
DM: is maybe not the best place to be, the dagger so close, and of course, he can't move except by teleporting because he's all jade.
DM: He teleports
DM: to
DM: a-- an-- the one area in Dranikor that seems not cursed by
DM: sh- by the pla- by the echoes of the plague and the,
DM: uh,
DM: dark energy of Apollyon and all of the many, many, many people who died here.
DM: It's the grand-- it's a grand, huge domed building, a temple to the eight divines.
DM: Eight sort of alcoves stretching out, um, to create these separate spaces for eight, uh, eight gods to be worshiped around this giant
DM: central dome.
Seeker: It's the same as the pantheon on this side.
Unknown: It's the same as the eight gods.
DM: Uh, it's the same eight gods.
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah. The, the architecture is a little different, and you actually recognize this as where you saw
DM: Kenzo had a dream where the, um, the awakened soul monks found Rai, and this is the building.
DM: And Dimitar is there as well.
DM: Um,
DM: and over the years,
DM: a hundred years pass, and Apollyon seems to grow weaker and weaker, but this
DM: net of chaos,
DM: this
DM: fragment of Limbo that's wrapped around the temple seems to grow stronger and stronger.
DM: And it seems like there's tendrils from it reaching out across the world.
DM: And as Apollyon grows weaker and the chaos of Limbo grows stronger, Rai makes a decision
DM: that perhaps the only way forward-- that if he does nothing,
DM: then this curse that Cha'mutte left behind may grow too strong.
DM: And so he leaves the dagger
DM: in what he thinks is the one place it will be safe under the protection of the divine.
DM: Maybe it's still there, maybe it's not.
DM: And vanishes.
DM: And that's when you wake up.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Hey, Tim.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: I can long rest in four hours, right?
Delwath: So in-- I'm gonna long rest, wake up, cast Aid, and then short rest.
DM: Okay.
DM: Um-
Unknown: So we get the bonus hit points.
Unknown: Which I completely understand.
Unknown: So,
Unknown: Cha'mutte dies.
Unknown: Rai teleports to Dranikor.
Kenzo: There's a dra- there's a dagger flying towards the tomb.
Kenzo: Catches the dagger.
Kenzo: Stands there for like a few decades, and then is like, "What?
Unknown: Is that what he decided to do?" He goes to the temple.
DM: He goes to the temple.
Unknown: To the temple.
DM: Apollyon keeps getting weaker every year that he's disconnected from his phylactery.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So Rai feels that Apollyon has gotten so weak that he doesn't have to stand guard anymore,
DM: goes to the temple
Unknown: Which temple?
DM: The Temple of the Eight Divines in Dranikor.
Unknown: Ah, okay.
DM: Which is the only place that isn't full of the-
Unknown: The red plague
DM: ... plague death.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Waits.
DM: Sh- Apollyon's getting weaker, but this Limbo chaos that Cha'mut has used to
DM: imprison,
DM: the f- the fragments of Limbo that Cha'mut has used to imprison Apollyon are growing stronger, and they're connect- They're like...
DM: There's like a net of Limbo stretching out across the world that Rai is getting worried about.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: And then what he does?
DM: Then he decides he needs...
DM: The vision ends with him, like, putting the dagger in the temple and
DM: deciding to go do something about the
DM: Limbo chaos.
Unknown: Wait, but doesn't... So what does his hand get pulled to bits?
DM: Presumably he fails to do something about the Limbo chaos, and his hand explodes into bits.
Unknown: Yeah, we... No, but we knew that, right?
DM: You knew that, yeah.
Unknown: We saw the b-
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So but he, he's off with the monks trying to get rid of-
Unknown: Right, right, right
Seeker: ... and that's when his hand explodes.
Seeker: So bit, that probably happened in Isengard.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: And he's, throughout this time,
Seeker: he's jade.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah. I mean, he's, we don't know.
Delwath: He could have the whole, his whole body could have exploded, right?
Unknown: We don't know if it was just his hand.
Unknown: Do we?
Seeker: Yeah, where is the rest of him?
Seeker: Must be in Isengard.
Unknown: In Isengard. Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: So we think he's been in Isengard for the past 40 years.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: But the dagger is in this temple in Dranikor.
Unknown: Well, unless it moved.
Unknown: But it's a good starting spot.
DM: It's a good starting spot.
Unknown: Oh, we could help with there.
Seeker: Having seen it.
DM: Could.
Seeker: We could try anyway.
Unknown: Worth a lot.
Unknown: All right, cool.
Seeker: Sort of raises the question, do we...
Unknown: Wait,
Seeker: can we not teleport from here to there because of the-
Unknown: Anti-magic
Unknown: ... anti-magic?
DM: Anti-magic.
Kenzo: We have to get back to the ship.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: I guess we fly there anyways.
Unknown: We'll have the ship with us.
Seeker: We don't, we don't have time, probably.
Wellby: How far is it from here to there?
Unknown: We're, we're close to Dranikor right now, right?
Unknown: Maybe two hours.
Unknown: It'd be a couple hundred miles.
DM: Yeah, you're pretty close to Dranikor.
DM: I mean, this was a-
Seeker: We do want the ship with us.
DM: You're like, um, you're probably no mo- You're definitely no more than 200 miles.
DM: That's 20 hours.
DM: That's less than a day.
Seeker: Also, like, Vindristjarna versus
Seeker: vast domed structure, we could probably take it.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Puncture the dome and shit.
Delwath: I mean, the first thing we're gonna have to do is defeat our own doppelgangers.
Delwath: But wait, they can't level up.
DM: Right.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: It's true. They don't have eighth level slots.
Unknown: Nice.
Seeker: Are there a lot more of those, we think?
Delwath: There's one of each of us.
DM: There's one of each of you.
Unknown: Remember, they all have eighth level-
DM: Oh, but Seeker's the only one who has eighth level slots, so...
Unknown: But none of them have eighth level slots.
Seeker: And, uh, they haven't been destroyed.
Delwath: No, they all died once, and then we start this again.
DM: They all wear some amulet, so when you fight them, you have to take the amulet off them before you kill them, otherwise they just reform again.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Oh, man.
DM: Well, that's for another time.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: So,
DM: uh,
DM: okay, let's see what happens.
DM: Um,
DM: at about...
DM: So what happens if the lynx is triggered?
Unknown: It's alarm spell.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: So it's, it's mental currently.
Unknown: I can choose whether it's noise or mental, but it's mental.
DM: So at about,
DM: um,
DM: maybe
DM: 1:00 in the morning,
DM: um, the alarm spell is trig- You don't, do you know what triggers it?
Unknown: I think so, but I'm not sure.
Unknown: I may, probab- I don't know, maybe not.
Wellby: 1:00 in the morning is a full long rest, right?
DM: Uh-
Unknown: Starting at what?
DM: 5:00 to-
Unknown: Only four hours.
Unknown: 5:00 to 1:00? Yeah, that's...
DM: No, that's not eight hours, is it?
Unknown: Yeah, it is.
Unknown: I don't know.
DM: Oh yeah, it is eight hours. Yeah, that's a full long rest.
DM: Um...
Delwath: It doesn't tell me who's-
DM: It doesn't... So, okay, at about 1:00, you've all completed a long rest, but the spell is not finished,
DM: and
DM: the spell still needs another four hours.
DM: The alarm is triggered.
Unknown: What spell?
DM: Some arc- Oh no, you're not doing some arcane cantrip.
Unknown: We can't do it.
DM: Okay, 1:00 AM.
Unknown: What spell is it?
DM: I forgot. 1:00 AM, the spell, the alarm is triggered.
Seeker: Just at the moment we could have started doing something.
Unknown: Like, we got like eight hours of sleep, right?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: We long rested.
Delwath: But it's probably Tilly and Milo, not, uh, Frank, we hope.
Wellby: Can we see what triggered it?
DM: You can climb out of the tunnel.
Wellby: I climb out of the tunnel very carefully.
Kenzo: Is Dimitar in the tunnel with us this whole time?
DM: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: Huh?
DM: No, he sleeps curled up in the statue.
Wellby: There's a, there's a people out of the tunnel.
DM: Out of the statue, that's right. You can go out into the, um-
Seeker: You can see into the temple at least
DM: ... um, there is a pair of dragonets
DM: that are just kind of sitting in the temple,
DM: kind of curious about just keeping an eye.
Unknown: Wait, Dimitar-
Unknown: It'd be really funny to use the god's voice.
Unknown: Do you know them?
Delwath: I... Does Dimitar know these dragonets?
DM: Nope.
Seeker: Can we hear them if they talk?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Can you Soul Sight them?
Unknown: Sure.
Unknown: That's free, right?
DM: Yeah.
DM: Um-
Seeker: We're keeping very quiet
DM: ... they're, I mean, they're just, they're watchful.
DM: They're sort of bored.
Unknown: What's CR?
DM: Two.
Wellby: Do we just sleep?
Seeker: That's what I'd like to suggest.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Going to sleep.
DM: I think that's like a wisdom save.
Unknown: No save.
DM: No, the spell changed.
Delwath: Oh, come on. The new s- the new sleep spell is the dumbest...
Wellby: What is it?
Delwath: It's literally the worst spell in the world.
DM: Oh, well.
DM: I would assume you'd use the existing sleep or whatever.
DM: I didn't read the new sleep spell.
Unknown: The new sleep spell's stupid.
Delwath: It's like literally an idiotic spell that you would never take.
Seeker: Why does it work?
Delwath: Well, the old sleep spell is super fun because it's all about hit points.
Wellby: Right.
Unknown: It's like designed to knock down.
Delwath: The new sleep spell is just a wisdom save or nothing happens to you.
Unknown: It's-- And even if you make your wisdom save, you don't even fall asleep.
Wellby: Hmm.
Unknown: It-
DM: Well, I mean, it's the same.
DM: I mean, sleep, the sleep spell doesn't last, it doesn't make you fall asleep, but it still only lasts for a minute, the old sleep.
Unknown: It does make you fall asleep.
DM: But you wake up when the spell ends.
Delwath: You wake up when the spell ends, yes.
DM: So it's the sa- it's the same thing.
DM: It's just too safe. It's useful in different contexts.
Delwath: It's a double save.
Delwath: But so what I always liked about the sleep spell is that it, the whole point of the sleep spell is it doesn't require a save.
DM: I, I don't really care which way or the other.
DM: No, I much rather keep the old sleep spell.
DM: I mean, there's no way that a CR two creature is making two wisdom saves against a...
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It has the roughly the same effect.
Delwath: No, but it's much more useful.
Delwath: Like the situation I actually used sleep was to-
DM: Is when you take down enemies right at the very end.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: It was taking on Kagdurs. It was taking on Kagdurs that-
DM: That would be harder to do.
Delwath: That's much harder to deal with.
Unknown: I, I do not like the new sleep spell.
Unknown: I forgot about it.
DM: Yeah, it's not even a... Oh, it's a sorcerer spell.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Well, I have it for free from the Neswat, from the Neswat.
DM: Yeah,
DM: yeah. Uh, they fall asleep for a minute.
DM: [thudding]
Delwath: Well, I... Hold on.
Delwath: We need a plan before we cast sleep.
Wellby: Um,
Wellby: tie them up and release them at dawn to go report back.
Wellby: I think so. Right.
Wellby: So we can fight in the dark.
Delwath: I think we drag them into the tunnels and tie them, yeah.
DM: Okay.
DM: You drag them in, you tie them up and drag them into the tunnels.
Delwath: Ask them and interrogate them a little bit.
Delwath: I'll try and scare them.
DM: Okay. Let's... Hold on one sec.
DM: [paper rustling] I mean,
DM: they're, you know, they're kind of...
Delwath: I just want them to tell me what their orders were.
Delwath: I don't, they don't need to betray the dragon.
Delwath: They don't need to do anything. Just what do you do?
Delwath: Why'd you come here? What are you doing here?
Delwath: We won't kill you. [paper rustling]
DM: Um.
Delwath: But you're not going anyf- anywhere for a while, and you got to spell why you came here.
Unknown: That's it.
DM: Uh, what language are they asking then?
Delwath: They only speak, uh... Oh, I'd probably have to have to cast tongues.
Delwath: Um, they don't speak Common, do they?
DM: They don't speak Common.
Delwath: I can, I, I'll just cast tongues.
Unknown: It's fine.
DM: Okay.
DM: One sec. I'll be right back.
DM: [sighs] [coughs] I mean, they're, they're like a bit freaked.
DM: It's like everybody's up in arms.
DM: All the dragonets have been sent
DM: everywhere across the island.
DM: We're to keep watch
DM: and report back ev- in two hours if anything shows up.
Delwath: And they don't report back.
Delwath: So it's okay. Maybe it's okay if she just comes here in two hours.
Delwath: What are we waiting for?
Wellby: Are there any others posted to this area of the island, like this sector?
Wellby: Where, where are the nearest ones?
Wellby: Can we move to other buildings in this complex?
DM: She was very mad. I don't know.
DM: They're everywhere.
Delwath: Did you fly over here with any, anybody else?
Delwath: You guys come here and split up or just the two of you?
DM: Ten of us.
Delwath: There's probably ten covering the top of the monastery.
Unknown: There's eight temples. Well, great.
Wellby: In two hours, everybody else flies back.
Wellby: We can move to one of the other buildings.
Unknown: Why do we want to move to another building?
Wellby: So she doesn't just come and breathe acid through the roof
Wellby: and kill us while we're all waiting inside.
Unknown: I mean, like
Unknown: these people
Delwath: think we're... We...
Unknown: Yeah, sure.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: I, I will, I will, uh, thank them for their honesty and tell them, um-
Delwath: So are you, uh...
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: I'll ask them if they know either of our two f- Gresh- Gresher.
Delwath: What's her name? M-
DM: Megren?
DM: Yeah.
DM: No.
Delwath: Are you, um,
Delwath: are you one of the true believers?
Delwath: Are you just scared of her?
DM: Who?
DM: Looks kind of confused by the question.
Unknown: True believer.
DM: We all believe she's the queen of the island.
Delwath: When she's dead, are you gonna be happy or sad?
DM: Surprised.
Unknown: [laughs] I mean, as an aside, why don't we just tell these people to tell her we're waiting
Unknown: for her here?
DM: Sure.
Unknown: And then not be here.
Unknown: Wait. Uh,
Kenzo: would we want to fight her, though?
Delwath: Well, somewhere around here, but, but...
Kenzo: What's our plan?
Delwath: Well, we have two hours. We'll make it in a minute.
Delwath: Okay. Um-
Kenzo: And put some music.
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: So I'm gonna, um, I'm gonna tell them we might have more to say in a bit.
Delwath: You know, we'll go away from them.
Unknown: Siri here. Let me know if I can help.
Delwath: Um, I'm gonna
Delwath: reset... I mean, I'll reset the links.
DM: Uh, I don't think your...
DM: Is your thing on?
Kenzo: Uh, Schwartz, want me to pass away? Should be.
Unknown: [gentle music]
DM: There we
DM: go. Reset the links?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And you're going back into the tunnels?
Delwath: I think, well, we're gonna talk for a little bit.
Wellby: Do we have heroic inspiration again after long rest?
Unknown: Yes.
Seeker: Oh, nice.
Delwath: We'll cook... That with a cooked breakfast.
Unknown: And plus 20.
Delwath: Midnight breakfast.
Unknown: Yeah, I... Yes.
Unknown: Midnight breakfast.
Delwath: Yeah. Midnight snack.
Unknown: Nice tasty midnight snack.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: man, that's a good feat. I'm glad I took that feat.
Seeker: Heroic inspiration. Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: We're using it a lot.
Kenzo: Oh, man. It's fucking so useful.
DM: It's huge. I mean, so is alert.
Delwath: Alert is also great.
Unknown: Alert's been incredibly useful.
Delwath: Oh, my God. Yeah, also good. What did you take as your origin feat?
DM: Crafter.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: Which is very Seeker.
Delwath: That'll be good.
DM: He's gonna get a lot of use out of it later.
Delwath: That'll be good when we go and make all the magic items at the forge.
Seeker: Oh, yeah, we can make stuff.
Delwath: Um, so I think the plan is to send these folks back
Delwath: to honestly report that we're here in this place,
Unknown: and then move.
Kenzo: How do we move?
Unknown: We just walk to another building.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: But we should decide where we want to be.
Wellby: I like fighting her from the lighthouse.
Unknown: Highest point on the island.
Delwath: Like go up to the top?
Unknown: We're gonna need the air. Yeah.
Wellby: Maybe there's a way to turn it on.
Seeker: Is that helpful? It's broken.
DM: Oh, it's broken?
Seeker: Yeah, it's cracked.
Delwath: So remind me of the setup at the top of the mountain.
Delwath: There's the eight temples around the central lighthouse.
DM: There's the eight temples around a courtyard, and then there's this, the lighthouse in the middle that has a bell and then a cracked lighthouse mechanism on the top.
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: I mean, maybe... I don't know. Maybe we can put a drift glyphs in there or something.
Wellby: Like it'd be nice not to be in total darkness fighting her,
Kenzo: which may not be- It's 1:00 in the morning right now, right?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: It's like midnight.
Wellby: 3:00 they all report back?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Kind of want to know where Tilly and Milo are.
Kenzo: I'm sure they're doing great.
Delwath: Yeah, but if they're coming here...
Delwath: Well, we'll see what happens, I guess.
DM: So what are you doing at the moment?
DM: Just waiting?
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: I think so.
Seeker: Oh, I should do long rest.
DM: Yeah. Everybody should long rest.
Unknown: Like,
Delwath: I mean, let's, let's, uh, wait two hours
Delwath: and then send these dragons back.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, we could even send them back...
Delwath: They might not pass it along, but we could tell them, you know, tell, uh,
Delwath: tell Ra'ghemdros that, you know, we don't think she's, can hurt us, and we're leaving, you know.
Delwath: We... I don't know, try and piss her off and make her come after us unstrategically.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: something like...
Unknown: Like... Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: I don't know what the message would be.
Unknown: You know, we're, um...
Wellby: We're resting now, but we'll be ready to meet with her at dawn.
Unknown: There you go.
Wellby: If she'd like to come to see us then, this is where we'll be.
Delwath: Yeah. We took, we, we took, we took what we believe is our fa- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: We took our fair payment
Unknown: from her.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: And, uh, we're resting in the Sibyl's temple, which is an, you know, a sacred space, and we expect that she won't violate it,
Delwath: and we'll be prepared to meet her at dawn, uh, outside the temple.
Wellby: She should come to us then.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. She should come meet us at dawn here.
Wellby: And we freed her from the burden of having to, uh-
Delwath: Right. Yeah
Unknown: ... keep her prisoner trapped.
Unknown: We... Right.
Kenzo: And she'll thank us. So much, she has so much gratitude for us.
Delwath: Yeah. We did her a favor.
DM: Okay So you're gonna just wait the two hours and let them go with that message?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, about an hour later, 2:00 in the morning, um, you see
DM: Tilly and Milo walking up the path,
DM: like looking around for you.
DM: You're not... Are you hiding still in the tunnels?
Delwath: Yeah, we're back in the tunnels, right?
Unknown: Okay. Well, so the-
Unknown: Nobody knows. Watching out
DM: ... the links, the links triggers another alarm then.
Delwath: So we'll walk out again.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Yeah.
DM: Dimitaur is, "The..."
DM: Wait.
Unknown: Shh, shh.
DM: She doesn't say anything.
Unknown: [laughs] Shh.
Wellby: Uh, we'll reach out to them telepathically.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: There you go.
Unknown: And say where we are and...
DM: Uh,
DM: I hope you're ready to fight an army.
Unknown: An army?
Wellby: When you say an army...
DM: You can see her up in the sky.
DM: She's flying around with about 15 dragonets and four chimeras.
Seeker: Yeah, we should anticipate that.
Unknown: Oh, that's...
Delwath: Ah, this is when-
Wellby: Nothing that the fireballs can't solve.
Delwath: Wow, but hold on.
Unknown: Uh,
Delwath: we should... It would be...
Delwath: Wait, hold on, hold on. I gotta look at my actual...
Delwath: Um, hold on one second. I just want to look at my w- my messenger one more and see what it actually, the actual name.
Seeker: Just by raw firepower, that's not,
Seeker: not a situation we want to be in, I don't think, is it?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Uh, so when you summon the links, it can...
Delwath: It's an action to summon.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: It can do... It can travel 50 miles an hour for two hours per day.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Right? But going 50 miles an hour to and from the coast-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... is only taking...
Delwath: I can do that five times.
DM: Yep.
Delwath: And I've only done it four times.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: So
Delwath: send a message to Ghesh and...
Delwath: Right? Last ditch, Kenzo, what, what are you gonna say to them to convince them to come help us?
Unknown: Um, tell them that, um...
Kenzo: Oh, well, they, they also don't know that all of us are here, right?
Kenzo: Or they do, they know... Oh, yeah, they know that they're...
Kenzo: I've got, like, magic animals or something.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: Yeah. I'll tell them, um, you know, we conquered the, uh, uh, we conquered the dangers in the west.
Kenzo: We, um,
Kenzo: we freed, um, the, the dragons captive,
Kenzo: uh, that's been held captive for hundreds of years, and now we're gonna kill the dragon.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: we've
Kenzo: killed several of the dragons.
Kenzo: Uh, [laughs] you should have total confidence in our success.
Unknown: No, uh...
Delwath: I think something like, um,
Delwath: you've expressed displeasure about Ra'ghemdros's rule before.
Delwath: She's coming to fight us now with the true believer dragonets, and we're gonna kill her.
Delwath: And any help you could provide
Delwath: will inc- like, I don't know.
Kenzo: No, I think it's also just like, like, look, um,
Kenzo: you don't like the dragon.
Kenzo: We don't like the dragon.
Delwath: N- this is your chance.
Kenzo: We're gonna kill the dragon for sure.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: And, um-
Delwath: But, but we need your help
Kenzo: ... we need your help.
Kenzo: Um, and the... what... all we need you to do is to, uh, just hold off the other, the other-
Delwath: Yeah, just hold off the true believers.
Kenzo: Hold off the true believers. We'll handle the dragon.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: And after, by noon tomorrow, the whole island is gonna be yours.
Delwath: Yeah, we're, yeah, we're gonna give the island to the dragon.
Unknown: The whole-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... uh, the whole island will be the dragonets' free of a dragon
Unknown: by-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... by, by noon tomorrow.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: By later. By... And all you have to do-
Delwath: And we'll give you your first pick of the thing from her, non-magical item from the horde.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: First choice.
Unknown: Yeah. First-
Delwath: Everybody, everybody who fights.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Delwath: Anybody who fights.
Kenzo: Anybody who fights. Well, actually, we'll, we'll say anybody who fights, um, um-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... gets, gets-
Delwath: Well, no. Ghesh and
Delwath: Ma- Magen, Magen?
DM: Megren.
Delwath: Megren get first pick.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But anybody who fights gets something from the horde.
Kenzo: Get something from the horde.
DM: Something shiny from the horde.
Unknown: Something, something good.
Kenzo: Some- something shine, something shiny from the horde.
DM: Really shiny.
Kenzo: Yeah. Really shiny.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: And all they have to do-
Delwath: And spread the word. Any dragonet who fights against-
Unknown: Spread the word. Yes, get something from the horde.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: We'll take the dragons.
Delwath: And any leader, any tower commander who fights can get their first pick of something from the horde,
Delwath: as long as it's not magical.
Wellby: And as long as we all get to pick before them.
Delwath: No.
Unknown: Yeah. What do you mean? We're gonna, we're gonna let them pick non-magical stuff.
Delwath: Who cares?
Wellby: But the throne.
Wellby: I guess we can't take it anyways.
Unknown: Yeah, like, who cares? No.
Unknown: No, but just, just... Well, the...
Kenzo: We'll, we'll promise them some sweet items from the island.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Just, you know.
Delwath: But I think Ghesh and...
Delwath: They deserve first pick.
Unknown: Yeah, that's fine. Yeah.
Unknown: Right? Ghesh and Magen- Magenda.
Unknown: We can give them, we can give them great stuff.
Kenzo: They'll, they'll get some cool stuff.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So I'll send 50 miles an hour.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: So it would... Six miles, right?
Delwath: Or something like that.
DM: It's like...
DM: No, it's like 15 miles from the coast from here.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Um, well, ask Milo how far out-
Delwath: So I probably don't have enough to get a message response.
Delwath: No response.
DM: How far out are the dragons?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I mean,
DM: not so close.
DM: They're in the east now.
DM: She seems to be doing a circle around the entire island.
DM: I think you got two hours, if you're lucky.
Delwath: So when these guys leave, I think, I think the next step, we sent our message to-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... hopefully something comes of it Um,
Unknown: I mean,
Unknown: should we tell these people to spread the word?
Wellby: Which people?
Delwath: The two who were kidnapped.
Seeker: We want them on our side too.
Wellby: They, no, no, they left.
Unknown: They haven't left.
DM: They haven't left.
Delwath: Toil came back first.
Wellby: Oh, wow.
Seeker: And it's like factionally are they loyal to-
Delwath: Who knows? But like can we, should we just tell them?
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: We want them.
Unknown: We want-
Seeker: The most loyal could probably be swayed by enough treasure.
Delwath: Look, we tell them.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: It's easier if Kenzo does it so I don't have to cast another spell, 'cause then I can't speak Draconic.
Delwath: But tell them,
Delwath: give the message to-
Kenzo: Spread the word.
Unknown: Sp-
Kenzo: Spread the word far and wide that the last, the dragon's last night is tonight.
Delwath: And that anybody-
Unknown: That by...
Kenzo: Anybody that participates will get part of that shiny thing from the treasure.
Kenzo: It's your opportunity to be free.
Kenzo: The island will be yours.
Unknown: By, by, by laying low the dragon.
Unknown: And we pull out some examples, like this is the kind of shiny thing you can get.
Delwath: Yeah. But like we have to see them in the sky.
Unknown: We're not messing around. [laughs]
Delwath: We have to see them in the sky in the battle.
Delwath: They can't just like fly.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But they don't have to fight the dragon.
Kenzo: They do not have to fight the dragon.
Delwath: They only have to fight other dragonets.
Wellby: Yep, yep.
Unknown: Right? They can-
Kenzo: But tonight, but tonight is the last night-
Unknown: Right
Kenzo: ... of Raghemldros' rule.
Delwath: Yeah. That's actually, we should put this in the scrolls too.
Delwath: The deal I think we should make with the dragonets is any dragonet who shows up in the battle
Delwath: who fights other dragonets, they can run away as soon as there are no-
Wellby: Yeah
Delwath: ... dragonets still fighting for Raghemda.
Wellby: Good.
Delwath: Right? But they have to show up and fight in the sky.
Unknown: We have to see them.
Wellby: Okay.
Delwath: And if they, they do that, they get something from the hoard.
Kenzo: And they get to be part of this, this future without Raghemldros.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: We'll tell them to. I mean-
Wellby: All right
Unknown: ... be interesting to see how do they react.
DM: Um,
DM: make an insight check. Or Kenzo.
DM: Kenzo's the insider. Or Well- do you have insight, Wellby?
Wellby: Mm-hmm. I have great insight.
DM: Okay. Both of you can make an insight check.
Kenzo: I have extremely good. 20 something, 25 I think.
Wellby: Uh, 23 for me.
DM: Yeah. They're...
Kenzo: 25, I think.
DM: They're, uh, they're definitely curious.
DM: I mean...
Unknown: Just tell your friends
DM: ... they're, they're trying not to let on anything, but they're kind of like, "Um, okay."
DM: So an hour passes.
DM: Two o'clock.
Delwath: I mean, we should climb up to the tower at some point, right?
DM: Um-
Seeker: How, how am I gonna...
Seeker: If I'm gonna fully prep,
Seeker: I will activate the ladder.
Delwath: It, it's hard to know.
Delwath: Those are pretty fast to do, right?
Seeker: The ladder is an action.
DM: The spell's an action. The ladder's an action.
DM: If you want to do a construct on the ladder then.
Seeker: Yeah. But the construct isn't able to fly, does it?
DM: So, right, maybe you pick something else.
Unknown: Yeah. Well.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: I mean, it would be nice if we could...
Delwath: Is there any way we can think of to get...
Delwath: I mean, it's gonna be, in theory, we should be able to see her coming, although not if it's dark.
Wellby: It'll be getting close to dawn though, right?
Wellby: It'll be 5:00 by the time she gets there?
DM: Well, the dragonets are gone at 3:00.
DM: You still got like an hour till like pre-dawn twilight, and two hours till dawn.
Wellby: I think we should go see if we can turn on the...
Delwath: Let's go tinker with the thing.
Wellby: Might as well.
Delwath: I mean, we may as well climb up there, right?
Delwath: Like that, we want that to be our-
Wellby: If nothing else, it would be deeply epic.
Delwath: It would be, to get the lighthouse on.
Seeker: Hell yeah. And what does this even do?
Seeker: Yeah, I should go. I can identify again today.
Kenzo: Yeah, iden- d- Dimitar.
Kenzo: Dimitar's been living here for like 40 years.
Kenzo: How does it work?
DM: I mean,
DM: there used to be
DM: something in the center,
DM: some sort of crystal that generated light, I think.
Unknown: Like you climb up there, you poke around.
DM: I don't-
Delwath: We just try putting a driftglobe in and see what happens
DM: ... flies so well anymore, but there's like a, it's like hollow in the middle.
DM: Some of the crystals are broken.
DM: I think it used to ha- you know, shine precisely.
Seeker: Precisely where?
DM: I don't know.
Delwath: Let's go investigate it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Is it just like eight faceted?
DM: Yeah.
DM: So you climb up.
Unknown: Yeah. Mm-hmm.
DM: And so it's, it's, it's eight faceted, and like Seeker is pretty good at this sort of stuff.
DM: You'd think the way it would've normally worked is like it could have shined along the paths of the pilgrim roads, and it would
DM: splinter the light so it would shine across the, all the pilgrim roads at night so that they would have-
Seeker: To light their way.
DM: Yeah. Right.
Wellby: That's really cool.
DM: But two of the, two of the facets are broken, and there's clearly, like there's clearly supposed to be something big in the middle.
Seeker: So it'd be much more powerful in a dr- driftglobe.
Unknown: But...
DM: Well, maybe not in daylight.
DM: Definitely way more powerful than a lantern.
Delwath: But daylight lasts for an hour.
Wellby: Lasts for an hour, and we have two driftglobes.
Wellby: We can do two dope.
Delwath: But, but before we do any, like can Seeker futz about and see if you, see if it would even...
Delwath: Before we trigger daylight, just use the regular light and it, does it, does it, is it weak, right?
Unknown: Does it do anything?
Unknown: Oh, let's-
Wellby: I think we don't want to turn it on because as soon as we turn it on-
Seeker: We telegraph our position a little bit.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Oh, that's true. Well-
Seeker: But didn't we tell them where to meet us anyway?
Unknown: True.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Why do-
Wellby: Can you figure out... So it, it shines in these like spotlights, but will it give ambient light around the top of the tower?
DM: I mean, the, the, the way that-
Unknown: That's a good question
DM: ... the way that you imagine it-
Seeker: We could set it up a different way than it was before
DM: ... well, the way you imagine it would've worked is the whole top of the mountain would be glowing with light.
Unknown: And the beams would come down. Cut
DM: And then there would be beams coming down.
DM: Now, it's cracked.
DM: Two of the panels are broken entirely and definitely could not be repaired, and a third panel is like shifted out of place and is misaligned.
Delwath: I mean, if we could just get enough light to give us...
Delwath: I mean, the ideal goal here is really to get enough light to- We'd love to have three rounds notice before she's close enough to do anything, 'cause then you could cast your stuff.
Delwath: Like there's a bunch of stuff you can do to prep.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: Cast Fly, cast-
Seeker: Oh, so the light might actually help see her-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... from longer range.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: I can also start shooting at 270 feet now.
Seeker: Oh, that's nice. Wow.
Wellby: Which is a long way.
Unknown: That is.
Seeker: So can I use Mending on the broken part?
Unknown: Um,
DM: so you could... Mending?
DM: Yes. The ones that are like shattered, there's too much-
Unknown: Mm
Unknown: ... material missing.
DM: But the one that's just like cracked out of place you could fix with Mending, yeah.
Seeker: And then I suppose I could Performance of Creation like
Seeker: missing crystal chunks.
Unknown: Yeah. Why not?
Seeker: That would ruin my Performance of Creation.
Seeker: I don't usually need that for anything else w- when I'm animating the ladder.
DM: And you can do two things, right?
Unknown: So two, two chunks.
Unknown: Two chunks.
Seeker: It's probably worth doing.
Delwath: I mean, you took the craft feat.
Delwath: You may as well craft something.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. All right.
Unknown: You paid 60 gold. [laughs]
Unknown: I will set about fully repairing.
Unknown: Hell yeah.
Unknown: I like it.
DM: Let's go.
Unknown: Awesome.
Delwath: And yeah, we have daylight to power it, right?
DM: It takes some tinkering to get it w- it's probably gonna take you about half an hour to get it working.
Seeker: Oh, and then this, the repaired piece only lasts for five hours.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: That's okay
Unknown: It's not a permanent repair, but yeah.
Unknown: Five hours.
Wellby: You'll need it during that very fight.
Unknown: One way or other, this'll be over in five hours.
Unknown: That's true.
Unknown: Probably.
Delwath: Or it'll also be dawn and then we won't need it. [laughs]
Unknown: Or it'll be dawn.
Unknown: It'll be light out.
DM: It's gonna be dawn in two hours.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Uh, you probably have... Now with Seeker's tinker, you probably have half an hour before like the expectation of when she'd arrive.
DM: But I was like,
DM: "So what's the plan?
DM: I mean, I know we're not big on plans, right?
Unknown: But..."
Delwath: Okay. Can you fly?
DM: He takes out a potion.
DM: I mean, yeah.
Delwath: How long does it last?
Unknown: An hour.
Delwath: Good enough. Uh, and can Tilly fly?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: But
DM: he looks at Delwath.
DM: Do you have a bow?
Unknown: No.
DM: I'm not one to, you know,
DM: hide from a fight,
DM: but maybe it would make more sense for me to shoot arrows from cover.
Unknown: Sure.
Unknown: If you want to fly.
Unknown: Oh, hey.
Wellby: You have an extra bow, shortbow.
Unknown: I'll, I'll take that trade.
Unknown: You have a, you have a bow.
Unknown: No, he has a bow.
DM: Is it a good bow?
Wellby: Uh, it's a sh- sh- you know.
DM: But not magic.
Wellby: Uh, I have arrows I can give you.
DM: I, I'd take some arrows.
Unknown: I mean, uh, yeah.
Delwath: I think th- I think that's a good trade.
Wellby: Oh, shoot. Yes. I know what I'm gonna do.
Wellby: I'm gonna give him 20 of the honed accurate scare arrows so he also does not have disadvantage at long range.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Anyone want ice cream?
Delwath: Yeah. I'll get some ice cream.
Delwath: I'll come serve myself in a minute. Oh, potion of heroism.
Unknown: What's that?
Delwath: I have a potion of heroism.
Delwath: It blasts. It's 1D4 to every attack roll.
DM: Tilly says...
Delwath: Who's that gonna be most useful for?
Unknown: I mean, I've...
DM: When the dragon comes-
Unknown: I like Kenzo
DM: ... how much warning do we think we'll have?
DM: 'Cause I can summon my own draconic spirit to fight it.
Delwath: Uh, we think...
Delwath: Well, look, so-
Seeker: Who's saying that?
Unknown: Tilly
Unknown: Tilly.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: if, uh, if our friend Seeker here can repair this light which we're working on, and he's quite, I'm quite confident in his abilities.
Delwath: We're almost there.
Delwath: We're hoping to shine a light.
Delwath: We expect it will be, I mean, what?
Delwath: It's gonna be at least 1,000 feet, right?
Unknown: We should have at least-
DM: Well, the ra- I mean, so the minimum range daylight is what?
DM: 60 feet?
Unknown: I think something like that.
DM: So your minimum is 60 feet, which wouldn't do you much good.
Delwath: No, it does no good at all.
DM: I hope that you'll be able to increase that by a fair bit.
DM: 300, 1,000.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: You don't know quite how much.
Wellby: 300, the dragon can probably-
Delwath: Uh, it's 120. Daylight's 120.
Wellby: Right.
Delwath: It's 60 foot bright, 60 foot dim.
Wellby: Dim. Dragon can probably move 120 per round.
Delwath: Yeah. And it's gonna have breath and things.
Delwath: We need, we need, we need five...
Delwath: To have a round, we need to see it at 500 feet I think would be my guess.
Delwath: If we can see it at 500 feet we can get spells off before it can close to us.
Delwath: That would be the ideal. That's our goal is I mean a thou- Like that would be my guess, right?
Wellby: If I was the dragon, I would also send in my minions first to soften us up and then
Wellby: come in myself second.
Wellby: Although the dragon may not do that.
Delwath: Um, okay. This is-
Unknown: W- we're, we're-
DM: ... not anywhere close to enough space so each square is gonna be 10 feet.
Delwath: Use the little mini... Um, uh, let's see.
Unknown: Do you want the ice cream out or put it away?
Unknown: Uh, put it a- put it away.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Um, don't they, there are no little mini squares on there too?
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah. So each mini square.
Unknown: It's hard to use our figures on the mini squares.
DM: Let's just say each, each square is...
DM: I mean, you're all gonna be flying anyway, so it's gonna be tough to track.
Delwath: That's true.
Unknown: Um...
Kenzo: The stack dice is nice, but each one represents 10, 10 feet.
Unknown: Who...
Delwath: Kenzo, do you have any useful potions?
Unknown: Potion?
Delwath: I'm thinking... So I have a potion of heroism which lets you add a 1D4 to your attack to your D20 rolls.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: I'm thinking Kenzo might be the best to...
Delwath: 'Cause you make the most attacks.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Make a lot of attacks.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So it gives you the most-
Wellby: That's good
Delwath: ... it's like, 'cause each attack you get an extra 1D4 to hit, so like it gives you the most.
Unknown: Oh, extra 1D4 to hit?
Delwath: Yeah. It's to your D20 checks.
Unknown: Oh, sick.
Delwath: Any D20 check. Not damage, but...
Unknown: For every D20 check?
Delwath: Yeah. You get, you add a 1D4.
Kenzo: That's pretty awesome.
Kenzo: Yeah. I would like that.
Delwath: And you also get 10 temporary hit points.
Wellby: I have a potion of Haste.
Unknown: You have a potion of Haste?
Unknown: Oh, fuck.
Wellby: Which feels like it could be a good thing, 'cause I could do two...
Wellby: Basically two sneak attacks per round,
Wellby: and I could start shooting-
Unknown: Teleport scroll
Wellby: ... like the chimeras.
Unknown: So-
Unknown: What's the Haste do again?
Unknown: Use that and grapple.
Wellby: An extra action.
Seeker: Well, we would've had to had the idea before.
Delwath: The four.
DM: Well, I gave you a free potion of Flying to make up for it, so.
Unknown: Yeah, I know.
Unknown: Oh, yeah, Haste would be awesome.
DM: But also, Milo and Tilly only level 10, so they're a little bit nervous of the breath weapon, which could one-hit them.
Unknown: They're level 10?
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: What class are they, druid and-
DM: Druid and rogue.
Wellby: Oh, sweet.
DM: This is the basic arrangement.
DM: These are the eight temples.
Delwath: But, but we're gonna be a...
Delwath: So I think our goal here is to-
DM: [laughs] This is gonna be a complicated fight.
Unknown: It's gonna be super complicated.
Kenzo: Oh, wait, I have a potion of Growth.
Delwath: I don't know if that helps that much. What does it do?
Wellby: Add one?
DM: It adds 1d4 to your... It makes you large, and it adds 1d4 to every damage.
Wellby: Oh.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: That's-
Kenzo: I mean, giant Kenzo is pretty...
Kenzo: That'd be pretty fun.
Kenzo: Giant flying Kenzo.
Delwath: What else do we have?
Delwath: Advantage on strength checks, enlarged weapons are on strength, meh.
Delwath: What does Haste do? It lets you make-
Wellby: +2 to AC, advantage on dex, and an additional attack action-
Unknown: While in Haste
Wellby: ... or death doesn't get you out of it.
Delwath: Um, do we have any other potions?
Kenzo: I have a bunch of healing potions.
Delwath: I have a bunch of healing potions too, and a potion of Heroism.
Kenzo: What does that do?
Delwath: That's the one that would give you 1d4.
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: I mean, what the fuck? I'll do the potion of Growth.
DM: Use it.
Delwath: I mean, you could just...
Delwath: Yeah, like why not?
Unknown: Well...
DM: Um, Tilly is gonna say
DM: she could also give you a few ex-...
DM: Oh, wait. You already have a-
Unknown: Yep
DM: ... you can't
Delwath: Ah, but, um, Seeker, the...
Delwath: She should cast Aid on,
Delwath: she should cast Aid on Wellby, herself, and Milo.
DM: Oh, yeah, okay. So Wellby, you get 15 extra hit points from Tilly.
Kenzo: Yeah, I get an extra 1, 1d4 extra damage.
Kenzo: Yeah, for sure. I'll be enlarged.
Delwath: You take the potion of Heroism too.
Kenzo: Wow. All right.
Wellby: 15 temporary hit points?
Unknown: No.
DM: No, 15... It's like a-
Delwath: Increase your hit point maximum by 15
DM: ... hit point maximum increased by 15.
Kenzo: Who said that that bonus 20 from you, uh, Wellby was?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: You don't have anything good?
Seeker: I don't have much that I can pull out for this fight.
Seeker: There's the scrolls.
Seeker: Teleport, Resurrection. Private sanctum.
Unknown: Oh, wrong.
Unknown: It's just not-
DM: Yeah, but it's not-
Unknown: For this situation
DM: ... yeah, yeah, yeah. No potions?
Delwath: Clairvoyance. I used the Watchful Rest.
DM: You should take that.
Kenzo: Oh, how do I do copy Kenzo again, Tim?
Unknown: Oh, we were gonna do that-
DM: Oh, right
Unknown: ... anyway.
DM: Of course.
Kenzo: Um, I, I opened... I, I restarted my computer.
DM: Oh, it's this one. Sorry, it's that one right there.
Seeker: And the Summon Construct is only useful if it can fly, and it's concentration.
Unknown: Ah, nice, nice, nice.
Unknown: Um.
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: It's not gonna be able to do anything.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah. If it can't fly, it's not gonna be useful.
DM: Wait, it's medium, right?
DM: The golem is medium.
DM: Yeah.
DM: It can ride the, it can ride the ladder.
Seeker: And if I, if I flavor the ladder-
DM: With air, it gets a 40 foot fly speed.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: All right. All right. Yeah, actually-
Delwath: I mean, Quagga will ride the ladder.
Delwath: What, what, what do you want?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: I mean, does Seeker really wanna ride the ladder into combat?
Seeker: Oh, but then I'll have no way to fly.
DM: You won't be able to fly.
Unknown: But that's okay, you hide.
DM: You hide on the ground with Milo.
Delwath: Our, our plan is to have a hiding group, which is Milo and you.
DM: All right.
Delwath: And Wellby, actually.
DM: Well, Wellby can fly as necessary.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah. And an attacking group,
Unknown: which is me and Kenzo.
Unknown: That's it?
Unknown: And what about the ladder?
DM: The dragon.
Unknown: And-
DM: And the dragon that Tilly summons-
Unknown: The, the dragon spirit-
DM: And the ladder
Delwath: ... and the ladder with the Quagga riding on top of the ladder.
Kenzo: Okay. Quagga on the ladder, we need them.
Unknown: Yeah, we definitely-
DM: Quagga on ladder, Tilly's dragon spirit-
Unknown: All right
DM: ... Kenzo as Dalith-
Unknown: Um-
DM: ... is the attack group.
Wellby: We got an army too.
DM: [laughs] Yeah, well, you're gonna need it.
Unknown: Holy shit.
Seeker: It's about to get crazy.
DM: So-
Kenzo: And w- wait, and Dimitar
DM: ...
DM: Dimitar is in the hide group.
Unknown: Hey, Mike.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Wand of Fireball and Mass Charge.
Unknown: I'm looking at the-
Wellby: What?
Seeker: There's a different construct st- approach, the stone one.
Wellby: Does either one of you have Divination?
Unknown: Tilly made a big difference in the last fight.
Wellby: Do any of us have Divination?
Seeker: But speed halved would make a huge difference-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
Kenzo: ... for the dragon.
Unknown: Yes.
Seeker: But it has to start its turn.
Wellby: This would be useful to know.
Unknown: No.
Wellby: Is the dragon gonna be in the first wave of the attack?
Unknown: When Tilly summons the spirit.
DM: Tilly starts the turn with 10 speed.
Seeker: So it's pretty unlikely that it would, but it could happen.
Unknown: Oh, we can ask Augur.
DM: Wow.
DM: Augur is just like, "Is this a good idea?"
Unknown: If the ladder managed to fly up right up to the dragon.
Delwath: I mean, but the ladder's gonna grab...
Delwath: No, the ladder flies up and grapples the dragon.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: Hanging on for dear life while the golem pounds it with his fists.
Seeker: Yeah.
Delwath: And does that.
DM: I mean, the dragon is 30 feet from, and has, like, a 60 foot wingspan.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: The golem could just drop, jump on its back.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Right. All right.
Delwath: Wait, is it huge?
Seeker: But, Tim, I was just thinking about using-
Unknown: Or gargantuan
Seeker: ... gargantuan. I was thinking about using this, the stony golem.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: The stone golem, 'cause that can still stay down.
DM: Oh, it can slow it. Yeah, yeah.
DM: I mean, you can also try Slow.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Do either of you have Divination?
Wellby: 'Cause it would be useful to know if the dragon will be in the first wave of the attack.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: We do have a magic item, but it's a one use.
Wellby: I don't know if you want to use it.
Kenzo: Feels like a pretty good time though.
Kenzo: Although, first wave, I mean,
Unknown: why not?
Unknown: Does that really affect-
Delwath: Oh, that lasts 10 minutes.
Delwath: The Font of Moonlight lasts 10 minutes.
Unknown: That's the-
DM: Yeah, that's the idea. You can cast it 'cause it's an action, so you're supposed to is, for a moon druid, you change and you bonus action-
Delwath: Change and cast it
DM: ... change and cast it, like, when you're about to open the door.
Delwath: Yeah. But that means if we get any kind of...
Delwath: If we have any...
DM: That also sheds light.
Delwath: It sheds light in 20, in 40 feet.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: But the cool thing is if I take damage, it's a, I can blind creatures.
DM: Right.
Delwath: Although it uses my reaction, which is massively over subscribed as it begins with.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Yeah. You might wanna save your reaction to not die.
Seeker: I guess I need to-
DM: It's probably more valuable for shield than for-
Seeker: ... get a new napkin for my now dirty napkin
Delwath: Well, not if the dragon is fleeing breath weapons.
DM: If the dragon is running. [laughs]
Delwath: Like, if I get hit with a breath weapon-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... it's any damage.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Oh, oh, okay.
Delwath: It's not a melee attack.
DM: Right. Right, right.
Delwath: Immediately after you take damage from a creature.
DM: Um,
DM: Tilly will also hand out two goodberries to everybody.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: And say, "If anybody drops, feed them a berry."
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: Yep.
Delwath: Wait, didn't we say Kenzo? Kenzo has goodberries now too.
Delwath: I think I have goodberries.
DM: Oh, you can do that too.
Kenzo: But the goodberries are only, like, one hit point.
Unknown: Yeah, but it'll bring you back-
DM: Yeah, but if you're at zero, it brings you up
Delwath: ... if you're at zero it brings you up to one.
DM: So it's a good way to not die.
Seeker: That sometimes matters.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, let's see.
DM: I don't think Tilly's got any other prep, unless you want to hide.
DM: She can cast Pass Without a Trace, but your strategy is the exact opposite of hide.
DM: You're trying to get as much bright light as possible.
Delwath: I mean, Tilly and Milo
Delwath: should look for... Wait, is Dimitar gonna come fight with us or is he gonna give-
Wellby: He's in the hide group
Delwath: ... the wand of fireballs to somebody?
DM: No, no, he's in the hide group.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: He's gonna shoot the wand of fireballs.
Unknown: And then run. Yeah, fine.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: How many people can be in your telepathy at once?
DM: I think it's... Is it eight or six?
DM: Eric?
Seeker: Uh, the Telepathy 3 is...
Unknown: Sorry, I was doing hit points.
DM: No, no, that's okay.
Seeker: Is, uh...
Seeker: I thought it was eight, but let me check.
DM: Teleport is eight. I can't remember.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Uh, eight.
DM: Okay. So you can get Dimitar, Milo, Tilly, and the four of you.
Unknown: Yep.
Wellby: Perfect.
Delwath: Okay. So the potion of fly's an hour?
DM: It's an hour.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: So the real thing, I think...
Delwath: Is there any reason not to just-
Wellby: Light the light and get going
Delwath: ... light the light and get going?
Wellby: What are we waiting for?
Wellby: Once everyone's in position, once they've got in good hide spots.
DM: Yeah. So Dimitar, I don't, we don't need, don't have good tokens for all these people, but that's okay.
DM: 'Cause,
DM: okay, Dimitar,
DM: Dimitar is gonna... Dimitar is staying in his Temple of the Civil.
DM: Um, he's actually gonna be on the roof of the Temple of the Civil.
Delwath: I'm just thinking the more warning we have before they appear, the better off we are.
DM: Are you using divination?
Kenzo: Oh, we can start using long range weapons and shooting at stuff.
Delwath: And casting... Like, I have
Delwath: two spells that I could,
Delwath: two prep spells that I could cast.
Delwath: One to give me bonus insights-
DM: [coughs]
Delwath: ... and one to,
Delwath: uh, give me extra damage.
DM: Right.
Delwath: And, like, you have all these potions, but they only last an hour.
Delwath: It's hard to know when to drink yet.
DM: Yeah. Right.
DM: So we should do a-
Delwath: How long does the potion of growth last?
Delwath: Is it an hour or 10 minutes?
Kenzo: Um, is...
Kenzo: It's, it's, it's a bunch of hours.
Seeker: I'll do the construct at sixth level,
Seeker: which gives it AC-
Unknown: 1d4 hours. No concentration required.
Delwath: 1d4? That's unusual.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Oh, yeah. [laughs] That's kind of random.
Kenzo: Eh, I mean, whatever.
DM: Okay. Here's Tilly the panoramic spirit-
Unknown: I'll just be huge for a while
DM: ...
DM: when it gets summoned.
Kenzo: Oh, 10 more temporary hit points. That's nice.
DM: Um-
Unknown: A bless spell
DM: ... nobody needs d4s, so I'll just use these d4s as Milo and Tilly.
DM: They're gonna be in... Milo's gonna be
DM: hiding. Where's, where's Wellby gonna be?
Wellby: Middle.
Delwath: Like on the top of the thing?
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: So Well- Milo's got the arrows now, so I think he's gonna just...
DM: I mean, he does... The more spread out everybody can be, the better off you are.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: So he's gonna hide in the doorway.
Wellby: He should be on whatever side is...
Wellby: No, it doesn't matter. Yeah, cool.
DM: And Tilly is gonna be here.
Kenzo: Don't we have, like, little, little, little fucking dudes miniature ones?
DM: Yeah. If anybody can find little dudes.
Unknown: Where the, where the little...
DM: I mean, I'm gonna have to use dice for the-
Seeker: I'm sure this isn't it but we'll-
DM: ... the 50 million. Some of this is gonna have to be a bit theater of the mind, 'cause we're not gonna actually be able to track every single minion.
Wellby: No, you've, you've got a ton of little minions in there.
Unknown: There's a lot, there's a lot of creatures.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: You've got six fiery dwarves and six something else's.
DM: Okay. Yeah.
DM: Can somebody just throw some, put some of these onto stands?
DM: I don't need a dragon.
Wellby: You don't need a dragon?
DM: Nope.
Kenzo: We had, we found a really good one. We found a, we had a, we had a black, giant black dragon.
DM: Yeah. Where did that go?
Wellby: It's right here.
Kenzo: Uh, this can, this can be, uh, one of the-
Wellby: Here's a... This is not quite a Dimitar, but that could be a Dimitar.
Wellby: It's got wings anyway.
Unknown: This is, uh... What, what are these guys?
Unknown: These two travelers right here? What are these?
DM: I don't know. We don't have any gargantuan beasts.
Delwath: Tilly and-
Wellby: That's, yeah, Milo and Tilly
DM: I need like a base that's like...
Wellby: I have a bunch of little bases, like a bunch of little one slot bases.
Unknown: These, this kind or this kind?
Wellby: Uh, the flat kind.
DM: This is not big enough for us.
Unknown: Yeah. This one doesn't seem to be compatible with the- Yeah, there's two different types.
DM: The, the, the wiggly ones use the one slot base, and the hard plastic ones use the three slot base.
Unknown: These, these. Oh.
DM: Okay. So are you gonna turn on the daylight?
Unknown: Oh, there we go. Or are you gonna use divination, or are you gonna...
Wellby: I don't think we need the divination.
Wellby: Too much can change with the divination answer.
Delwath: I, I think we turn on the daylight as soon as we can,
Delwath: right? Like what are we waiting for? Are we waiting for anything?
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Do it last maybe.
DM: Eric, roll a D20.
Seeker: Ooh, that's an 11.
DM: Okay. Um.
Kenzo: Oh, you have, you have all the Yeah ...
Delwath: sets. Take what you need. Well, I just, I don't know if there's anything good, but keep, keep talking.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: so...
Wellby: I have more little big space space blockers.
Unknown: Where should Seeker be? Mm.
Seeker: We're gonna spread out basically.
Delwath: Yeah, we wanna be as spread out as we can, for sure.
Seeker: Right. Well, I'll start over here.
Seeker: But I think ladder construct team should start up high somewhere.
Delwath: Okay. Yeah, I mean, as soon as we have, um, indication that they're coming, we can start...
Delwath: We need... Like ideally we have like two or three rounds where we can start to position ourselves and cast spells and things.
Delwath: But it's gonna be hard to know exactly how many rounds we have.
DM: Uh, you got it. Yeah, you gotta just turn on the light.
Delwath: Well, no, I mean the point is we're gonna, we're turning on the light as soon as we can.
DM: Okay. You can turn it on now.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah. That's what we did. I thought that's why you had Eric roll a D20.
DM: Yeah, it is. But I didn't know if you were ready to do it.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Light shines out,
DM: illuminating the entire temple complex in this brilliant daylight and stretching about 600 feet in every direction.
Wellby: Awesome.
Delwath: Uh. That's kind of... That could be a- Wow, that's pretty solid ...
Delwath: it's not ideal, but do we have a, do we have a Tilly?
Delwath: Wait, what is Tilly, a druid? She's a druid.
Kenzo: Uh, I made... This is a, this is for a, one of the Tilly or, or-
Wellby: That's a Milo
Kenzo: ... Milo.
Delwath: I mean, this is not really great, but if-
Kenzo: What's that one?
Seeker: It's, that could be Tilly. Ladder construct team.
Wellby: Tim, how many chimeras are there?
DM: Uh, Milo said there were four.
DM: That was an hour ago.
Unknown: This is great.
Delwath: So do we see anything within 600 feet?
Unknown: Nope.
Seeker: There's nothing stone golemy is there, or stone constructy?
Seeker: Mm. Give me more stats.
Delwath: What about that?
Seeker: Oh wow, that's awesome.
Unknown: Uh.
Wellby: Can I have bases for these, Mike, for, for this?
Delwath: Uh, is it this size or is it this size?
Wellby: I don't think it matters 'cause I, I think smaller because of the map scale is different.
Seeker: So that's too big to be the stone construct, but it's stone at least.
Delwath: Oh, it's one square. It's fine.
Wellby: Cool. I took three more of that kind of base when you have a chance.
Seeker: Ladder will just be a die, I guess.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Oh, that's a gray clay golem. Or is that a stone golem?
Seeker: Yeah. We're doing stone this time.
Kenzo: Dude, that's perfect.
Unknown: So...
Wellby: Oops. Actually, Mike, I need the other kind of base.
Unknown: This kind?
Wellby: The squiggle. Yeah.
Wellby: Uh, two more after this.
DM: Okay. So just before the combat starts, um,
DM: Milo and Tilly want a quick ch- you know, chat.
DM: Like what's our plan here?
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: This is a scroll I think.
Delwath: So when you hit dragons hard enough, long enough, they fall dead.
Seeker: [laughs] It takes some persistence, doesn't it?
DM: [laughs] Tell me something I don't know.
Kenzo: Stay away from their breath weapon.
Unknown: Uh...
Delwath: I think-
Kenzo: Try not to be scared.
Unknown: Uh...
Delwath: I mean, do we have a plan? We should probably...
Delwath: We gotta take out the dragon.
Wellby: [laughs] Yes.
Delwath: Yes. Gonna have a swarm of other things.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: This is what I'm wondering, should we
DM: divide and conquer? If we get swarmed by dragonettes, it's not gonna go well.
Delwath: We're hoping
Delwath: that we have,
Delwath: we're hoping that we have, um, some dragonette help,
Delwath: but it's not clear.
Delwath: I think... So Kenzo I think should just, you just punch the dragon.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Kenzo's job is dragon puncher.
Unknown: Right?
Delwath: Like nothing but dragon punching.
Delwath: Try and stun it, whatever.
Delwath: Saltite it and then whatever.
Delwath: But you get five attacks, you're enlarged.
Kenzo: And I'm blessed.
Delwath: And you're blessed.
Delwath: You might want to get his claw.
Unknown: Oh yeah.
Delwath: 'Cause then you'd be D10- So that means you do- ...
DM: plus D6 plus D4 ... 1D6 plus 1D10 plus 1D4 with every attack.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Well, and, and I, and I roll a D24.
Unknown: Or a D20 plus D4.
Delwath: And you roll 1D24.
DM: D20... Yeah. Right.
Kenzo: For every, every attack roll.
Seeker: Yeah. And the ladder will just be there.
Delwath: And I think the ladder should back up Kenzo.
Delwath: Yeah. Delweth is either gonna dragon or if...
Delwath: I think we need multi firepower on the dragon.
Kenzo: I think so too. I, I think maybe me and you on the dragon and everybody else take out everybody else that's around.
DM: I mean, Mavi's pretty good at taking out minions 'cause he can shoot through three of them or four of them at once.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: I think that's what, um, what I and Milo should do.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: 'Cause we both have sneak attacks.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: But-
Delwath: Do a bunch of damage
Unknown: ... but
Delwath: dragons have crap dex saves generally
Wellby: Uh, did we see what its immunities were though?
Delwath: Oh wait, we already told you.
Unknown: We already told them.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Immune to acid and necrotic.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Immune to charm, frightened, para...
DM: But it has, it has true sight, so blind is not gonna affect it whatsoever.
Unknown: Ah.
Wellby: And it's immune to poison?
DM: It's immune to poison, stunned, petrified, paralyzed, frightened, and charmed.
Wellby: I can't do anything to it then.
Seeker: What if you hit it in its sunset scar?
DM: That might piss it off.
Kenzo: Hitting it in its... I think aiming for the sunset scar is the way.
Delwath: I mean, I think we also want to try to...
Unknown: That is totally the way.
Delwath: Wait, dragons have like a fright aura too, don't they?
Unknown: Yep.
Kenzo: And that's why you gotta stay within 30 feet of me.
Seeker: So I have this sunset thread.
Kenzo: That's why you and I gotta stay close and-
Delwath: Yeah, I mean, that's gonna-
Unknown: ... go melee
Delwath: ... a breath weapon. That's gonna make us...
Delwath: But what can we do?
Kenzo: We'll fly around.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Try to dodge it.
Delwath: I mean, we can try and be 30 feet... Ideally, we're 30 feet on either side.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Right? Ideally, we come at it like this.
Delwath: And we're da, da, da, and it's in between us, so it can't hit us both.
DM: So the... Kenzo's thing is e- he's immune to fear, but everybody within 30 feet-
Delwath: 30 feet has advantage
Unknown: ... everyone has advantage.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And you have cleansing touch if...
DM: If necessary.
Seeker: Tim, the, the sunset thread said it was spun by the Cloud Weaver.
Unknown: Should that be-
DM: That should be the Cloudspinner, yeah.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: I mean, she goes by many names.
Seeker: I wonder if like...
Delwath: That's a blinding one, but extra 2d6 damage
Unknown: ... make that into
DM: Now, the chimeras are probably not immune to any conditions.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Taking those out would be useful. Focus on those.
Wellby: I, that's what I'm thinking too.
Unknown: Yeah. Focus on those.
Unknown: Are you guys?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah, okay. So the, the flying strike team goes at the dragon.
Delwath: Everybody else keeps anything from...
Delwath: Kills everything else.
Unknown: And then what should I-
Kenzo: Focus on the chimeras first 'cause they're gonna be the...
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: What should I be doing from the ground?
Delwath: Do you have any area effect damage spells?
Unknown: Probably not.
Delwath: I mean, that's the one thing I was thinking is Synaptic Static is pretty good at clearing the field with...
Delwath: But it's better... I'm gonna be better off with Frank.
DM: I mean, something like Rune of Psychic Disruption against chimera is not gonna do much to the dragon, but against chimeras it's quite strong.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Right? Like...
Seeker: And that's 120 foot range.
Seeker: I could always... I have a couple of charges for boosting range.
Unknown: And you...
DM: If they fail the save, you take them out for a whole round.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: But, but can you... Are you, uh...
Kenzo: Can... It's 20 feet?
Unknown: It's 120.
Unknown: 120.
Unknown: 120 feet. Then I see-
DM: And you can make it 240 or
DM: optionally-
Seeker: Flavor it
DM: ... fla- no, go for double that to 4...
Delwath: To 500, 480.
Unknown: 480.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: But then you gotta make your check.
DM: You might fail.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: All right. That sounds great.
Seeker: It'd be nice to be able to hit one of those chimeras far, far away actually.
Unknown: That's interesting.
Wellby: We should get at least two rounds of arrow attacks on it.
Delwath: Don't... What's your ra- I thought your range was 270.
Wellby: 270.
DM: Depends on how fast they fly.
Delwath: I don't think we'll get two rounds.
Wellby: I think they have a flight speed more than 60.
Unknown: Might be 90.
Seeker: I love that we lit up the ball field.
Seeker: We're like playing night baseball.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: It's great.
Unknown: It's epic.
Wellby: Could be even one round would make a difference.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay, um, I'm almost ready.
DM: I just have to have like 12 tabs open, so give me one sec.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Tim, I have four chimera tokens and 13 minion tokens.
DM: Awesome.
DM: That should be about right.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: let me
Unknown: just use that. [sighs] I wonder if...
Unknown: Absorb Elements.
Delwath: Oh, Absorb Elements.
DM: That could be useful. Tilly also has that.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So...
Unknown: That's my breath weapon save.
Unknown: Uh, okay. Okay.
Delwath: Man, my reaction is so oversubscribed.
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: [laughs] Too many things to re- that you can do?
Delwath: Yeah, 'cause I... Absorb Elements gives me resistance to acid damage.
Unknown: What?
Delwath: Just against the triggering attack.
Delwath: I mean, it's until my n- it's just like I use it as a reaction when I get hit with the breath weapon.
Kenzo: I mean, that's useful.
Delwath: It's super useful.
Kenzo: Wait, hold on, hold on. Let's think for one second here.
Kenzo: Just in terms of rings. You got the acid resist...
Kenzo: Like, I feel like I should have that.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Right?
Unknown: You should take that.
Unknown: You know what I mean?
Delwath: Can, can we swap that?
DM: You can swap that.
Kenzo: Yeah. This in the prep.
Delwath: You have to give up something.
Delwath: What are you giving up? Your...
DM: Oh, but it's tough. He can't-
Unknown: Don't give up the cloak
Delwath: ... he can't take-
Unknown: Oh, no. You can't.
DM: He can't give up the cloak. He can't give up the tattoo, and he can't give up the staff.
Kenzo: No, I can give up the tattoo.
DM: No, don't you want to use the tattoo?
Kenzo: I mean, Langau's, you know...
Kenzo: I mean, honestly, right?
Kenzo: For, for fucking 50% damage on acid.
Wellby: Do you have a slot?
Seeker: There's gonna be some acid.
DM: Honestly, you're almost better off giving up the staff.
DM: I mean, you can still fight with it.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: You just can't use the heal staff.
Kenzo: Oh my God. Totally give up the staff.
Kenzo: That's crazy, but yeah.
Unknown: Oh, you, you just can't talk to me.
Delwath: But you're not even gonna fight with it if you have Langau's Claw.
Unknown: You're just-
Kenzo: No, I'm, I'm, I'm totally-
Unknown: You're going staff, right?
Kenzo: That's unbelievable.
Kenzo: Yeah. I, I'm going giant Kenzo feral throwing fucking massive like jaguar punches.
Unknown: I mean, I could-
Kenzo: Holy shit
Delwath: ... trade out Almarka's thing.
Delwath: But the plus one to its spell DCs is actually pretty useful.
Kenzo: I, I think this is the way.
Delwath: And resistance doesn't stack with resistance, right?
Unknown: Yeah, it doesn't.
Delwath: So I can, I can absorb...
Delwath: There's actually no point in me taking it 'cause I'll just ca- I mean, yeah, it means I could use my reaction.
DM: Yeah, we don't have an item for it, but just remember you're resistant to...
Kenzo: Holy shit. That's so crazy.
Kenzo: 'Cause it's like, yeah, I'm gonna have this ultra magic b- powerful staff I'm not gonna use.
Unknown: Tim.
Seeker: I'm gonna...
Seeker: I, I could reattune the binding stones, but they're still...
Seeker: I'm like looking at it. I'm like,
Seeker: is there anything in that that I could use actually?
Kenzo: Can you, can you do the if we're getting really fucked, just like roll a bunch of dice and then see if you can find the dragon?
DM: The thing is, if you're casting the, if you're casting the construct at sixth level, that's your concentration, right?
Seeker: So-
Seeker: Right. So that's-
DM: Watery Sphere could be useful
Unknown: ... but then the concentration
DM: Like, you could trap a bunch of mini- minions in that or a chimera, but it's concentration.
Delwath: The construct's pretty powerful
DM: I think a sixth level construct-
Delwath: We still have the
DM: ... a sixth level construct makes three attacks, right?
Seeker: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: So
Delwath: I, I would focus on the c- I'd construct and then support spells or psychic disruption thingy.
DM: All right.
Delwath: Right? I mean, do you have any, like, good...
Delwath: I mean, you can always Healing Word us.
Unknown: Like, you know, you have...
Seeker: There's not much else. I can't do Telekinesis, Wall of Stone.
Delwath: Oh, 'cause everything else is concentration.
DM: How many hit points does the construct have?
Unknown: Uh, 70.
DM: Okay.
DM: That's a lot. I mean, that's a-
Delwath: That's the Erupting Earth
DM: ... bunch of tanky stuff
Delwath: Wait, does Erupting Earth pull it to, pull something to the ground?
DM: Well, the problem is it has to be close to the ground to begin with.
Delwath: It has to be close to the ground. What about your Grasping Hand?
Unknown: That doesn't pull stuff to the ground either, does it?
DM: No, we swapped that out for Telekinesis anyway.
Unknown: Okay. Yeah.
DM: And Telekinesis is quite good at that sort of stuff.
Unknown: But it's a construct
Unknown: But it's concentration.
Delwath: It's a construct. I mean, you've got us those catapults too.
Seeker: That's 60 feet, so I feel like this is gonna be a,
Seeker: these are large playing fields.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But you can, remember, you can double it.
Unknown: You can double it.
DM: The nice thing about catapults-
Seeker: But I used the three charges to get the-
DM: Oh, so you only have two doubles
Unknown: ... air attack on the ladder.
DM: So you only have two things you can double.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But catapult, the nice thing about catapult is if it misses the first target, the next thing in the line still has to make the save.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay, so
DM: about 15 minutes later,
DM: you see coming into the edge of the light a wave of four chimeras and
DM: 13 dragonets flying behind them in like a formation
DM: flying towards you.
Seeker: That's at 600 feet?
DM: That's at 600 feet.
DM: They're moving 108, uh, 120 feet a round.
Unknown: 'Cause they're dashing and-
DM: 'Cause they're dashing
Unknown: ... yeah, I get it.
DM: 60 feet flying.
Delwath: I mean, we're all at the top of the tower right now, right, I assume?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Well, I didn't put Delwath on.
DM: No, well, the fly team is, but-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... but Tilly-
Unknown: No, no, no, sorry. When I said-
DM: Tilly summons her dragon
Delwath: When I said I'm gonna drink the potion of flying and cast, um, the radiant spell.
Unknown: Where did the Del- what Delwath do?
Unknown: Well, where's the dragon?
Kenzo: The dragon's not here.
DM: The dragon's not here.
DM: You don't see it yet.
DM: Dragon's coming from the direction
Delwath: But my spell lasts 10 minutes.
Kenzo: Should I eat the potions?
Delwath: You should eat the potions.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: They both last more than an hour.
Kenzo: Yeah. All right, I'll eat the potions.
Kenzo: Holy fuck.
Unknown: This is gonna be bad.
DM: Um, this dragon is also gonna be in, on the fly team, Tilly's dragon spirit.
Kenzo: Oh, this is not a... You're, where the fuck is the dragon then?
DM: Oh, it hasn't shown up yet.
Kenzo: I know, but the b- I thought this was, this was a-
DM: No, no, that's, that's Tilly's dragon.
Delwath: That's our good guy dragon.
DM: What?
Kenzo: There's a bigger dragon? Where's the big dragon?
Unknown: I wanna see the big dragon.
DM: I thought, I thought this was the-
Delwath: So wait, I have fly.
Delwath: Let's just fly for an hour
DM: ... the big dragon.
Delwath: Normal fly spell, but it lasts an hour.
DM: Uh, it's your speed.
Unknown: Oh, not-
DM: Is the only downside
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... but it's not concentration.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. So it's only f- ooh, 30 foot.
Delwath: That's a, that's rough.
Delwath: I'm gonna have a hard time keeping up with the dragon is the only problem with that.
DM: Do you have any way to boost your speed?
Delwath: Anybody have any way to boost my speed?
Wellby: I'm about to drink a potion of haste [laughs].
Delwath: How much, what does it do for it doubles your speed?
DM: Well, wait, do the boots of speed require attunement?
Wellby: Boots of speed do require attunement.
DM: Do you have an attunement slot you can swap that?
Delwath: I'd have to give up my
Delwath: rod.
DM: Right.
Delwath: I can't really give up my shield or my sword.
DM: Yeah, yeah. That one, yeah.
Delwath: I could give up my rod.
Delwath: It, it's not that useful actual- I mean, it's good, but, like,
Delwath: but I mean, I could just drink the potion of haste.
Unknown: You want it?
Wellby: I think so because it lets me do two sneak attacks a turn.
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: It doubles my damage output.
Delwath: Yeah. I mean, it's-
DM: It increases your damage by 25%
DM: ... 25% and yours by 100%.
DM: And you get high acc.
Delwath: No, no, it's more useful for, 'cause I already get three attacks.
Delwath: A fourth attack isn't...
Delwath: I could, I mean, the problem is with, I didn't realize the fly was not 60 foot.
DM: But is it, I mean, would you prefer 60 foot of concentration?
Unknown: No, not at all.
DM: All right.
Delwath: It's way better. No, no, no, but I think we were just playing for this is what I'm saying.
DM: Yeah, yeah. No, you're right. I'm, I'm happy to let you swap out the, for the boots.
Delwath: And what does it give my movement to?
Wellby: Doubles it.
Unknown: 60.
DM: So it would be a, it would be a 60 foot.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: It would be the same as the fly speed, but no concentration.
Delwath: I just think the dragon's gonna move either 60 or 90.
Delwath: I'm gonna really struggle to keep up with it-
Wellby: Agreed
Unknown: ... without
Delwath: that. I think, I think it's bet- I, honestly, I'm not gonna be casting a lot of spells
Delwath: on it. I mean, I lose the ability to get back a slot with an action, but-
Wellby: So you're gonna take the boots
Unknown: ... but I think I'm gonna take boots.
Kenzo: I've got, I've got 60.
DM: I think the, isn't the whistle double your speed?
Wellby: It is double your speed, yeah.
Unknown: Oh, great, so I got 130.
DM: So you've got 130 foot [laughs] speed.
Kenzo: Well, and also, wait, since I'm enlarged, does that do anything?
DM: That does.
Wellby: That's an interesting
DM: ... your speed.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
DM: The one thing about the whistle is if you take damage, you have to make a save, and you fall if you fail the save.
Unknown: That's fine.
DM: But it doesn't matter if you fall.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But you only have three charges, so if you fall three times, then you're out.
Unknown: That's fine.
Seeker: So the ladder team is only gonna have move 40.
Seeker: Is it just gonna be, is it gonna be able to engage at all?
DM: Ladder team needs to get on the dragon's back.
Delwath: Ladder team's gonna grapple the dragon and get on its back.
Seeker: All right, we just have to get there somehow.
Unknown: All right.
Delwath: I mean, I think it's gonna come at us.
Delwath: It's gonna try and kill us.
Unknown: Fair.
Seeker: Right [laughs].
Seeker: But it has ranged attacks, huh?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: 100 up to
Delwath: But its bigger attacks are its wings, its claws, and its bite, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I mean, Kenzo can also try and grapple it.
DM: Oh, no, Ken- oh, wait. No, you're, you're enlarged Kenzo.
Unknown: Okay, it can't work.
DM: You can only grapple things-
Unknown: No, but even enlarged, it doesn't matter
DM: ... no, it's gargantuan. Yeah
Unknown: ... it's large versus gargantuan.
DM: Can't grapple. Actually, the ladder can't grapple it.
DM: It's too big to grapple.
Delwath: But I was thinking the ladder's not gonna grapple it.
Delwath: The ladder's gonna wrap itself-
Delwath: The ladder can hang on to it
Delwath: ... the wrapple, the ladder wants to wrap itself around the dragon to provide an attack platform for
Delwath: the golem.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Right.
Delwath: Right? So that it can't... The whole idea of the ladder grappling would be that the dragon can't shake the golem.
DM: There's a big difference bet- yeah, so it's not grappling.
DM: It's holding on.
Unknown: Yes, yes. Yes, exactly [laughs].
Kenzo: What size are we right now?
Seeker: Kind of grappling yourself
Delwath: You're large. The rest of us will be-
Kenzo: I will be large.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I haven't drank the potion yet.
Delwath: No, no, no, no. You drank the po- well s-
Kenzo: Well, I, I wanna... Uh, for dramatic effect, I'm gonna drink the potion in a second 'cause I'm gonna double in size.
Unknown: I c-
Unknown: It's gonna be epic
Unknown: I get
Wellby: I have an open attunement slot. Is there anything that would be useful for me to attune to?
Kenzo: You have an open attunement slot?
Unknown: Oh my goodness.
Delwath: Well, 'cause he gave me the boots of speed.
Kenzo: I gave up my 1 for something.
Unknown: You should attune to something. Yeah.
Seeker: If I extend an unlock?
Unknown: No.
Kenzo: Let's see. Cloak of the Manor.
Unknown: I don't know.
Unknown: That's not so useful.
Unknown: Uh, let's see.
Delwath: You could attune to the dagger of blind sense.
Unknown: I don't know how useful that is.
Wellby: Let's look at that. It's only 30 feet.
Unknown: 30 feet. That's not that useful.
Kenzo: Ring of jumping? I have a ring of jumping, a ring of, uh, fire resistance.
Seeker: Imagine jumping from the tower onto the back of the dragon.
DM: The jump lets you jump 30 feet.
DM: That's not terrible.
DM: Fire resistance probably isn't gonna be that useful.
Kenzo: Well, the ring of jumping?
Unknown: Although-
Wellby: I can fly.
Unknown: Yeah, you can fly
DM: ... chimeras might have fire breath.
Unknown: I'd say get a ring of fire protection.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: All right. Fire resistance boom.
Unknown: Yours.
Kenzo: You have one too, right?
DM: You're, he's fire and acid.
Unknown: What? I thought I had-
Unknown: No, I mean you're fire and-
Kenzo: I'm, I'm acid. No, I just-
Unknown: And fire.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: You can attune to both.
Unknown: You attune to both.
DM: Attune to both.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Or you can pick, um-
Unknown: Cold
DM: ... cold. But fire is probably more useful.
Unknown: That's... Yeah, yeah. Okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: I got fire and acid.
Kenzo: You got fire.
Unknown: Guys, we're ready.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: We're gonna, we're gonna do great.
Kenzo: Kenzo, uh, like-
Delwath: You should hand out a hero- a bardic inspiration.
DM: Mm.
DM: Yeah, 'cause you might be out of range.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: 'Cause you're probably gonna be out of range.
Seeker: Out of range. So we'll give them to...
Delwath: You... I would just... I mean, you may as well j- I would give out one to everybody.
Unknown: I have, I have five.
Delwath: I mean, you could just hand out all five.
Delwath: It's just who to give them to.
Kenzo: But if you do them at, as reactions, does it have to be within your range?
Delwath: He is, has to be within, what? 60 feet.
DM: Every-
Unknown: 60
DM: ... he always has to be within 60 feet.
Kenzo: Can you give more than one to one person?
Unknown: No.
Kenzo: Ah. Oh, then just do fucking three, one to each of us, and then one to maybe the two halflings?
Kenzo: Or one to the-
Delwath: Or one to the wa- the ladder bardic inspiration.
Delwath: Or the golem.
Kenzo: Yeah, that would be very useful actually.
Unknown: Um.
DM: Yeah, you can give it one. They're creatures.
Delwath: You can give them inspiration.
Kenzo: Yeah. I think that feels right 'cause-
Seeker: Try the...
Delwath: I mean, you could give one to Tilly, who's more likely to use it 'cause they're dragon.
Unknown: Well, or-
DM: I mean, m- probab- like, just tactically, Milo is a one hit.
Delwath: Oh yeah, give one to Milo.
DM: Right. So having the ability to-
Delwath: Milo, either the golem or the ladder.
DM: Although actually, no
DM: ... and then the peach
DM: ... Milo says he doesn't need it.
Unknown: He's gonna have steady-
DM: He's pretty lucky by himself
Unknown: ... uh, hands.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: So I'll give one to the
Seeker: stone construct.
DM: But I mean, Tilly would take it.
Unknown: Yeah, give one to Tilly.
Delwath: And give one to Tilly.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: That's all, all of them.
Kenzo: Kenzo, uh, like knocks back this like really gross looking potion and drinks it, and as he's like drinking it, like starts getting bigger and bigger and bigger.
Kenzo: And now he's like 12 feet tall
Kenzo: and double in size.
Delwath: Delweth also starts to glow.
Kenzo: And, and staring down at you all.
Delwath: As, as the... As soon as the chimeras are like...
Unknown: Right
Delwath: ... as soon as we see the chimeras in the distance, Delweth-
DM: Okay. So let's, let's just...
DM: So you know how many shots you can take off of them, can we just go into initiative right now?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: While you do your actions.
Unknown: We're just describing.
Delwath: I mean, we could roll initiative, and then these can be our first turn.
DM: Yeah, exactly.
Seeker: 17.
Unknown: 20.
Unknown: 21.
Wellby: 26.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: Okay. 20 Delweth.
DM: What was... 26.
Unknown: 26.
Wellby: You want me to roll for Milo or Tilly?
DM: Uh, yeah. Give me-
Kenzo: Oh, wait, no. I get to roll extra D4s to both of these.
Delwath: You do. Not to both.
DM: No, no. Just to one.
Unknown: Just the one?
Delwath: But blessed applies to all D20 checks, right?
Kenzo: All D20, yes. Yes.
Delwath: Yeah, it's only attack rolls?
DM: It's just attack rolls.
Unknown: Oh, attack rolls.
Kenzo: No, no. It's anything with a D20.
Delwath: No, no, no, no, no. What does blessed do?
Unknown: I forget.
Kenzo: It's attack rolls at saving-
Unknown: Oh, attack rolls or saving throws
Unknown: ... and saves.
Delwath: That is not initiative.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Milo. Roll a D20 for Milo.
DM: He's plus eight.
Wellby: Uh, I rolled a four. That's 12 total.
DM: Okay, 12 for Milo.
DM: Uh, Tilly's only plus four.
Unknown: 10.
DM: I rolled a one.
Unknown: I rolled-
DM: For Tilly. Oh.
Delwath: I, I was rolling for Tilly.
DM: Well, the one rerolls to a two.
Unknown: So 14 total or 6 total?
DM: That's great. You got it.
Unknown: 14 or 10?
Delwath: 14.
DM: Okay. 14 for Tilly.
DM: Sorry, what was Seeker? 17?
Seeker: 17.
DM: And what was Kenzo?
Unknown: 21.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Okay, so let me just get all the...
DM: Let me just get everybody on here so I have everything.
DM: Mike, do you wanna run-
Delwath: It's so complicated
DM: ... Tilly and I'll run Milo?
Delwath: Yeah, I'll run Tilly. Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You run the construct.
DM: Yeah. So, so Milo...
DM: Here, let me... I can se- I actually have characters
Wellby: There's twice, twice as much of you to run.
Unknown: [laughs] Right.
Wellby: Or, or actually eight times as much of you to run, right?
DM: The, uh... Can you ac- I just texted you.
Unknown: That's Milo.
Seeker: Even though we're all running extra characters, Kenzo still has more attacks than anyone.
DM: [laughs] Yes.
Seeker: Although actually I'm gonna have-
Unknown: I can't... I-
DM: You know
Delwath: ... I, I... My computer's not on my-
Unknown: Five total.
Unknown: Yeah, I have five.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: It's-
DM: I don't know if I can-
Seeker: Just 'cause of the con- construct has three. It's great
DM: ... can I email it to you?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Um.
Delwath: Or I can just look at... Oh, I don't have access to this page.
DM: Oh. Uh.
DM: I don't know how to do that.
Delwath: Just on the My Characters, you can change...
Delwath: Click the Edit.
DM: Char- oh, character settings?
Unknown: D6, D4.
Delwath: Yeah, if you click Edit, and then there should be a privacy somewhere.
Kenzo: D6, D4, D10 plus 5.
Unknown: Wow.
Delwath: Um, if you scroll all the way down to Character Privacy at the bottom.
DM: Oh, yeah. Okay.
Unknown: And you can change it to public.
DM: Oh, I had it campaign only, but I didn't change it.
Delwath: They're not in the campaign.
DM: Yeah. Oh, I... Let me just put it on the campaign.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: It'll make it so much easier.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, and I get 10, 10 extra hit points too.
Unknown: That's nice.
Delwath: Yeah, you have 10, 10 hit points.
Unknown: Cool.
Delwath: Oh, and you got eight. You got eight from Tilly, right?
DM: Yep, I got my 15.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: Wow. [sighs] Okay.
Unknown: That's exciting.
Delwath: All right. So Eric's running three characters.
Seeker: Yeah, that's fine.
Delwath: I'm running two. Schwartz is running two.
Unknown: You're just running Kenzo.
Kenzo: Time attack. Double attack.
Unknown: You still have more attacks than anybody else.
Unknown: Imagine if we had a Delweth prime.
Unknown: I know. That would've been good.
Unknown: Another time.
Unknown: Another time
DM: Okay. I think I just successfully-
Delwath: I mean, you put it in the campaign-
DM: Oh
Unknown: ... I should just be able to
Seeker: Somebody's gotta do Dimitar also.
Delwath: Uh, Tim will run Dimitar too.
DM: I'm running Dimitar, yeah.
DM: Are they... Did I get them in the campaign successfully?
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Okay. So Milo only has his, um, has his rapier, but it's gonna be the same.
Delwath: Wait, did Tilly cast Aid?
DM: T- Tilly cast Aid.
Delwath: On herself as well as-
DM: Yeah. It's, it's on there already. It should be.
Unknown: Oh, wow. Okay.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Oh, I...
Unknown: Huh,
Unknown: can I actually tick things off?
DM: Here, here. Hold on. They're now...
DM: I'm, I'm unassigning them.
Delwath: I can't, I can't, I can't.
DM: Yeah, you can. Go, go claim the character.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I have to go into my campaigns.
DM: Schwartz, I unassigned Milo so you can claim Milo.
Wellby: Do I need to claim Milo? I can just open Milo.
Delwath: Yeah. But you can't-
DM: You can't tick off hit points
Delwath: ... you can't tick off hit points or anything-
Wellby: Ooh
Delwath: ... unless you claim.
Wellby: Uh, okay. Okay.
DM: Do you have enough slots to claim him?
Wellby: Uh.
DM: It's okay if you don't. I can tick off hit points.
DM: You just run him and I'll keep track of his damage.
Wellby: Yeah. Good. Good, good.
Unknown: Yeah. Okay.
DM: But you got Tilly.
Unknown: And I'm set.
DM: Okay. Tilly's more important 'cause Tilly has to kee- you might have to keep track of spell slots.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um-
Delwath: Wait, what is the draconic thing?
DM: It's the Summon Draconic Spirit.
Unknown: Fifth level?
DM: Yeah. I, it's fifth level.
Delwath: Ah, okay.
DM: It just... It's like a stat block like Eric's stuff.
Unknown: Yeah, okay.
DM: But it's just the default. Is it fifth level?
Seeker: I recommend if you wanna look at that draconic spirit thing, just open it in a new tab.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Seeker: Because it's so annoying to, like, go to a tab-
DM: Okay. Sorry. I was trying to get, um-
Seeker: ... then see it on D&D Beyond, scroll down to the thing, open the thing-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Seeker: ... and then scroll down to the other thing-
Unknown: How do you open a new tab?
Seeker: ... to find out anything. Oh, you'll just have to find another version of that somewhere.
Delwath: Oh, I just have to open the spell in another tab.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I see.
DM: Um-
Seeker: And presume it's gonna be the same information.
DM: Okay. So that's-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... that's 21 for dragonets.
Delwath: Okay. And I need...
Unknown: And I'm just gonna use notepad for...
DM: Okay. Do you wanna swap anything around
DM: for initiative?
Kenzo: Ooh, good question. Um...
Delwath: Oh, can cast a wrath weapon.
Kenzo: Yeah. 'Cause right now it's, uh...
Kenzo: I mean, I think this is good, right?
Kenzo: 'Cause we want you first. You know me second is still good.
Delwath: Wait, which kind of dragon is it-
DM: Uh
Unknown: ... that she summoned?
Delwath: Chromatic or gem?
DM: I don't know. I didn't read the spell.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Heck.
Unknown: Uh,
Delwath: I want the one that's resistant to acid.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Okay. It can be resistant to acid, but deal cold...
Delwath: This thing's not d- The black dragon is not cold, right?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: You can do resistant to acid and cold.
Delwath: So it's a, it's a chromatic.
DM: Okay.
DM: Cool. Um,
DM: uh, okay. Did I... I got dragon one, two, three.
Kenzo: Wow. This is, this is the craziest battle we've ever had.
DM: Oh, I didn't roll initiative for Dimitar.
DM: Dimitar-
Delwath: Oh, Tilly has resistance to acid too.
Unknown: That's nice.
DM: With those bard elements.
Unknown: Not-
DM: Oh, from her sea prim.
Unknown: From-
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: No, from Draconic Spirit.
DM: Oh, okay.
Unknown: When you cast-
DM: But she also has a s- the sea animation, which lets her, gives her a fly speed, but is she...
DM: It's-
Unknown: Oh my God
DM: ... you go to... Here, I'll send it.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: She's very complicated.
Wellby: [laughs]
Wellby: Now I know.
Seeker: To get through the first round.
DM: No, no, no. Once it starts, it's gonna be fast.
Seeker: 'Cause we're all gonna be immediately plastered with acid, you know?
DM: Oh, I don't know.
Unknown: I don't think so.
DM: The effects of this don't really matter.
DM: She just has a fly speed.
Delwath: Ah, okay. But, but the draconic spirit lets you gain the-
DM: The resistance
Delwath: ... resistance of one of its types.
DM: Yeah.
DM: Yeah. She has a 60 foot fly speed.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um, okay. I've got everybody.
DM: Okay. So you see Wellby is the first one who spots, um, the dragons coming in.
DM: I mean, the chimeras and the dragonets coming in, currently 600 feet away.
DM: I don't think you can hit them at that range.
Wellby: No.
DM: Okay. Um, Kenzo drinks his potion.
Kenzo: I drink both my potion potions.
DM: You can only do one a turn.
Delwath: Oh, okay. No. Can you, uh, can you bonus action one and regular action one?
DM: Well, you can only drink one potion a turn.
Unknown: Ah, okay.
DM: I don't care whether you do it-
Unknown: Whatever
Kenzo: ... bonus or regular.
Kenzo: Fine. Enlarge. Yep.
DM: Kenzo enlarges. Delwath casts his first spell.
Delwath: Yeah. And drinks the fly potion.
DM: Okay.
DM: Seeker casts...
Seeker: Well, at this range...
DM: It's 600 feet. You probably can't do anything.
Unknown: No.
DM: Um, Tilly-
Delwath: Wait. Huh.
Unknown: I actually can do something, but I don't know if I want to.
DM: Um,
DM: Tilly and Milo aren't gonna do anything but send the flying, spread the flyers out in a row to meet...
DM: I mean, you guys can all move to get the first move.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: they move 120 feet closer, so they're now 480 feet away.
DM: Um, still just waiting, aeronaut ready to shoot.
DM: Anybody else doing anything while they're 480 feet away?
Delwath: So hold on. Uh-
Wellby: Waiting to 90.
Delwath: W- I'm, we're flying.
Delwath: So I think Kenza, you and I should probably fly away, like, so that we're not...
Delwath: I dunno, we wanna stay 30 feet away.
Delwath: We should s- we should parallel track 30 feet.
Unknown: Yes. Yes. Yes. Yeah, we are always parallel tracking.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Right.
Kenzo: Can chimeras... Well, I guess we'll learn about chimeras in a second, but-
Wellby: Uh, I wanna move to a position where I can hit them at the absolute edge of my range in the next round.
Wellby: So-
Delwath: Are there any... There's no ally dragonets showing up, are there?
DM: Nope.
Unknown: Okay. So-
Wellby: How many feet away are they right now?
DM: Right now they're 480.
Unknown: So-
Wellby: They're gonna move 120 closer?
DM: Yep.
Wellby: 360.
DM: So they'll be 360.
Wellby: So I'll move
Wellby: 90 feet towards them.
DM: Okay. Wait, you got...
DM: Oh, right. 'Cause bonus action dash, right?
Seeker: So at this range I could hit with a rune of psychic disruption if I use both charges.
Delwath: I wouldn't use both your charges.
Seeker: I was just thinking about it. Am I gonna really do it twice though at 240?
DM: You're- Remember these are only 10 feet so it's only...
DM: So 120 is only 12 squares.
DM: It's entirely possible that there could be quite a lot of the battle happening more than 120 feet from you.
Seeker: All right. All right. So-
DM: Yeah. But it's up to you. Totally up to you.
Delwath: I would... You're b- you're much better off doing two, using it twice with two charges to get two-
Unknown: All right
Unknown: ... two spells.
Unknown: All right. That's-
DM: So wait, how many squares is it from the center there to
DM: the edge?
Unknown: One, two, three, four, five, six.
Unknown: 12.
DM: So that's 120. So they're now 240 feet off the edge.
DM: So like right here.
Delwath: Wait, 'cause are we flying? Are we gonna...
Delwath: Are we waiting or flying towards them?
Kenzo: Great question. Um-
Delwath: I mean, we're probably better waiting, right?
Kenzo: I, I think so.
Delwath: 'Cause over, all of our-
Kenzo: All the air, all the-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... the support air power is over-
Delwath: We wanna stay around the top.
Unknown: We do. We do.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: We wanna, we wanna stay so they can k- they get shot at with missiles.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: I mean, they're coming to us right now.
DM: Do you have a-
Unknown: This is-
DM: Um,
DM: they, so this-
Wellby: No, no, no. Never mind, I got it.
DM: Yeah, we'll stay here.
Kenzo: Yeah, we totally wanna stay here. We, we wanna keep them all within range of like fire- fireballs, like all of our rifle weapons.
DM: Yeah, so the start of the third round, they're 240 feet away.
DM: They've moved to... Oh, no.
DM: The start of the-
Unknown: Second round
DM: ... well, the only one that really matters is when the round that they start 240 feet away-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... right? 'Cause that's Welby's range.
DM: Right.
DM: So we'll just skip to the round where they start 240 feet away.
Delwath: Yeah. It only matters with the number of prep-
DM: With the number of preps that you got
Kenzo: ... mm-hmm. And I've drank two potions.
DM: You've drunk both your potions.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So they're 240 feet here.
Unknown: All right.
DM: Four chimeras, 13 dragonets in a row.
Unknown: Hold.
DM: Hold.
Unknown: Every- There's like, [whooshing].
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: You can see the dragon heads starting to sort of puff up-
Unknown: Hold on. I gotta look at Tilly's-
DM: ... into chimeras.
Wellby: So I'm gonna bonus action-
Delwath: So she only has a fourth-
Unknown: ... drink a potion of haste
Unknown: ... check dot too?
DM: She cast aid at fourth level.
Unknown: Ah, okay. Aid.
Seeker: And they're, the chimeras are-
Delwath: Does haste only last a minute?
DM: Yep.
Unknown: Lion-
Seeker: Okay. So you don't have to
Seeker: ... goat and dragon.
DM: Okay. So-
Wellby: Okay. So bonus action, drink potion of haste.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: And she gets aid so that's good.
Wellby: Take steady aim and shoot one.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: And then when it's turn, I'm gonna make my next-
Unknown: Do we have chimeras?
Wellby: ... action contingent on-
DM: Uh, yeah. Where were the chimeras?
Unknown: Oh, here are four. They're not-
DM: I mean, four creatures
Wellby: ... well, they're different creatures, so.
DM: Yeah. So they're-
Kenzo: And Kenzo and, uh-
DM: They're here
Unknown: ... who's all the
Wellby: And the-
Seeker: Those are kind of hard to blind, but they each have 50 hide.
DM: Uh, yeah. They might be difficult to blind 'cause they have three heads.
Wellby: I'm just gonna dump damage on these guys instead.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: The dragonets are like a little bit behind.
DM: The chimeras are like in a,
DM: uh, in a row.
Wellby: So for that second action, Tim, like to say my-
Kenzo: This is Welby. All right. This is, uh-
Wellby: ... I'm gonna shoot the same creature when it comes turn-
Wellby: ... this is Delweth
Wellby: ... is that the way that works? So like-
DM: No, it's you'd say like when it moves 10 feet closer to me.
Wellby: Awesome. Yeah.
DM: Or something like that.
Wellby: Cool, cool, cool.
DM: Which will be on its turn, right?
Wellby: Awesome. All right.
DM: So you're aiming for, let's say, this chimera here.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: They're 240 feet away now.
DM: Welby's turn, this is the beginning of-
Wellby: Well, 270 from me, 240 from the edge of the map.
DM: Right. It's the beginning of this round.
Delwath: There's a, Delweth and Tilly both have 300 foot spells, so don't skip us in the initiative.
DM: I'm not going to.
Seeker: Oh, 300.
Wellby: That is, uh, 23.
DM: So this is, this is round four, but you drank the haste potion the last round, right?
Wellby: No, I drank it in round four.
DM: In round four. Okay.
Delwath: As a bonus action.
DM: So round 14 it ends.
DM: I don't think we'll get to round 14.
Delwath: Wait, they're, they're-
DM: I'm gonna keep hit points for all these
Delwath: ... they're 240 feet from the edge?
Unknown: They're 240 feet from the edge of the map.
Delwath: Okay. So 270, 10, 20, 30.
Delwath: Okay, so you'd have to be here
Delwath: to ice storm. Tilly's still way too far away.
DM: I mean, she can move closer in the previous rounds.
Delwath: Actually, she's gonna move over to this.
Delwath: Can she move over, she could be on this roof?
DM: Yeah. She can fly.
DM: She has a 60 foot fly speed.
Unknown: Ah, okay.
DM: One, two. This is all on one, both hits on one chimera.
Wellby: Yep. So the first is 41.
DM: Its AC is 15, by the way.
Wellby: Awesome. So the first is 41 damage.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Is it bloodied?
DM: Uh, nope.
Wellby: All right. The second with advantage because of haste.
Unknown: Yes.
Seeker: We're gonna need to scatter.
DM: Are we?
Wellby: Actually, tell me when it's time to shoot the second one.
Unknown: Or it would help to get the golem onto the dragon-
DM: Uh, yep, I will
Seeker: ... which would half its speed.
Wellby: Oh.
Kenzo: Once, once the dragon shows up.
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah. Once the dragon shows up.
Delwath: The golem just has to stay. So Kenzo-
Unknown: That's awesome. That's awesome
Delwath: ... Kenzo, Delweth, and the golem have to stick within 30 feet of each other.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: 'Cause then I can scatter.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: I can scatter, I mean, I could scatter me and the golem to be right next...
Unknown: And Kenzo.
Unknown: Yes.
Seeker: We all clap today. We could put the golem in the dragon's face.
Delwath: To be right in the dragon's face.
DM: So, s- uh, sorry.
DM: So Welby went.
Unknown: Like well positioned right now.
DM: Sorry, how much damage did you do?
DM: The first arrow of the battle was 41, I think you said.
Wellby: Yes. Yeah.
DM: 41 damage at this chimera here.
Unknown: First blood.
DM: First blood. The arrow strikes and it seems totally somewhat unbothered as they keep just beating their wings, flying in rage towards you.
DM: Uh, after Welby is Kenzo.
DM: You're just waiting till they're cl- till they're 90.
Kenzo: I'm waiting till they're 90 to soul seven, yeah.
DM: Okay. Um, dragonets are flying with them.
DM: Delweth is up.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: I'm gonna save my spell slots.
DM: Okay. Seeker Tilly's up.
Delwath: Tilly is gonna fly 30 feet this way and cast ice storm.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Uh, at fourth, is it a f-
DM: It's a fourth level.
Unknown: It's a fourth level.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Is it this round?
Wellby: They are presently 270 feet, uh, excuse me, 240 feet-
DM: 40 feet from the edge
Wellby: ... from the edge of the map.
Delwath: It's a, ice storm is a 20 foot
Delwath: cylinder.
Delwath: 20 foot radius, 40 foot high cylinder.
DM: That's gonna get two of them.
Delwath: So I might just try and wipe dr- can I get one and a bunch of dragonets?
Unknown: Can I do that?
DM: The dragonets are flying in a line like 10 feet behind, sort of in two li- this is like a formation, right?
Unknown: Ah, okay.
DM: Everybody's spaced like 10 feet from each other.
DM: The dragonets are like this.
Delwath: Um,
Delwath: I'm gonna go-
DM: So-
Delwath: I'll hit, I'll hit-
DM: So you can hit two chimeras or you can hit five dragonets
DM: Or you can hit...
DM: You can hit two chimeras and two dragonets, or you could hit, like, five dragonets.
Delwath: Actually, it doesn't do that much damage.
Delwath: Five dragonets might be better, 'cause it'll probably be more likely to wipe them out.
DM: The dragonets are minions.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: So if they fail the save, they die.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: If they succeed the save, you have to do more than their hit points worth of damage.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Um, chimeras for now.
DM: Okay. What's the save?
Delwath: DC 17 dex.
Delwath: And being the one he hurt, plus-
Kenzo: But how are we gonna kill the dragonets then?
Unknown: Next turn.
DM: They both fail.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: All right. Nice.
DM: So rain of ice pours down.
Delwath: Actually, it's not bad damage, 'cause it's four...
Delwath: I didn't see the 4d6.
Delwath: Where's all the d6 at?
Wellby: Wellby needs all of these.
Delwath: Uh, 7,
Delwath: 17, 22, 21 damage.
DM: Okay.
DM: The ice rains down on
DM: the,
DM: um...
DM: Uh,
DM: she also has resistance to cold, thunder, and lightning.
DM: I don't think that'll come up.
DM: Um,
DM: okay. So they'll-
Unknown: And then she's gonna retreat back to the roof
DM: ... so the ice rains down on...
DM: How, how much damage did you say? Sorry.
Delwath: 20, 21.
DM: Okay.
DM: Rains down on these two chimeras.
DM: This, just we're gonna remember, one, two, three, four is the chimeras.
DM: Um,
DM: as
DM: now they move
DM: 120 feet closer, but Wellby gets a shot.
Wellby: 27 or 28.
DM: Yeah, 15 AC on the chimeras.
Delwath: Oh, that was your second-
DM: That's his readied action
Unknown: ...
Delwath: which is what? Via your haste?
Wellby: Yep.
Wellby: 31, 37.
DM: 37. The first chimera is bloodied.
Delwath: Then why can't you just take two shots at them?
DM: Because then he doesn't get sneak attack.
DM: It's only once per... You can only get sneak attack once per turn.
Unknown: Ah.
Unknown: What about Milo?
Wellby: Oh, and Milo gets a shot.
Delwath: Yeah, why can't he-
DM: 270. He can get a shot too.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Cool.
Wellby: Uh, Milo takes steady aim
Wellby: and, uh-
DM: Reroll the 1..
Wellby: Plus 10 is 17.
DM: 17'll hit a chimera.
Kenzo: Nice. AC 15.
Wellby: No, I'm sorry. Plus ni- nine, but it still hits.
Wellby: Uh, so his sneak attack is 5d6 plus 6 is 66.
Kenzo: Yeah, they're nasty.
Wellby: Plus-
Delwath: We haven't... Yeah, we've barely done anything
Wellby: ... five.
Kenzo: I mean, it's just like [dice clattering] just, just Wellby.
Wellby: Okay. It was not great. I'm not yet the druid.
DM: I know.
Wellby: There's 10-
Unknown: Druid
Wellby: ... 16, 17-
Delwath: Tilly got some weather damage out
Unknown: ... plus five is 22.
Kenzo: I totally did not realize that Milo-
Wellby: 22
Unknown: ... until we were, like, 10th level-
DM: I know
Kenzo: ... and we're like, awesome and-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... what are we do-
DM: Um-
Kenzo: Like, why the fuck have they not been with us this whole time?
Unknown: Like
DM: ... they have their own agenda.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But killing a dragon, I mean...
Unknown: Yeah, this is pretty sweet.
DM: Um, okay. Um,
DM: let's see. What's... What is...
DM: Okay, so that, that was...
DM: That would've been the end of the last round then, 'cause Milo was the last in initiative.
Kenzo: Okay. Now we're round, round five.
DM: So now we're round, beginning round-
Unknown: Five
DM: ... five.
DM: They're now 120 feet away from the edge.
Kenzo: Come on. I'm gonna fly closer to the soul site.
Delwath: Yeah. Should we, should we move in?
Delwath: I mean, I'm just-
Kenzo: I'm... I, I, I wanna stay...
Kenzo: I'm, I'm not gonna-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... engage yet, but I'm just gonna get close enough to soul site.
Wellby: All right. I'm gonna make my... I'm up first?
DM: Uh, yep, you're up first.
Wellby: Same chimera.
Wellby: [dice clattering] Uh, that hits.
Unknown: That hits.
Wellby: [dice clattering] And that is a bunch of numbers.
DM: Wellby's arrow kills the first chimera.
Unknown: Come on. [imitates arrow whooshing]
Wellby: Cool.
Unknown: Where's the dragon?
Delwath: Yeah, I know. Exactly.
DM: That, and that's Kenza's out.
Kenzo: All right. So now they're 120 feet-
DM: 120 feet, yeah.
Kenzo: Ah, man, I mean, I could f- I could fucking just go engage, engage them.
Kenzo: I mean, uh, for a first... Let me... I'm gonna move, um, 30 feet just to get...
Kenzo: What, was one, each one of these squares is how much?
DM: 10.
Kenzo: Okay. I'm gonna move, um, close enough now that I'm in range to soul sight, um-
DM: One of the chimeras
Kenzo: ... one of the chimera. Yeah. Just moving-
DM: Um, they are CR 6. They're immune to frightened.
Unknown: That's it?
DM: They're-
Unknown: Their weakest save?
DM: Weakest is intelligence, strongest is strength.
Seeker: It's good that their weakest is intelligence.
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: Sweet.
Kenzo: Oh, you know what? Actually,
Kenzo: um, funny enough, um, I've got a 90-foot acid arrow.
Unknown: I'll shoot that.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Ow.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: So what is this? This is D20 plus 5?
Unknown: I think so.
DM: Uh, yep.
Kenzo: Oh, wait. All right.
Unknown: Plus.
Kenzo: So now... Yeah, okay. Okay, now it's gonna get interesting.
Kenzo: So now, uh, do I have, uh, advantage from anything?
DM: No.
Wellby: No, 'cause the one you would've is dead, so nothing.
Kenzo: Okay. All right. So then, um,
Kenzo: I roll these two for my attack roll
Kenzo: plus 5. Uh, 7...
Kenzo: Oh, wait. Oh, fuck, with acid arrow.
Kenzo: Yeah, shit. That's annoying.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: That's not a great-
Kenzo: 12. That misses.
DM: That misses.
Unknown: All right. Then I retreat back.
DM: Yeah. Acid arrow is not, like, your best move.
Unknown: Yeah, that's fine.
Delwath: But we're just... Wait, we don't wanna, we don't wanna, like-
Unknown: Yeah, we're not, we're not
Unknown: ... over-
Unknown: ... engaged yet. This is-
DM: Okay. Delwath?
Delwath: All right. Delwath is gonna fly...
Delwath: Wait, they're... This is 120?
DM: Those are... They're all... Just treat them all like 120 from here
Delwath: From the edge or from-
DM: From the edge
Unknown: ... the edge?
DM: Yeah, yeah. They'll close onto the map next round.
Delwath: Oh, they're 120 from the edge. Oh.
Unknown: They're 120 from the edge?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Oh, so how did you shoot the-
Kenzo: I have 160 move. I, like, went closer-
Unknown: Ah
Unknown: ... to them.
Unknown: So you went 80.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: You went... I see.
Unknown: 120 from the edge.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I can't really get them. I don't think I want to spend a spell slot.
Unknown: Um-
DM: What is... Is Seeker just...
DM: Seeker is hiding right now in...
DM: So, so Seeker's in the doorway?
Seeker: Yeah. I'm gonna have to run up if I want to do that.
Delwath: 'Cause my best is 120.
Delwath: So when they hit the edge...
Delwath: Wait, can I ready an action?
Delwath: I'm gonna ready an action.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: They've been... I'm gonna ready an action to Eldritch Blast as soon as they're within 120 feet.
DM: Okay.
DM: So that's Delwath. Seeker?
Seeker: Within 120 feet of where you're standing?
Delwath: Yeah. I mean, I'm gonna fly.
Delwath: I'm gonna be like... What, is that Kenza?
Unknown: Where's Kenza?
Kenzo: That's Kenza, right, right here.
Unknown: Right there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So 10, 20, thir- I'm gonna be like there.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: And so when they're 120 feet of me,
Delwath: Eldritch Blast. That, like any c- the first chimera that comes within 120 feet-
DM: Okay
Delwath: ... I'm just gonna do all my Eldritch Blasts on.
Seeker: So I, if I move up to where you are and use my range doubling, I could hit one of the chimeras with a Rune of Psychic Destruction.
DM: You could.
Seeker: So I'm gonna do that.
Delwath: So don't then... Well, the dragon's not here yet, but it could appear.
Delwath: Like I'm nervous about us bunching the battle.
Unknown: Well, how m- actually, how much, uh-
Delwath: That's... Do you have 30 regular move?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: You can only move three squares.
Seeker: Oh, I may not be able to do this then.
Kenzo: So I can go there- Do you want to start it closer or...?
Unknown: Well-
Unknown: 16
Delwath: ... it's 16.
Kenzo: 'Cause you could have been moving this whole time, too, all these rounds.
Unknown: One, two, three, four, five-
Unknown: True
Seeker: ... six, seven, eight, nine, ten, 11, 12.
Unknown: That's true.
Delwath: It's 12... From there you're good.
Delwath: From there it's up, it's 12 to here and 100-
Kenzo: From, from here?
Delwath: Yeah. It's 12 to the edge and 12 to the edge.
Seeker: So that's, that's right at my range.
Seeker: Okay. So I cast, um,
Seeker: a double distance Rune of Psychic Destruction at-
DM: Okay
Unknown: ... at the fifth level.
DM: Chimera two, the one that's wounded?
Seeker: Yeah, chimera two.
Seeker: Uh, so it makes a,
Seeker: uh, INT 18 save.
DM: Oh, they're terrible at INT.
DM: That's a five.
DM: [dice rolling]
Seeker: So that's 7d6 psychic damage and incapacitated-
DM: Okay
Seeker: ... at the start of my next turn.
Delwath: Oh, so does it fall?
Unknown: 7d6, if you want. It falls.
DM: If it's incapacitated, it falls.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Nice.
DM: It lands on the ground. They're flying about 50 feet up, so roll an extra 5d6 for fall damage.
Seeker: Oh, okay. So that's, um-
Delwath: 15, 22
Seeker: ... 22 plus an extra five you said?
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Yep.
DM: [dice rolling]
Unknown: That's, um-
Unknown: 60, 18.
Unknown: 18.
Unknown: 8, 40.
DM: 22 and 18?
Unknown: 40.
DM: Okay. That one's almost gone.
DM: The first one is dead.
Unknown: Smashed to the ground. All right.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Who's next?
DM: Um, after Seeker is Tilly.
Delwath: Tilly is going to...
Delwath: Tilly's job... Wait, we said Till- I mean, Tilly's like, yeah, I'm gonna burn slots.
Unknown: Tilly's gonna burn slots.
DM: Tilly can burn slots, for sure.
Delwath: Yeah. Oh wait, that's Delwath though.
Unknown: Tilly can't use Delwath's slots.
Delwath: Tilly is going to-
Unknown: The construct is-
Unknown: There's-
Seeker: ... getting excited stonily
Delwath: ... uh, I don't...
Delwath: There's nothing with-
Unknown: I should-
Delwath: ... wait, 120.
Unknown: Should they just like-
Delwath: Sorry, I don't know how characters-
Unknown: ... hit her?
Unknown: ... keep that well.
DM: That's fine. Just go for it.
Unknown: I think another ice storm.
DM: Just use another ice storm.
Delwath: Yeah, I think another ice storm on this one.
DM: Just like knockout, ma- or hit the two-
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. Ice storm on those two chimeras.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Yeah. [dice rolling]
DM: Uh, fail. [dice rolling] Fail.
Delwath: 17. So that's-
DM: So that's chimeras three and four.
Delwath: Uh, 4d6 and 2d10.
Delwath: [dice rolling] Ah, crap damage though.
Delwath: 5, 10, 14 damage.
DM: Eh.
Unknown: It's awful.
DM: It's not nothing.
DM: Um, that ends Tilly's turn, so they're all moving now.
DM: You have a readied?
Wellby: Yep. I have a shot on the guy who fell to the ground.
DM: Okay. [dice rolling]
Wellby: That is 16.
Wellby: 16.
DM: Um, that hits, although because he's prone, you have disadvantage on ranged attacks, which cancels your advantage.
DM: So
DM: that's not gonna work.
DM: I mean, you're not gonna sneak attack on him.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: Pr- you have disadvantage on prone creatures if you're further than five feet from them.
Wellby: Oh, well, got it. Sharpshooter doesn't negate that.
DM: No.
Unknown: That's just cover.
DM: That's just cover and range.
Wellby: Uh, I rolled both these simultaneously.
Unknown: Should I roll again or-
DM: Well, it, I mean, you can hit.
DM: I'm just saying you're not gonna get sneak attack and advantage.
Wellby: Can I shoot a different one instead?
DM: Uh, the readied actions has to be specific.
Unknown: All right. So I-
DM: You, you can hit. It's fine you hit.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: But just roll your strength damage.
Wellby: This is useless. Yeah. All right. That is a mighty
Unknown: seven. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: It's bloodied.
DM: Um,
DM: Milo can take a shot.
Wellby: Uh, cool. He's gonna hit that same one on the ground.
Unknown: [dice rolling]
Delwath: But he also has the same problem.
Unknown: N-
Unknown: Yeah, he shouldn't shoot the one on the ground.
Unknown: He should change. Yeah.
DM: Go at one of the others.
Wellby: Seven was the higher plus-
DM: Plus
Wellby: ... nine, 16.
DM: That hits
Unknown: ... to
Wellby: hit. 2 more d6s.
Delwath: Yeah, we can s- I mean, it's better to knock two out of that actually.
Wellby: So 12, 18, 20, 30 altogether.
DM: Okay. That one's pretty wounded too.
DM: That ends Milo's turn.
Kenzo: This is just like-
DM: An invisible dragon-
Unknown: Oh-
DM: ... turns visible
Unknown: ... this is just-
Delwath: Oh, man, I should have stayed invisible.
Unknown: Wait
Unknown: ... this is just, this is
Unknown: just-
Unknown: I...
Unknown: Didn't you have-
DM: That was a long time ago
Delwath: ... No, I used-
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Fair enough.
DM: And shoots a line of darkness.
Unknown: Darkness?
Unknown: Oh.
DM: And acid.
Unknown: Darkness. That's interesting.
DM: Let me see.
Delwath: Wait, this is a daylight.
Delwath: We're powering the thing with daylight-
DM: I know
Delwath: ... just so you know.
DM: Um.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: 90 feet long and 20 feet wide, so it's two squares wide and nine squares long.
DM: One, two, so one,
DM: one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, sorry, nine.
DM: Who's that in the door?
Delwath: That's Milo.
DM: Okay. So it's gonna hit everybody here.
Delwath: Wait, Kenza and me are supposed to be 30...
Delwath: Oh, if it goes in the middle, it's 30 feet.
Unknown: Huh?
Delwath: Kenza and I are supposed to be 30 feet apart.
Kenzo: We're 30 feet apart.
Delwath: Oh, but it's shooting in between us.
Unknown: Yep. Because-
DM: It's shooting in between you.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: It's 20 feet wide.
Wellby: Does that cover the vertical distances involved?
Unknown: Where are we vertical?
DM: Well, okay, it can go...
DM: Where are you right now?
Unknown: It's okay. We can move.
Kenzo: I think it can hit you.
Unknown: No, it definitely hits.
DM: It can definitely hit you because you're thir- I mean-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... you're 30 feet this way.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
DM: So all of you, everybody there.
DM: Fortunately, Milo has invasion, evasion, otherwise he would probably be dead.
DM: Make a dexterity saving throw.
DM: [dice rolling]
Delwath: Fail. Six.
Delwath: That's not even worth trying to save [dice rolling] on a fail.
Unknown: So
Seeker: the, the ladder rolls, uh-
DM: I need some more d6s
Unknown: ... an eight
DM: I need a... Well, I'll just roll auto.
Unknown: I need a one [dice rolling]
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: There's more d-
Unknown: You should roll auto in general. Just roll auto.
Seeker: Yeah, I'll roll auto. [dice rolling] Um.
Seeker: The stone construct [dice rolling] rolls a 17.
Unknown: 23.
Wellby: 18 for Milo.
DM: Uh, okay. So anybody who beats a 22 succeeds.
Unknown: Fuck.
Seeker: Oh, oh. Oh man.
Delwath: He uses Bardic.
Wellby: He's gonna use his Bardic.
Kenzo: Definitely use Bardic.
DM: What'd you get?
Unknown: 23. [dice rolling] Oh, fuck.
Kenzo: He still fails.
Wellby: He still only gets a 20.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Half damage, but still.
DM: So that is, um, 32 points of acid damage.
Kenzo: To what?
DM: Um, hold on. Let me just roll.
DM: And...
Unknown: They're all gonna die.
DM: 38 points of necrotic damage.
Delwath: It's not that bad. That's its breath.
DM: That's his breath. So Milo takes half of that because of evasion.
Delwath: I mean, that's half my hit points, but...
DM: So-
Seeker: That is a total of 70.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: 70. Anybody who failed takes 70.
Wellby: You're tracking hit points for everyone.
DM: But unless you're Milo, in which case you take 35.
Delwath: But you're not in the range. Oh, the, those guys are though.
Delwath: Do they make their save?
Seeker: No.
Unknown: Are they dead?
Seeker: They didn't make it a 22 save. Like there's no possible way they beat that.
Delwath: Yeah. Yeah. Could've rolled 20. Are they dead?
Seeker: Um, the, the stone construct is, is.
Unknown: Oh, that's awful.
Unknown: Right at, hits zero.
Delwath: Oh no, it cracks.
Kenzo: Can I eat a goodberry or [laughs]
Unknown: The stone construct cracks.
Unknown: No, it's too... You can't. You can't bring it back.
Seeker: The la- the ladder is down to 15.
DM: And that ends-
Unknown: Wow
DM: ... the dragon's turn.
Delwath: Well, that's kind of sad. We never got to use the construct.
Unknown: Hold on. Hold-
DM: I mean, you can summon it again.
Delwath: You can cast it.
DM: You can summon it at sixth level.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Hold on, hold on, though. Wait, so...
Kenzo: But it was 30 necrotic.
DM: It was 70 total, but, uh-
Unknown: You made the save
DM: ... 32-
Unknown: I made my save
Unknown: ... so zero.
DM: So you take zero if you make your save.
DM: You have evasion. You don't take any damage if you make a dex save.
Delwath: Oh, wait. Was that acid? That was acid and-
DM: 32 acid, 38 necrotic.
Delwath: I'm gonna, I'm gonna...
DM: So you add 16 back.
Delwath: Yeah. [sighs] 'Cause that's gonna last till the start of my next turn.
Kenzo: Is evasion a natural ability or is it-
DM: Yeah, it's part of your monk. It's your monk ability.
Kenzo: I've always had evasion?
DM: Yeah, since seventh level.
Unknown: Sweet. [intense music]
DM: Uh, that brings up Wellby.
DM: [die rolling] So Milo's down to, like, half his health.
DM: Oh, uh, the drac- the...
DM: Oh, that thing's, it's not immune to acid, it's just resistant to acid, right?
Delwath: Yeah, summon draconic spirit, it is resistant to acid.
DM: How many hit points does it have?
Unknown: It has 50.
DM: How m- did it make its save?
Delwath: I didn't, I forgot to roll a save.
Delwath: [die rolling] No.
DM: Okay. So it takes
DM: 38 plus 16.
Delwath: 48, it's gone.
Kenzo: Is this, uh... Oh, that's, that's the ladder.
Seeker: It, it took out the draconic spirit?
DM: It took out the draconic spirit and it took out the summons.
Unknown: Damn.
Kenzo: Is it, uh... How, how, how many...
Unknown: How high up is it flying to?
DM: Yeah, it's flying, it's flying.
DM: It's about level with you.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: How high are we?
DM: That ends its turn, so Wellby, you're up.
Wellby: Chimeras, right?
DM: That was your job.
Unknown: Stand close.
DM: So the chimeras, the chimeras now at the be- they move another 120 feet closer.
Seeker: Or just run away because...
DM: This one stands up and this one's lagging back, but let's put these guys on the map.
Kenzo: Yeah, the chimeras. Finish them off.
Delwath: So I still get my attack.
Delwath: I get my ready action.
DM: You get your ready action, yep.
DM: Uh, not if you use your reaction to...
DM: Your ready action takes a reaction, so if you-
DM: Wow.
Unknown: Uh,
Delwath: three shots on a chimera.
Delwath: I'm probably better not using absorb elements.
Unknown: Hm.
Delwath: I'll take the 16 damage back.
DM: Okay. [die rolling]
Unknown: [laughs] 13.
DM: On a chimera, 13 misses.
Unknown: [die rolling] 19.
Unknown: That hits.
Unknown: [die rolling] [laughs]
Seeker: This, this is not going well.
Delwath: I think we might... I mean, why did we stay to fight these guys?
Delwath: [die rolling] Three damage.
Delwath: I, totally, that was a awful decision.
Wellby: Dimitar guilted us into it.
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: It is what it is.
Delwath: But Dim, you know you can't, like, kill us, right?
Seeker: Dimitar has not-
DM: You forced us to fight the dragon.
Unknown: No, we, we, we, we, we're totally fine.
DM: You're... Come on, it doesn't get his dr-
Unknown: That's true
DM: ... it's not gonna get his breath weapon back for a while.
Kenzo: We're, we're, we're... I think we're in great shape.
Delwath: I think not.
Wellby: We have the upper hand.
Unknown: [laughs] You've taken out, like, a good chunk of its health.
Delwath: I know. I'm not worried about the minions.
Kenzo: Well, just wait for the dragonets.
Kenzo: We to... The, the, our dragonets are gonna show up.
Delwath: Nah, I think the effect of our...
Unknown: Well, we'll see.
Unknown: They're good. They're good. They'll show up in a bit.
DM: Who's turn is it?
DM: Uh, so that...
DM: So Wel- Wellby hasn't done...
Unknown: Uh, Wellby, have you done anything yet?
DM: Nope.
DM: It's Wellby's turn.
Unknown: All right. I'm gonna shoot-
DM: Kenzo's next
Wellby: ... chimera number three.
DM: Okay. [die rolling]
Unknown: That hits.
DM: Hits.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: more sixes.
DM: Dragons are supposed to make a dramatic entry.
Delwath: Yeah, I know.
Kenzo: No, that was great.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: It was feeling too easy.
Unknown: It was.
Unknown: It was feeling like way too easy.
Unknown: It was way too easy.
Kenzo: I was just like, what's going on?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: We're just like-
DM: You're, you're over-
Kenzo: ... we're just slaughtering these, these...
Kenzo: We haven't taken any damage. We're just sitting here relaxed.
DM: Uh, the nice effect of his sunlight though is normally it would leave scars of darkness across the battlefield, but they're instantly dispelled by the daylight spell.
Wellby: Oh, awesome. I'm also gonna dump all four charges of the [dice rolling] fire into this one.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Oh, that's not great rolling.
Wellby: So that's 15.
Delwath: We used all our good rolls against the fiend.
Unknown: 21.
DM: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: Eh, we'll see.
Wellby: 25, 28.
Unknown: And he's down.
Wellby: Plus 6 is 34.
Wellby: Um, so that's 34 to start and then...
Unknown: [dice rolling]
Kenzo: Your hay says you get another.
Wellby: No, this is for the fire.
Wellby: It's another 16,
Wellby: so that's 50-
DM: Okay
Wellby: ... all together.
DM: Nine... That one's looking almost dead.
Wellby: Oh, shit. Can I move?
Kenzo: You didn't, you are not in the breath weapon attack radius, so you're, you're fine.
Kenzo: Are you flying?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, he's flying.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: Dimitaur-
Wellby: Actually I'm gonna move
DM: ... on telepathy says, "Don't worry.
DM: I got this guys."
Unknown: What?
Kenzo: He's gonna use fireball on the dragon?
Wellby: Tim, I wanna take... Can I take-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... one of those D6s off to use a withdraw?
DM: Yep.
Wellby: I will do that.
Wellby: I'll move 45 feet,
Wellby: what? Straight upwards.
Unknown: Up?
Wellby: Yeah. Why not?
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: And then I'll ready an action
Wellby: to shoot, uh, number three again
Wellby: with whatever move.
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh, that ends Welby's turn.
DM: Um, Kenzo is up.
Unknown: All right friends.
Kenzo: It is time-
DM: How much damage does a seventh level fireball do?
Unknown: Let's go do other stuff.
Unknown: Uh.
DM: 4th, 5th, 6th, 7th. 12 D8s, yeah?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: It's 8d6 plus fourth, fifth, sixth, seventh.
Delwath: Yeah, 12d6.
Kenzo: So wait, I, um, for bless I get a d4 on all of my...
Kenzo: So even for the-
Unknown: Every-
Kenzo: Right, so it's, it's, each one of these gets a d4.
DM: Yeah, yep. Yep, yep.
Kenzo: Great. All right, so these count, right?
Unknown: So who are you closing on?
Kenzo: Um, so I'm gonna go fuckin'...
Unknown: Let's go Ra'ghemdros.
Unknown: Fuck up the dragon?
Unknown: Fuck you. Let's go.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Ken- massive double-sized huge f- Kenzo, still small compared to the dragon, but large,
Kenzo: flies over to engage the dragon.
Kenzo: [object clattering] Oh, shit.
Unknown: Sorry. [laughs]
Unknown: All right. [sighs]
DM: Five attacks.
Unknown: Here we go.
DM: Flurry of blows.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Langal's claw.
Kenzo: Giant jaguar claw starts...
Kenzo: Oh, I actually, I actually don't have to be, I actually don't have to be engaged.
Unknown: But-
DM: You can be 15 feet away.
DM: There's no reason to be that close.
Unknown: Yeah, actually I'm gonna pull back
Unknown: one square.
Kenzo: All right, um, I'm gonna do these separately as, um, my, uh...
Unknown: Right? Oh, no, I don't have advantage right now.
Wellby: You don't have advantage.
DM: You don't have advantage.
Kenzo: All right. So but this is plus 10.
DM: Right. A dragon's AC is-
Kenzo: Again, and then it can attack again
Unknown: 22.
DM: Dragon's AC is 20.
Kenzo: Okay, so 22 hits.
Delwath: You could resummon the construct.
Delwath: I could use a healing...
Delwath: If I'm gonna charge into combat with it, a healing word might be helpful.
Kenzo: Um, and then I do D6 from the claw-
Kenzo: It'll probably stay at 50 for one turn
Kenzo: ... D4 from the, uh, bl-, uh, from the enlarged-
Kenzo: I don't know if it can get to 50 in one turn
Kenzo: ... and then D10 plus five, right?
DM: Uh, yep, that's what you roll, plus five.
Wellby: For damage. [dice rolling]
Wellby: When you summon the construct-
Unknown: Is
DM: this a two?
Wellby: Like summon it on the dragon's back
DM: That's a two
Wellby: So four-
Unknown: That's what I was just reading about it
Unknown: ... eight plus five is-
Unknown: 90 foot range
Unknown: ... 13.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Okay, that's the first attack.
DM: First attack.
Delwath: The ladder is here.
Unknown: 13.
Delwath: The ladder's still there.
DM: Wait, when did it go anyways?
Unknown: Second attack. [dice rolling]
DM: Seeker's a- right a- immediately after you.
Unknown: The second attack hits.
Unknown: So goes when's Tilly?
DM: Tilly's immediately after Seeker, then the chimeras, then Milo.
Kenzo: Um, Tim, I'm gonna... Wait, is it, is he immune to stun?
Unknown: He-
Seeker: It's that or use catapults
DM: ... yes, he's immune to stun.
Kenzo: He's immune to all my, my tricks, right?
DM: He's immune to all your tricks-
Unknown: No, they're not
DM: ... except your-
Seeker: Hit him with it
DM: ... massive giant fists
Unknown: ... I'm 10 feet away.
Unknown: Yeah. All right.
Unknown: I would... [dice rolling] I mean, you could go stun a chimera.
DM: They would probably fall pretty quickly.
DM: Yeah, but that's-
Kenzo: 3, 7, 12.
Unknown: So that's-
DM: Second attack is a 12
Kenzo: ... second attack is a 12. [dice rolling]
Unknown: Hits.
Unknown: Still hits.
Unknown: Plus 10, right?
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Oh, no, what's going on?
Delwath: I think s- I mean, summoning the construct [dice rolling] is maybe not a bad move.
Unknown: Ooh, this was a good one.
Unknown: Um-
DM: I mean, you could-
Unknown: ... a special 15
DM: ... summon the construct onto the dragon's back
Seeker: ... that's what I was thinking, yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah. Uh, third attack is a 22.
DM: Just have to get-
Unknown: 22 damage
Unknown: ... yep
Seeker: ... a tiny bit closer. Oh, no.
DM: Just don't get dead.
Unknown: Natural 20.
Wellby: Natural 20.
Kenzo: Let's fucking go.
Unknown: Yay.
Unknown: All right.
DM: That's, that's your fourth attack, so you still got one more.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh, so, so I roll these damage twice.
DM: All of it, all of it's twice. Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Okay,
Unknown: all right.
DM: Kenzo's just like-
Unknown: I'm, I'm-
DM: ... "No, no."
Unknown: ... just fuck this dragon.
DM: I dodge and dash.
Unknown: Oh, fuck this bitch. So s-
Delwath: 17
Delwath: ... 17.
Kenzo: Okay, I'm doing a lot of fucking damage to this thing.
Delwath: So that's 20. [dice rolling]
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: Nice rolling.
Unknown: 17.
Unknown: Plus three plus-
Kenzo: Hold on, hold on. 31 plus 5, that's 36.
DM: 36.
Kenzo: And I got one more attack, my fifth attack.
Unknown: [dice rolling] Hits.
DM: Nice.
Delwath: All right, I'm feeling better about this.
Seeker: Yeah, that was good.
Unknown: [laughs] Kenzo's revived my stellar spirits.
Unknown: Uh, 10.
DM: I mean, Delwath was spot-
Kenzo: That's another 15
DM: ... on the fiend fight.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: And then Kenzo-
Unknown: 15
DM: ... hit the dragon fight.
Unknown: Yeah. Delwath's like, "Kenzo-"
DM: That's another 15 damage
Kenzo: ... another 15 damage, yeah.
Unknown: What'd you do?
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Good damage.
DM: Kenza did 98...
Unknown: Oh, no, min- yeah, 98 damage in one round.
Seeker: Can we get a visual on it?
Kenzo: Uh, just giant, massive jaguar fist, just faster than you can even see, going boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, right into the dra- Like, the dragon's head's going uh, uh, uh,
Unknown: uh, uh, uh, uh. [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Yeah, your giant fist is, like, kind of the size of its head.
Kenzo: That was satisfying.
Kenzo: Please swap.
DM: Oh, yeah.
DM: Just gonna bring
DM: my... Uh, okay. That ends Kenzo's turn.
DM: The dragonets...
DM: Um, Welby, you moved 40 feet straight up?
Wellby: 45 feet straight up.
DM: Okay. Um, the dragonets are gonna split into two groups.
DM: One group is gonna dash
DM: and swarm Delvy, Welby.
DM: That's half of them. That's seven of them.
Wellby: I think that they can't close into melee with me this round unless they dash.
Delwath: Yeah, they dash.
DM: They dash.
Unknown: That's what I said.
Wellby: Oh, okay.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: So they can't attack.
DM: Yeah, they can't attack-
Wellby: Great
DM: ... but they can close into melee.
Unknown: So one, two, three, four.
Wellby: Does my readied action require my reaction?
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Yes.
Wellby: Okay.
Kenzo: So I'm just moving all seven of these together-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... into, like, a group.
DM: They're like around Welby. The other six, um, are looking for spellcasters.
DM: The only one they can see right now is-
Unknown: Tilly?
DM: ... Seek- oh, Tilly's on the roof.
Delwath: Tilly's on the roof.
DM: They're gonna move towards Tilly.
Kenzo: How many of them?
DM: [laughs] Um, all-
Unknown: Five?
DM: All five of them that are left.
Unknown: Oh, six.
Unknown: Wait, was, was Tilly... Tilly was unclear
Delwath: assignment. I think, I think draconic sp- oh, wait, can they close to her?
DM: Um, h- no, that's, like, five squares, right?
DM: That- They...
DM: No, they get within...
DM: They can dash. They close with her with a dash
Delwath: Okay, but they're surrounding her?
DM: They're surrounding her.
Unknown: Man, that's annoying.
DM: Go to it.
Unknown: And the
Wellby: chimeras move?
DM: No, the chime- chimeras are later in the initiative.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: I just wasn't keeping them separate while they were just all dashing.
Unknown: Good.
DM: That ends the dragon S turn.
Unknown: And what about the minions?
DM: Then... They're minions.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Del, what's up?
Delwath: I can close to the dragon.
Delwath: I'm just doing it.
Unknown: Yeah, let's fucking go, Del.
Unknown: Like, I mean-
Unknown: Let's just fucking go.
DM: Oh, sorry, I forgot. Um, oh no, not for Kenzo, but Delwath, when you
DM: start your turn,
DM: uh, Kenza is not within 30 feet, is he?
Unknown: No.
DM: Uh, when you start your turn-
Unknown: Oh, Kenza, you're supposed to stay within 30 feet of me
DM: ... within... Oh, well, how close are you to the dragon right now?
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Uh, it was like 80, 70 feet.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Or 60.
DM: You don't need to make your save till you get within 30 feet of the dragon.
Kenzo: Yeah, but then you'll be within 30 feet.
Delwath: That'll all get me 30 feet of Kenza.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: When you get within 30 feet of the dragon for the first time you have to make a save against fear.
Delwath: Okay. So, so I'm gonna close to here.
Kenzo: Nice. Perfect.
Delwath: But I'm within 30 feet of Kenzo.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So make your wisdom save with advantage.
Delwath: Well, hopefully I do better on my second roll.
Unknown: I need a different die. I'm not happy with this die.
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: Yes. [clapping]
DM: And you are immune to its fear.
Delwath: Okay. So I close.
Unknown: Bonus action mark it.
DM: Good thing you had advantage.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: bonus action mark it.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: And then
Unknown: stab it.
Kenzo: Dragon claw came in handy.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Uh, 21.
DM: That hits. AC is 20.
Delwath: I need two D6 too.
Unknown: Here.
Kenzo: Actually, I want that.
Delwath: Okay, let's take two of yours. Okay, so this glowing...
Delwath: I mean, Delwath's glowing with bright light and when he attacks some of the light travels along his sword-
Kenzo: Ooh, that's good damage
Kenzo: ... and hits the dragon.
Kenzo: We like that.
Delwath: 10, 19 plus 5.
Unknown: 24.
Delwath: 24. Attack one is 24.
Unknown: Not crit.
DM: That's a 20.
Delwath: I'll do smite.
Kenzo: You can declare that after a crit?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, it's after you hit.
Unknown: That's sweet.
Unknown: Oh man, that's a lot of damage.
Unknown: Uh-
Unknown: Look
Delwath: ... I'll do smite is eight, seven...
Delwath: Wait, how much did you say it was? Six, six, so 12.
DM: 12 D8.
Unknown: Six.
Delwath: Oops. So it's one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
Delwath: So it's eight, it's this doubled.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Wait, be careful.
Delwath: Uh, 10, 20,
Delwath: uh, 10, 20,
Unknown: 30,
Delwath: uh, plus fi- uh, plus 5, 40, 48.
Delwath: That included my normal plus 5.
Unknown: Okay. Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: So yeah.
DM: All right.
Delwath: 15,
Unknown: 20,
Unknown: 30,
Delwath: 8, 9,
Delwath: uh, 45. Oh, I'm giving Kenzo a run for his money.
Unknown: Yeah, this is, I mean, this is-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... this is how it should be.
DM: Um, after Delwath ends its turn-
Delwath: I'm not done. I got one more attack.
DM: Oh, you're... Oh, sorry.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Three attacks. Three attacks.
DM: Oh, you might surpass Kenzo then.
DM: You're gonna surpass Kenzo if you hit.
Unknown: You will.
Unknown: Yeah?
Delwath: That burns a spell. I knew I was saving my spell slots for a reason.
Unknown: That smells good.
DM: Mm.
Unknown: Oh, plus 5 more damage.
Delwath: I forgot I marked it.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Oh, I still crit on 19s.
Unknown: Nope.
Wellby: You crit on 19s?
Unknown: Uh, 17. That misses.
DM: That misses.
DM: So after, after Delwath's-
Delwath: With when I've marked the creature
DM: ... after Delwath's turn, um, you can see the dragon is angry and pissed.
DM: It wasn't quite expecting this much fight.
DM: Sort of shakes its wings and these,
DM: um, globules of acid fly out of its mouth.
DM: Um,
DM: let's see. Who's within nine squares?
DM: One,
DM: uh, one, two, three-
Seeker: Um, I'm not
DM: ... four, five, six.
Delwath: No. Nine is 100, nine squares is like 90 feet?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. Okay.
DM: Two, three. One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
DM: Uh,
DM: Wellby is not.
DM: Tilly is. Dimitar is hiding.
DM: Um, so everybody but Wellby has to make a dexterity saving throw.
DM: Dex plus seven.
DM: Tilly gets
DM: an 8.
Delwath: Tilly rolls a one.
Unknown: 24.
Delwath: Uh, Tilly has a pl- has a two.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Delwath has a 14.
Wellby: Milo rolls a-
Unknown: No, a 15
Wellby: ... 27.
DM: Okay. Anybody... Sorry, 27.
Unknown: 24.
Unknown: But I might-
DM: 24.
Unknown: Shit.
DM: What did you roll?
Unknown: 15.
DM: Okay. That fails.
Unknown: Okay. I think-
DM: You two succeed
Unknown: ... I'm going to-
DM: What did you roll?
Unknown: 13.
DM: You fail. Tilly fails.
Wellby: Does she have heroic inspiration?
Seeker: I can heroic inspiration that, right?
DM: You can.
Delwath: Oh, wait, she's a halfling.
Seeker: That's just re-roll, right?
DM: Oh, she re-rolls ones. Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: 8.
Seeker: All right. So I use my heroic inspiration to re-roll mine.
Unknown: 6.
Delwath: I actually get plus 7.
Unknown: That's a 2.
Delwath: I have 22.
Unknown: That's-
DM: Okay. You succeed
Seeker: ... 17.
DM: Um, so a globule-
Unknown: 18, 20
DM: ... of acid... Sorry, what did you get?
Seeker: 17.
DM: A globule of acid attaches itself to Seeker.
Unknown: Shit.
DM: Tilly.
DM: What did Milo roll?
Unknown: 27.
Unknown: 7. Yeah.
DM: Seeker and Tilly.
Unknown: Ah.
Delwath: Wait, Tilly got... I don't know.
Delwath: She only got an 8. She's not gonna make it even with bardic inspiration.
Kenzo: What'd you get?
Delwath: Uh, I got a 15, but I used my favor of the gods.
Unknown: Latanchi came down and blessed me and gave me a plus 7.
DM: Tilly, Tilly might have to run.
DM: Um, so Tilly and Seeker take, um, 14 points of acid damage and a globule of acid is attached to each of you.
DM: You can use an acid, an action to remove it, uh, from yourself or another creature.
Delwath: Tilly's gonna absorb elements.
DM: Okay. But if you don't remove it, you take 14 damage at the s- um, end of every turn.
Delwath: It's only 7 damage. That's not...
Delwath: I mean, she can absorb elements every turn.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Yeah Okay.
Kenzo: So she's still all right.
Unknown: She's okay.
Unknown: How many hit points does she have?
Delwath: 81 right now.
Unknown: Ah, man. She's-
DM: So she wasn't hit by the breath weapon.
Delwath: No, she missed the breath. Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um.
Unknown: Did you get hit by the breath weapon?
Unknown: No.
Seeker: Oh, great. Great.
Unknown: So I could, I could take 14 damage all day long.
DM: It's Seeker's turn.
DM: Um-
Kenzo: All right, Seeker, let's do something awesome.
Unknown: I, I was-
Delwath: Summon the go one is back
Seeker: ... I was mad about that stone construct getting destroyed.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: And I just realized, if I cast it at eighth level, it can make four attacks.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs] Do it. Do it.
Unknown: And has-
Unknown: Just do it
Unknown: ... 100 points-
Unknown: Just... No, no
Unknown: ... of AC 21.
Unknown: That's absolutely.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: You, you need to give-
Unknown: And-
Unknown: You need to give Captain America a run for his money.
DM: That's fucking go. Yeah, let's fucking go.
Seeker: I can drop it... Well, it's still...
Seeker: Anyway, it'll be pretty good.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: I can drop it-
Unknown: Eight attacks
Seeker: ... basically onto-
DM: Four
DM: ... yeah, you can drop it onto its back.
Seeker: Onto the dragon's back.
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: Hold on. Let, let me see if there's a way to balance it here.
Unknown: Go ahead and put it...
Unknown: [laughs] So-
DM: I don't think it's gonna-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Two four, two four and the sixes.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Um.
Unknown: Oh, yeah. There you go.
Unknown: So it-
Seeker: Can you do it like this?
Seeker: And it can attack right away, right?
DM: It can attack right away.
Unknown: Yeah. Um.
Delwath: Does its damage go up 'cause it's...
Delwath: No, it just gets more attacks.
Seeker: Yeah. Um,
Seeker: so its attack is...
Kenzo: How long does, before it can do its breath weapon again?
Delwath: It rolls every turn and if it gets a six, it can do it again.
Unknown: [dice rolling] That's usually how dragons work.
Seeker: Oh, actually no, it is more. It's-
Unknown: 'Cause you went down.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: That, that's really, that's actually really cool.
Unknown: 28 plus 12.
Kenzo: Yeah, it's creepy and scary.
Delwath: Yeah, another breath weapon would take Delwath down.
Seeker: And my attack roll is D20 plus two.
Delwath: But you're fi-... I mean, you...
Delwath: With evasion, it's so useful against dragons.
Unknown: It is.
Kenzo: It's pretty fucking amazing, yeah.
Unknown: So I have four of those.
Kenzo: You also have evasion, right? Yeah. Good.
Unknown: 19.
DM: Yeah, Milo-
Unknown: Did Milo get hit by the first one?
Unknown: Nope.
DM: He was out of the breath weapon.
Kenzo: Milo get hit by the first one?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Milo's the biggest, in the most danger.
Wellby: Milo also has evasion, though, as a rogue.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: So he took half.
Kenzo: Oh, he took half damage.
Wellby: Otherwise, okay. Being serious troll.
Seeker: Yeah. Um, all right.
Seeker: So I'll... The stone construct makes its four slam attacks.
Unknown: [dice rolling]
Unknown: Let's go.
Seeker: Oh, man.
Unknown: Oh, no.
Unknown: It's plus.
Seeker: So a 28, a 21.
Delwath: Those two of them hit.
Unknown: Two hits
Seeker: ... a 16 and a 11.
Unknown: Two hit.
DM: Two hit.
Seeker: So that's
Seeker: 2D8 plus [dice rolling] 24 damage.
Unknown: 2D8 plus?
Unknown: Uh, 2D8. I'm just talking D8s here.
Kenzo: 2D8 plus what?
Unknown: 24.
Unknown: Oh, nice.
Seeker: [dice rolling] So
Seeker: 27.
DM: 27. That's-
Unknown: Hey, man.
Kenzo: That's good.
DM: [laughs] Wait, does it have rider?
DM: Does it do something?
Delwath: Yeah. Decreased speed by...
Seeker: So stony lethargy.
Seeker: When a creature the constructs can see starts his turn within 10 feet of the construct, the construct can force it to make a wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC.
Delwath: Oh, it can use reactions.
Unknown: DC.
Seeker: That's good.
Seeker: On a failed save, the target can't use reactions and its speed is halved until the start of his next turn.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: I mean, it might make a save.
Seeker: A wisdom save, yeah.
DM: That ends Seeker's turn.
Kenzo: Did you roll a wisdom save?
Unknown: Uh, the ladder.
DM: No, that's when it starts its turn.
Unknown: Ladder.
Seeker: But ladder also has a move of 40.
DM: Is the ladder immune to fear or have we looked at this before?
Seeker: That's a good question.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: The ladder...
Kenzo: [laughs] Well, once it's within 30 feet of me, it still gets-
Unknown: No
Unknown: ... it still gets a save.
DM: Okay. So ladder needs to roll a f- a save against the fright.
Unknown: Look.
Unknown: With advantage.
Unknown: Wait, wait.
Unknown: It's, it started with him.
Seeker: Immune to frightened.
Unknown: Oh, no, no.
Delwath: Yeah, it's immune.
Unknown: Sorry, sorry.
DM: La- Of course it's the heroic ladder.
Unknown: It's the ladder. [laughs]
DM: The ladder. It can't be scared.
Kenzo: Did, did the ladder give the fatal blow to the last dragon anyways?
Unknown: It was, it was-
Unknown: I think it did.
Unknown: It did.
DM: It did.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
DM: The last dragon, the ladder grappled it and held it down-
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... for the most of the fight.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: And made it possible for you to finish it.
Kenzo: All right, so you're moving this closer?
Seeker: So the, the ladder is gonna go up...
Seeker: Should I try to grapple instead of slam?
Wellby: Totally, 'cause gr- grapple also neutralizes-
DM: Well, well you can't. It's too...
DM: This is an ancient dragon. It's gargantuan.
DM: It's too big for the ladder to grapple.
Seeker: All right. So it just makes its, its slam attack.
Seeker: [dice rolling] Uh, that's a 24.
Unknown: That hits.
Seeker: So hit. [dice rolling] And it's-
Wellby: It's just that, like, the ladder should get on its back or otherwise out of [dice rolling] its breath weapon-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... direction.
Kenzo: Yeah. Getting on, on the, on it.
Seeker: It only has a 40 move though, so.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Well.
Delwath: I mean, we want to be spread out so that...
Delwath: I mean, that's fine. It can't... I mean, it could move over here and get all of us with a breath weapon, but.
Unknown: That's just how it is. That's like how the-
Seeker: Um, so 1D10 plus five damage.
Unknown: Yeah, that'd be a two.
Delwath: Or move here and get all of us and Tilly, but.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: So that's... [dice rolling] It does,
Seeker: uh, 12 damage with its slam.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: Now Seeker should move probably.
Seeker: I, I only have 30 moves, so I can go like,
Seeker: I don't know, back over here, I guess.
Kenzo: That's pretty good.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Minions-
Unknown: Okay
Delwath: ... how many minions die if they fail saves?
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: Okay.
Kenzo: Oh, you're gonna do like radiance or something?
Unknown: No, I'm not. Tilly.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Okay.
Unknown: Uh, that ends Seeker's turn. [dice rolling] Tilly's up.
Delwath: Tilly is gonna cast-
Unknown: Come on, Tilly
Delwath: ... uh, so there's no point in... Is there any point...
Delwath: Oh, it's still worth up casting, 'cause if they make the save, they get-
DM: If they make the save, you have to pass their hit points.
Delwath: Tilly is gonna cast a second level thunder wave to clear out the mess.
DM: Oh, okay. Awesome.
Delwath: Exactly. [dice rolling] DC 17 con save.
DM: Okay. There's one, two, three-
Unknown: Good call
DM: ... four, five, six around there.
DM: Um, con?
Delwath: DC 17 con.
DM: Okay, so they have-
Wellby: Does it reach the closest chimeran?
Delwath: It's 15 feet.
DM: No, that's not gonna reach the chimeras.
Unknown: So it's not.
DM: [dice rolling] Yeah, it's plus, only plus two.
DM: Um,
DM: one
DM: succeeds. [dice rolling] And-
Delwath: Five damage for the one that succeeds.
DM: Okay. So one... Oh, sorry.
DM: Tilly starts her turn, when she starts her turn surrounded by these, she takes four points of acid damage.
Delwath: Uh, is that... She's resistant-
DM: Is it to the end?
Delwath: ... until the end, until the end of your next turn for sure.
Unknown: Then she takes two points.
DM: She takes nine points total.
DM: Two points plus another seven from the globule.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: And she kills all but one of these.
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: Nice.
Seeker: Amazing.
Delwath: Oh, no, start of your next turn.
DM: Sorry, she's not resistant, so she takes 11 points of acid damage.
Unknown: Totally s-
DM: Sorry, 14 points of acid damage
Seeker: ... tied his Tilly turn. We had a little moment, but.
Delwath: Okay. And there's one left.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Breath weapon's scary.
Unknown: [laughs] It's scary.
Delwath: She's flying, so she's gonna fly-
DM: We'd like you to review. She's got a 60 foot fly speed.
DM: She might want to just get out of there.
Delwath: Yeah. She doesn't actually care about the attack of opportunity.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: She's gonna go-
DM: One minion can't rip one
Unknown: ... to, let's see
DM: One, two, three
Kenzo: Uh, don't we like kinda wanna spread 'em out a little bit more and attack it?
Delwath: Yeah, I wanna get away, but I don't...
Delwath: She doesn't wanna fight towards the chimeras
Kenzo: How about over here? Up this way.
DM: If you can just like back that way.
Delwath: Yeah. One, two, three, four, five [sneezes] six.
DM: Like there. Okay, that ends Tilly's turn.
DM: Um, the chimeras are up.
Wellby: So first, the chimera-
DM: Reaction
Wellby: ... that I hit rolls a DC 13 CON save against the-
DM: Fire
Wellby: Yep.
DM: You hit the one... You hit three?
Wellby: Three.
DM: Um,
DM: that fails.
Wellby: Awesome. That is eight plus six is 14 points of fire damage, and it's still on fire.
DM: Okay.
DM: Um,
DM: sorry, that was... Which chimera was that?
DM: Four?
Unknown: Chimera three.
Wellby: Three.
DM: Three.
Unknown: Four's not been touched.
Wellby: Four's not been touched.
DM: Four's, four's been hit, was hit by...
DM: It's CON saving throw.
Unknown: Oh, the cone. Yeah
DM: ... was hit by the ice thing.
Kenzo: That's the ice thing. Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: okay. So two is now just dashing to get onto the battlefield.
DM: these ones... So how...
DM: You're 45 feet up.
DM: Okay, they've got a 60 foot fly, so this one's gonna close onto you.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: And-
Wellby: I don't think it can close onto me this round
DM: ... it's two over and four up.
DM: It's 20 and 40, and the hypotenuse is shorter than the two sides.
Wellby: Yeah, but it started its turn two squares into the map.
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: It s- it started with an extra 20 feet of move when it came-
Unknown: It was on the map
Wellby: ...
Wellby: onto the map.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Oh, if it's here, then it's like one, two, third...
DM: Well, it's still two 'cause of diagonal movement.
DM: We always just count that as-
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: I think it can close on you.
Wellby: Sure.
Unknown: Funny.
DM: The prone one can't because it...
DM: This one can't 'cause it's too far away.
Wellby: But as it's moving, I shoot it.
DM: Yes.
Seeker: [laughs] Naturally.
Wellby: And that is a 21.
DM: Okay. That hits.
Wellby: Uh, somebody's a lower 'cause I'm low on D6s.
Unknown: Yeah. The D6 has got a bit scattered.
DM: Well, this was-
Kenzo: Well, they're all... They're being used to indicate-
Wellby: It's terrible
Unknown: ... people, people flying and stuff
Wellby: Um, just 25
Unknown: ... their structural.
DM: Okay.
DM: Um, both chimera two and chimera three are looking pretty badly hurt,
DM: so that's the two non-prone ones.
DM: Oh, sorry. The chimera two was the prone one.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, so chimera three is nearly dead.
DM: That's the one that just flew up to you.
DM: Um, chimera four is unhurt.
DM: The prone one is bloodied.
DM: Um, and the chimera now is going to-
Kenzo: Four's not unhurt. It's g- just got that little bit ice damage.
DM: Uh,
DM: four is a little bit hurt-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... but not very badly.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: It's going to make, um,
DM: two... It's gonna make three bite attacks.
DM: Um,
DM: uh, the first...
DM: Well, first it's gonna make two bite attacks against Wellby.
DM: Um, that's gonna be a 14 and a 20.
Wellby: Both miss 'cause I have plus two AC from haste.
DM: Ah, okay.
DM: [laughs] Sweet.
DM: And then-
Delwath: 20 AC's nice, isn't it?
DM: Um...
Wellby: Yes.
DM: [laughs] Uh, it is going to use its, um, roar.
DM: You must make a wisdom saving throw or be frightened.
Wellby: Wisdom saving throw-
Unknown: Nope
Wellby: ... is, uh, 14, which is not great and probably doesn't beat it.
DM: You are frightened.
Delwath: Do you have bardic inspiration?
Wellby: Do I have bardic inspiration?
Unknown: You do. You do.
Wellby: Did you give it to me?
Kenzo: I gave him a little.
DM: You haven't used it yet, have you?
Unknown: I don't think he has.
Wellby: I don't think I've used it.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Who's used inspiration?
DM: You have?
Delwath: No, I used-
DM: Tilly
Delwath: ... I used favor the gods. Tilly used inspiration.
DM: Tilly used inspiration.
Delwath: I used favor the gods.
Wellby: All right. That's 24 to save.
DM: [laughs] That succeeds. Wait, you only roll one.
Seeker: The original stone con-
Wellby: Uh, I rolled the 10 then
Delwath: [laughs] Okay. What was the other one?
Wellby: A three.
DM: Just roll it again.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: The original stone construct had one-
DM: No.
Unknown: Oh, wow.
DM: You succeed. You were only off by two anyway.
DM: You were not-
Kenzo: You used your heroic.
Wellby: Do I get anything in addition?
DM: You get nine temporary hit points.
Unknown: Oh, you can inspire yourself.
Delwath: Tilly gets temporary hit points.
DM: What did you roll?
Delwath: Uh, like a four.
DM: Okay. Give her... Just give her four...
DM: Well, yeah, just give her four temporary hit points.
Delwath: No, I'm just gonna give her four hit points back.
DM: Yeah, yeah, that makes sense. Okay.
DM: Um, and then it's going to, um...
DM: It... Does it care about those minions?
Delwath: The chimera?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Die.
Wellby: It has a very low intelligence.
DM: It's just gonna spit fire at you.
DM: Um-
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: This is the fourth thing it's done now.
DM: With so-
Unknown: Collaterally
Wellby: Oh, it has a bunch of heads.
DM: It has three heads and a bonus action.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: so make a dex save.
Delwath: Yeah, what do you care if people spit fire at you?
Unknown: Dodge out of the way.
Wellby: Do I have a ring of fire resist?...
Wellby: I have a ring of fire resistance.
Unknown: You do have a ring of fire resistance.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, and the most you can take is one quarter of the damage.
Wellby: All right. I roll, uh, something over 20.
Wellby: 24.
DM: So you take zero damage.
Unknown: Yeah. You guys-
Wellby: Awesome
Delwath: ... you two laugh in the face of breath weapons.
Delwath: You just dance around.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: Um, and
DM: it's only a, it's only a 10-foot radius, and it's aiming a little off to the side, so I think it's just gonna hit that one minion-
Unknown: It's gonna hit Dimitaur
DM: ... that's closest to you.
Delwath: Oh, yeah. Wait.
DM: What?
Delwath: Did Dimitaur... What happened to Dimitaur?
DM: Dimitaur, he's like...
DM: He's waiting.
Kenzo: He's very excited to act.
DM: He needs the dragon not to be surrounded by people.
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: He's about to hit him with a fireball.
Delwath: Man, he should get meta magic so he gets high, like safe spell.
DM: Um, one minion also dies from the fire, the closest one to you.
DM: Um, that ends that chimera's turn.
DM: This chimera, um, is going to
DM: fly,
DM: um, also going to just fly, dashing, um, to get behind you, closing in on Wellby.
Delwath: Thanks for drawing all the other-
DM: Um-
Unknown: ... people
Wellby: No, no, this is the plan. This is good.
DM: Still has a bonus action-
Kenzo: This actually, this actually... So you're, you're excellent
DM: ... so it's also gonna roar
Wellby: Your axe did-
Wellby: It's also gonna roar
Unknown: ... quite well.
DM: But it dashes, so it can't attack you with its heads.
Unknown: Wisdom save.
DM: Wisdom save.
Wellby: Wisdom save is
Wellby: 17? 17.
DM: That makes it.
Unknown: All right.
DM: Man, that rogue, rogue level 15 ability is pretty good.
Unknown: Are you proficient in all saves?
Wellby: No, but I got wisdom and something else.
DM: Wisdom and intelligence, I think.
Wellby: Yeah. Wisdom, yeah.
DM: That saved you from the Feeble Mind, too.
Unknown: Oh, the Befuddle.
DM: The Befuddle.
Wellby: Although, in fairness, I still can't cast spells [laughs].
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: No, except-
Kenzo: You still can't what?
DM: Uh-
Unknown: Cast spells
DM: ... activating your armor is a magic action.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
DM: It made it so you can fly.
Delwath: Okay, okay. Whose turn? I forget the order.
DM: So that ends-
Unknown: This is crazy
DM: ... the chimera's, Milo's turn.
Unknown: The dragon is after Milo.
Unknown: Oh, fuck.
DM: Uh, Dimitaur says, "Get ready."
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Um, Milo's gonna shoot number three.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Who's the closest to death, right?
DM: Number three is very close to death.
DM: That's the one that attacked you.
Kenzo: That's the... This is two. This is thir- This is three.
DM: Three is this one.
Unknown: Three is this one, yeah.
DM: This is two. This is three.
DM: That's four.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: How close to death is two?
DM: Two is, like, just past bloody.
DM: All right.
DM: Three is, like, one strike.
Kenzo: Three. He's gonna take a hit.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, negative 20.
DM: It only has eight hit points left, so three is dead.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: [coughs] That ends-
Unknown: [sighs]
DM: ... Milo's turn. Now it's the dragon's turn.
Unknown: Oh, fuck.
DM: It looks around. It's pissed.
Seeker: So now does it have to make that wisdom saving throw because of the-
DM: Oh, it does. It does.
Kenzo: Yes.
Unknown: It's-
Delwath: It hasn't used a lot of legendary actions.
DM: It used the gobbles.
Unknown: Oh, yeah, it did use the gobble.
DM: Um, that is a...
Seeker: It's against Milo, so it's-
DM: Uh, 25
Seeker: Yeah, so it succeeds.
DM: It is pissed at this light that is messing up all of its darkness actions.
Unknown: Oh, shit.
DM: So it is going to-
Unknown: Oh, no
DM: ... destroy the light.
Wellby: We have a second drift globe.
DM: First-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... it is going to-
Unknown: Another drift globe
DM: ... bite at Delwath.
DM: Um, that's a...
DM: Oh, that's only a 19.
DM: That misses.
DM: That misses. It's gonna slash at you with a claw.
Delwath: Delwath again?
DM: Delwath again. That is a 24.
Delwath: I will cast Shield.
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh, Delwath again. Uh, that's a 30-
Unknown: Battle
DM: ... 2.
Unknown: [laughs] 32.
DM: An attack over 30. Um, wait, sorry.
DM: Delwath is that one right there, the, in the way.
Delwath: No, that's Delwath.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: That's Delwath, okay. So Delwath takes,
DM: um,
DM: 15 points of slashing damage, and it's gonna just shove you out of the way with its claw, moving you 15 feet this way.
Unknown: That's great.
Kenzo: But the ladder is still in front, and then the clay golem, the golem is still on top of him, right?
DM: Yeah, and then it's gonna fly
DM: up.
Kenzo: With the golem?
DM: Yep. Golem on its back,
DM: and land right there.
Kenzo: Do I get an opportunity attack?
DM: No, 'cause y- none of you are within-
Seeker: So it's... And I was. I'm on the-
DM: It pushed. It pushed you.
Kenzo: But I'm with the... I get an attack
DM: Oh, you have the lion guard's claw.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So you're, you get an opportunity attack.
Kenzo: Thank you.
Wellby: The ladder was not in melee with him?
Seeker: The ladder is in melee.
DM: Uh, it-
Kenzo: Yeah, the ladder-
DM: The ladder does as well.
Unknown: So that's-
DM: And it lands on the top of this thing, and you hear Dimitaur-
Unknown: Hold on, hold on, hold on. Let's, let's do this. Let's do-
Kenzo: Yeah, do your opportunity attack
Unknown: ... let's do our opportunity attacks first.
DM: Sure.
Unknown: Crit. Fuck, does this fucking go?
DM: The ladder.
Unknown: The ladder.
Unknown: Let's fucking go ladder.
Wellby: Fucking ladder.
Seeker: So that's, um...
Seeker: So what do I, what do I double? It's a 1d10 plus 5.
Delwath: So roll the d10 twice, two d10.
Unknown: Thank you.
Seeker: S- six, I guess.
Delwath: Plus five, so 11.
Unknown: So 11. All right.
Kenzo: And then opportunity attack with its claw.
Kenzo: That definitely hits.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: So 26, and then I do, uh- So how, how much did the ladder do?
Delwath: 11.
Unknown: Okay. And then I do, uh,
Kenzo: 10, thir- eight, uh, 18.
DM: 18 damage, okay.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Great
DM: ... Dimitaur says, "Now's my chance."
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: He's been holding an action to cast a 7th level fireball from his wand-
Kenzo: Let's go
DM: ... for a long time.
Kenzo: Let's go, Dimitaur.
DM: And you see-
Seeker: Oh, and the stone construct is gonna get hit by it.
DM: Oh.
Unknown: That's fine.
DM: Yeah, well.
Unknown: Well.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: The dragon is big enough. Can't he just get the left, right side of the dragon?
DM: Oh, yeah, he can hit... He can just hit it.
DM: He aims it right below the dragon.
Unknown: There's a huge empty space right here.
DM: So the stone golem is shielded-
Unknown: By the body of the dragon
DM: ... by the body of the dragon from...
DM: Uh, so that is four-
Unknown: 12
DM: ... 12 D6.
DM: Somebody want to roll for damage on that?
Unknown: 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13.
DM: It's a 12 D6es.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: All right. Let's go, Dimitaur.
DM: Does it fall?
Unknown: This is 12?
DM: Uh, I don't think so.
Kenzo: One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine,
Unknown: 10.
Unknown: All right, 11 total.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: That's all of his charges on his wand of fireballs.
Unknown: Yep. Thanks, Dimitaur.
Kenzo: Channeling rise. Visualizing lots of fives and sixes.
Unknown: Let's see.
DM: All right. Not bad.
Delwath: Let's see.
Delwath: Not... But not bad.
Unknown: Okay, 10,
Unknown: 20,
Kenzo: uh, 30,
Unknown: uh,
Kenzo: 35-
DM: 40
Unknown: ... 40, 45.
DM: 45.
Unknown: 45.
DM: Wait.
Unknown: Did I kill it?
Unknown: Didn't kill it.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: But that was, that, that was... We, we appreciated that.
Unknown: It was a good shot, though.
Unknown: Yeah, it was a good shot.
DM: And now it's gonna use its object interaction to knock one of the two drift globes.
DM: It can't knock both without using an action.
DM: Just
DM: use a giant claw to just knock it,
DM: toss, rolling down into that temple right there.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So the light radius reduces to 300 feet.
Seeker: 300. So it's all the way at the top of the tower, which is how high?
DM: It's like, it's like-
Unknown: I mean, we were flying.
DM: Oh. You were flying pretty high.
Kenzo: Wait, the lion guard's claw, I also get push.
Kenzo: I can push him 15 feet.
DM: He's too big.
Unknown: Ah.
Unknown: Can't push gargantuan creatures.
Unknown: Mm-mm.
DM: You're o- you're only large. You need to be huge to push.
Unknown: Yeah. Okay. Probably need another push on-
DM: All right. Who's up? So that ends the dragon's turn.
DM: So Wellby.
Unknown: Ugh.
DM: Wellby is fucking fucked [laughs].
Delwath: Can, can you escape?
Delwath: I mean, you could... Couldn't you bonus action disengage, fly up, and then...
Delwath: I mean, then you don't get sneak attack, though, so.
DM: Well, you get it on the last one you hit from Vax.
Wellby: Who's the last one that I hit?
Unknown: Didn't you... Oh, no.
Wellby: Uh, it was the one that was dead.
Unknown: Oh, it's dead. It's dead. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Shit. Um.
Delwath: Wait. You could hit...
Delwath: Fight the drag- Disengage, fly up, and attack the dragon.
Unknown: You'll get sneak attack. The golem's on his back.
DM: It's true.
Wellby: Yeah, sure. I'll cunning action disengage.
DM: Oh, sorry. You start your turn in front of the minions.
DM: You take, uh, four points of,
DM: um, acid damage.
Wellby: What?
DM: From the little guys? Um, because they're all, like, a- dripping with acid and they're, like, spitting it across among them.
Wellby: Oh.
DM: And so you're just caught in the crossfire.
Delwath: He's fine. That's Tilly. She...
Delwath: Yeah, she's fine. Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Um,
Wellby: all right. Cool, cool, cool.
Wellby: I'll cunning action disengage.
Unknown: Nice.
Wellby: I'll fly up 90 feet.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Uh, which is great because then they can't attack me next round.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Although maybe they all swarm to you, and that's not good.
Delwath: Nah, it's a... Yeah, take the sneak attack on the dragon.
Delwath: It's okay.
Unknown: Why is it okay? [laughs] Uh.
Unknown: Oh, actually, I gotta think about this for a minute.
Kenzo: Don't, don't we want to be able to, uh, deal, like, 100 points of damage per round against the dragon?
Wellby: I have 127 hit points right now.
Wellby: I can probably withstand a round of being swarmed.
Unknown: Okay. Just...
Unknown: Yeah, sure. Or bait.
Wellby: I mean, it keeps-
Unknown: Fly, fly up and then shoot
Wellby: ... I mean, it keeps everybody else off-
Unknown: Yeah
Wellby: ... of you guys.
Delwath: Yeah. Bait, bait's a good move, too.
Wellby: So I think I'm gonna stay right there.
Wellby: I'm gonna take steady aim at the wounded one.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: And shoot it, and then ready an action to shoot it again.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: They're both wounded, but you mean the one that's badly...
Unknown: That's bloody.
Wellby: One...
Wellby: Fuck. That's a 15 with advantage.
DM: That's the AC.
Wellby: Oh, holy shit.
Unknown: Wow.
Wellby: Okay.
Unknown: Nice.
Wellby: I mean, let's roll some D6s.
Unknown: Thank you for your service. We'll- You're killing that...
Kenzo: You're killing the f- the formerly prone one?
DM: The formerly prone one, yeah.
Wellby: 35 on the formerly prone one.
DM: That's gotta be dead. Okay, that one's looking... That's not quite dead.
DM: It's not dead? The fuck? They have 130 hit points.
Unknown: Wow. [sighs] Okay.
Delwath: You can't create a lower level pact slot than your pact slots, right?
Delwath: No, I can't even create a pact- No. Yeah, okay.
DM: I can't create a pact slot with sorcerer points. Not with sorcerer points, no.
Wellby: All right.
DM: That ends your turn. What your reaction is to?
Wellby: Ready an action to shoot that same one again.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: And I'm just gonna take whatever they decide to do.
DM: Okay. So that ends
DM: Wellby's turn. The dragon...
DM: Oh, you fuck. Oh, that's a legendary action.
DM: Yep. I forgot about that.
DM: Um, is going to, um,
DM: turn shadowy and incorporeal,
DM: gaining resistance to all damage until the start of their next turn.
Unknown: The fuck?
Unknown: Well, it's fair that it gets cool things, too.
Wellby: Wow.
Kenzo: Well, at least we know that. [laughs]
Wellby: Sure. We're like, hey, look.
Unknown: Thanks.
Wellby: Look at that.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: I
Wellby: didn't know dragons could do that.
Delwath: Uh, whose turn? Uh- That was Wender, then...
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo is next. Well, I guess, uh, since I can't attack it, I'm just gonna come over here and kill this.
DM: I mean you can attack it, it's just all your attacks do half damage.
DM: Yeah. Resistance just means damage is cut in half.
Wellby: It means he'll only do, like, 50 points of damage instead of 100.
Delwath: But its dex saving throw is pretty bad, right?
Delwath: Yep. If it failed a save, that would make it fall...
Delwath: Go prone. Would it fall off that?
DM: Right now it's perched on top of the- Yeah ...
Unknown: lighthouse. Mm, grease.
Delwath: If it failed its save with grease, would it fall off the top?
Unknown: Still attack the dragon? It might.
Kenzo: I'm thinking about here to kill this thing and then still attack the dragon probably, huh?
Wellby: This one definitely can't be killed over a round.
DM: It would probably use a legendary resistance to-
Wellby: Yeah
Unknown: ... keep itself from falling.
Wellby: This one still has, like, 130 hit points.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. But still, you're burning a legendary resistance with a personal slot.
Unknown: Yeah. It's a pretty bad trade. Yeah, that's a great trade.
Kenzo: Um, what do you guys think? Still attack the dragon even though that's half damage?
Wellby: You have enough move to go down, grab the drift globe, run back up, put it in, and turn it back on again.
Unknown: Yeah, it takes an, uh, it takes an action to turn it back on.
Unknown: Oh, wait, it's not turned off.
Wellby: Well, that would... It turned off. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: It's not turned off. Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Do you have enough... I also have a drift globe.
Unknown: No, both of them are in there.
DM: Yeah. That's how it could only knock out one.
Unknown: There's two drift globes in there.
Wellby: Were both of the drift globes-
Kenzo: Was my... Was it my drift globe in there? Yeah, your-
Wellby: Okay
Kenzo: ... and Vax's. Oh,
Delwath: okay. I mean, does my spell count as a s- it counts as its leveled spell for emanating light.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, I don't... I wouldn't be as worried, like, I'll be a beacon.
Delwath: You can still see the dragon to fight.
Delwath: I wouldn't waste your action on the restoring the drift globe.
Wellby: All right.
DM: It wouldn't be his action, it would just be his move.
DM: Oh. As your free object interaction to pick it up.
Delwath: Well, I'd waste your move on it.
Wellby: Huh?
Delwath: If you can run ahead-
Wellby: Yeah, dude, I have 100-
Unknown: Move
Wellby: ... I have 160 move.
DM: Well, you'd have to put it back in your next turn.
DM: You can fly down, pick it up, punch him, next turn put it back.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Do that. All right, fine. I'll do that.
Kenzo: So I'll go down over here, pick up the, pick up the drift globe.
Unknown: Well, that might make you a target.
DM: If you're holding the drift globe, it's probably gonna attack you.
Unknown: You should be.
Wellby: Well, it's gonna-
Unknown: No
Wellby: ... attack somebody no matter what.
Delwath: Yeah, that's good because I have almost no hit points right now.
Wellby: It's not gonna not attack anybody.
Unknown: That's fine. It's fine.
Kenzo: Okay. You, you should, uh- So now it takes half damage if, uh, if I hit.
DM: It takes half damage from all your hits.
Unknown: All right. Let's fucking go.
Kenzo: And I don't have advantage.
Wellby: Correct.
Kenzo: No. 20 to hit, right? Yeah.
Unknown: Okay. That hits.
DM: And that, the first attack does- Oh, I forgot to mention, the last turn you passed it over to Bloody.
DM: I forget exactly where. Who did?
Unknown: Well over Bloody. Which? The dragon.
Kenzo: The dragon. The dragon is? Oh, holy fuck.
DM: I mean, not well over Bloody,
Unknown: but... Uh. I mean, you've done 300 hit points of damage.
Kenzo: It better ... 11. Attack one.
DM: 11. That's, so reduced to half, it's five.
Kenzo: Yep. Attack one. Attack two.
Kenzo: Oh, fuck. I think I miss
Unknown: Um
Delwath: It's 20 AC.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You miss.
Kenzo: That's, that's a miss. 14.
Kenzo: Do I bardic inspiration or do I save that?
Unknown: What if I save that?
DM: No, save that. You have five attacks.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Save it for a six.
Kenzo: That's my first miss. All right.
Kenzo: Third attack. [dice rolling] Natural 20.
Kenzo: Crit. [sighs] Okay, crit.
Kenzo: So I do on the crit [dice rolling] literally like this.
Kenzo: Uh, what is that?
Kenzo: 12, 16, 21.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Hold on, hold on. 21 plus, [dice rolling] uh, plus, uh, 11 is 33, plus 5 is 38.
DM: Yeah, so-
Kenzo: 19
DM: ... 19.
Unknown: All right. Attack-
Wellby: You're still doing some meaningful damage.
Unknown: I am.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Attack number four. [dice rolling] Ooh.
Kenzo: Uh, 19. That misses.
Unknown: Fuck.
DM: That misses, yeah.
Kenzo: And attack number five. [dice rolling] No.
DM: That misses.
Unknown: Damn.
Unknown: Oof.
DM: Distracted by holding the light gl-
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
DM: With your hand.
DM: Well, at least you missed on the round it's invulnerable.
DM: It's resistant.
Unknown: Yes, exactly.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Right, right, right, right. Yeah.
Unknown: Yep. All right. That's all right.
DM: That ends Kenza's turn.
DM: The dragonettes.
DM: You didn't move-
Kenzo: And every time you say... Every time you say that...
Kenzo: Uh, he, he went up. Oh, no, he did not move.
Unknown: No.
DM: You didn't move, right?
Wellby: Who didn't move?
Unknown: You didn't move.
DM: You didn't move. Wellby didn't move.
Unknown: No.
DM: Uh, okay. So-
Kenzo: This is like a good soldier moment.
DM: Yep. Um, the dragonettes, there's what, five of them remaining?
Kenzo: Dude, are any of the fucking other...
Kenzo: Like, nobody's getting any gold right now.
Unknown: Six, six now.
Kenzo: Like, none of the, none of the fucking, like-
DM: Well, you have no idea what's going on outside the radius of darkness.
DM: Maybe they stopped 50 other dragon-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... dragonettes from coming to help.
Wellby: Certainly they will claim to have done so.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
DM: Well, maybe they're just looting the lair right now.
Unknown: We should go over there.
Wellby: No, they would-
Delwath: Nah. [dice rolling] [laughs]
Delwath: They're not that hard to kill. If they loot the lair, we'll just take them in the back.
Unknown: That's, uh, that's true.
Wellby: If they try to loot the lair, the lair will kill them.
Kenzo: Yeah, the lair will kill them.
DM: I feel like that usually.
DM: 27.
Unknown: Kind of a gamble for that.
Wellby: 27.
DM: Uh, it's a hit.
Wellby: Hits me.
DM: So you take 20...
DM: So there, there's five of them by you.
DM: You take, um, 20 points of acid damage.
Wellby: Is this one attack or all of them?
DM: Yeah, one attack. They have minions make a group attack.
Wellby: Okay, okay.
DM: So it's the whole attack, all the minions.
Wellby: Awesome. I don't know if there's gonna be five more of those.
DM: No, no, no.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: That's why they get, like, such a big plus to hit is because you add all their pluses together.
Wellby: Okay.
DM: Um, and you are...
DM: Uh, you have to make a dex saving throw.
Wellby: I have advantage on dex saving throws because [dice rolling]
Unknown: Love that.
Wellby: And that is 20.
DM: You are not coated in acid.
Wellby: That's good.
DM: Um, that ends the minions' turns, but the chimeras
DM: now are both going to...
DM: Wait, are... Did you fail... You didn't fail your frightened save, did you?
Wellby: Did not. It succeeded.
DM: Um,
DM: you're im- so you're now immune to both of their roars till, for the next 24 hours, so they're not gonna waste their time doing that again.
DM: Um, one of them is gonna...
DM: The first one is gonna start by trying to grab you with its lion's mouth and toss you.
DM: [dice rolling] Oh, that's only a 10 to hit.
DM: That misses.
DM: Um, it'll just bite you with the...
DM: Ugh, that's a 15 to hit.
DM: That misses. [dice rolling] That is a 22 to hit.
Wellby: That's a hit.
DM: So you take
DM: five, nine points of piercing damage.
Wellby: Awesome.
DM: Now, the second one is gonna attempt to toss you.
DM: [dice rolling] Um, that is a 22 to hit.
Wellby: That is a hit.
DM: Um, dex or strength save.
Wellby: Ooh.
Wellby: Strength save.
Wellby: [dice rolling] [laughs]
DM: Oof. Not a good save.
DM: [dice rolling]
Wellby: That's a six.
DM: Okay. It throws you, like, 15, 20 feet up, just with its mouth.
Wellby: That's not a bad thing
DM: ... out of the way of the minions and then shoots you with fire.
Wellby: Oh, that's less good.
DM: Make a dex, but it's a dex save, so.
Wellby: All right. Dex save with advantage is 28.
DM: Yeah, you succeed. Um, so you take half da- or you take no damage 'cause you have evasion.
Wellby: It tosses me up 15 feet?
Wellby: Sorry, this is the second one now?
DM: This is the second one.
Wellby: All right. Yeah.
DM: Tosses you up, then-
Wellby: Good
DM: ... drag you back.
Kenzo: Don't you get a reaction now to shoot somebody?
DM: He's using his reaction for haste.
DM: He's not going.
Wellby: Oh, wait, wait. When the second one moves, I shoot it.
Unknown: He can get that reaction-
DM: Okay. Yeah, roll, roll that
Unknown: ... to close with me first.
DM: Roll that. Yeah. [dice rolling]
Wellby: That's a natural 20.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Okay.
Wellby: That is,
Wellby: uh-
Kenzo: That's gonna kill that front one
Wellby: ... surely death, but that's gonna be 17, these-
DM: Yeah, the second one's dead.
Unknown: 46.
Wellby: I rolled terribly. I don't... That's only 51.
DM: Yeah, it's still dead.
Kenzo: This one's dead?
DM: Yep.
Unknown: Awesome.
Delwath: There's only one chimera left.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Plus minions.
Unknown: All right.
DM: So that ends the chimeras' turn.
DM: Uh-
Seeker: Wellby's fighting a entire war up here
DM: ... oh, sorry. I think I skipped [laughs]...
Unknown: This is... I'm good right now
DM: ... sorry, guys. I skipped... I kind of got out of order there.
DM: I moved the... It's okay.
DM: Dalweth, Seeker, and Tilly are all next.
Unknown: All right.
DM: In that order. Dalweth, Seeker, Tilly.
Delwath: How badly hurt is that chimera?
Unknown: Did the dragon-
DM: That chimera is pretty-
Kenzo: The dragon, the dragon is what?
DM: It's-
Wellby: It's only had 14
DM: ... 14 damage, so.
Wellby: You should ignore the chimeras. I'm-
Kenzo: The dragon is what?
Wellby: ... just fine.
Unknown: What's his hit points?
Wellby: It's still at 98 hit points.
Delwath: Well, I was just wondering-
Kenzo: Oh, 'cause the dragon is all health
Delwath: ... it's resistant to all damage.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Is this the turn to do something else?
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Kenzo: I mean, I still did a bunch of damage.
Unknown: That's true. That's true.
Unknown: Half of 100's still 50.
Delwath: Half of 100's still 50.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: I mean, we're not even 300 points-
Unknown: We have a point. We have a point [laughs]
Kenzo: ... we're down, we're down th- like, I did, like, 40 points of damage to the thing.
DM: Um, uh-
Wellby: Dragon. Do the dragon. I don't need it.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: No. Okay, hold on. Uh, I know what I'm gonna do.
Delwath: All right. I'm gonna close with the dragon,
Delwath: just come up behind it.
DM: Yep.
Delwath: And I will attack it.
Kenzo: You're still within 30 feet of me, right?
DM: Well, no, he's already made the sneak attack.
Delwath: I've already made the sneak attack on the-
Unknown: No, you have to make it once. If you succeed once, you are done.
Delwath: Uh, 17 would miss.
DM: Miss, yeah.
Delwath: Uh, should I bardic?
Wellby: Uh, not this round. Not this round.
Delwath: That also misses
Kenzo: It's all right, I missed three times. Save the, save the math
Wellby: I like the flavors right there, though. That it's like misty and incorporeal and-
DM: Misty and incorporeal
Delwath: That also misses. Three misses
DM: ... misty and incorporeal.
DM: Your slashes can't-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... get purchase on it
Delwath: But, but, but I'm gonna cast a spell.
Delwath: Um, Somnatic
Unknown: Static.
DM: Nice, nice.
Delwath: Uh, that is a 20-foot radius, so can I get all the minions and that guy?
DM: Yeah.
DM: Uh, 20-foot radius is four squares.
Unknown: Uh, yeah.
Unknown: 20 foot.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Okay. So I will...
Unknown: Oh,
Delwath: no I can't use two meta magics on the same turn, so I probably shouldn't do that 'cause then...
Delwath: Wait, Wellby's... Is Wellby above them?
Unknown: Wellby's-
Kenzo: Wellby's ab- Wellby got thrown up in the air
Unknown: Wellby's above them
Delwath: Oh, he got thrown 20 feet up.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: So I can get them without hitting Wellby.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Um.
Wellby: Is it a sphere or a cylinder?
Delwath: It's a sphere.
DM: So you-
Kenzo: Totally can
DM: ... yeah, I mean, because of where you put it, yeah
Kenzo: They were all around Wellby.
DM: They were all around Wellby
Kenzo: And then they got thr- Wellby got thrown up.
Delwath: As long as Wellby's even five feet up, I can just put it further down
DM: Well, but it's a sphere so if he's...
DM: But actually he's 20 feet up, so you're pretty-
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah
DM: ... I think you can still get them all.
Delwath: Okay. Uh-
Kenzo: That was perfect to get thrown 20 feet in the air
Delwath: ... that is a-
Wellby: That was the ideal, really
Unknown: It was completely ideal
Delwath: ... yes. So that's two sorcery points, the bonus action.
Unknown: Cast it
Kenzo: You got out of, uh, you got out of, uh, melee with the, the fucking things-
Unknown: And, um-
Unknown: ... and then you didn't get hit with the thing, so
Delwath: ... and, uh, DC 19-
Unknown: Sounds like you had a good turn
Delwath: ... DC 18, uh, int checks, insights.
DM: Well, the chimera can't succeed.
DM: It's got a minus four.
DM: Um,
DM: and the minions...
Seeker: It's not always the case that three heads is better than one.
DM: [laughs] The, the minions-
Unknown: Holy shit. Nice
DM: ... could technically succeed
Unknown: 10,
Unknown: 20.
DM: Ooh, natural 20. Oh, natural 20
Delwath: How many hit points do they have?
DM: Uh, it's probably not gonna matter
Delwath: It does 10, 20,
Delwath: 33 points of eight...
Delwath: No, wait 28.
DM: They have 18 hit points
Delwath: It does 32 da- uh,
Delwath: 10, 20, uh, 10, 20-
Wellby: Yeah
Delwath: ... 28, 29.
Delwath: It does 32. Ah, that's not quite enough
DM: So that two of them survive with two hit points left
Unknown: Okay. Um-
Kenzo: So there's only two left?
DM: There's only two left
Delwath: A- and the chimera has D6, um, minus on all of its-
DM: Yeah, so it ha-
Unknown: ... tackles and
DM: ... it's 32 damage, so the chimera takes 32.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Nice.
Unknown: Nice. Great.
DM: And it's minus D6.
Delwath: All right. Tilly's turn?
DM: Tilly's, uh, Seeker and then Tilly in either order.
DM: Okay
DM: And Seeker is Seeker, golem, ladder.
Seeker: Yes. Um,
Seeker: I could hit that chimera with a catapult.
DM: That's a good idea
Seeker: Actually, can I? What's the range on that?
Unknown: Um-
DM: I mean, you could move
Seeker: Oh, the range is 60, actually.
DM: That's six squares.
Wellby: It's like 11-ish squares.
Wellby: 10, 11
Seeker: So if I, I can move as far as here, that would be one, two, three, four, five, s- oh.
Seeker: So actually I cannot hit it with the catapult.
Kenzo: Wait. You're... Where are you? Oh, you're back there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. I'm back there.
Kenzo: You could hit the dragon with it. Oh, right.
Unknown: No, you can't hit the dragon.
DM: Um, by the way, you do notice on Seeker's turn the dragon, despite being distracted by the lights, is puffing in
DM: its chest.
Kenzo: Oh, fuck. Breath weapon.
Seeker: Oh, God.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: well, okay. I will, I will hit the...
Unknown: [banging]
Unknown: What was that noise? Huh.
Wellby: It's the house shifting.
Unknown: Um.
Wellby: Tenure.
Kenzo: Dragon puffing its chest.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: I mean, if I were the dragon... Well, I guess the golem's on its back, so it would probably go someplace secure and try to hit all of us like this.
Unknown: Um, and the breath-
Delwath: Wait. Is this, this dragon not immune to restraint, is it?
DM: Nope
Seeker: The breath weapon's damage type was-
DM: Necrotic and acid
Unknown: And acid, yeah.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: all right. I will hit the dragon with a catapult at,
Seeker: uh, fifth level.
Kenzo: That's Milo, right?
Unknown: Mm-hmm
DM: That's Milo, yeah
Seeker: But I will use my final-
Kenzo: So right now he's probably gonna like go here and try to hit us all like that
Seeker: ... glove charge-
Kenzo: You're fucking safe
Seeker: ... to use the earth-
DM: Milo's turn is after Tilly's, so Milo could move
Unknown: Milo could move
Unknown: All right.
Seeker: So I cast a fifth level catapult with the earth elemental.
DM: Okay
Unknown: We'll get opportunity, that's-
Unknown: Um, so that's-
Delwath: I mean, I'll die if I get hit by the breath again.
Delwath: Oh, but Tilly could heal me
Seeker: ... a dex save.
Unknown: You got a good barbarian in pocket
Unknown: DC 18.
Unknown: Well, I'm at a hit point, one.
Unknown: Hmm?
DM: As a, uh, who?
DM: On the dragon?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: DC what?
Unknown: 18.
DM: Um, that is not good.
Seeker: So it's-
DM: That's a...
DM: Yeah, that's a, that's like a 12
Seeker: So 78 and then I'm just gonna-
Delwath: It's not using legendary resistance.
Delwath: I should remind you.
DM: Not on the, not on just the damage.
DM: It's sa- it saves its legendary resistance for conditions
Seeker: So that's-
DM: It's not... It still has over 100 hit points, so it's not too worried
Seeker: 78, that's 10, 20.
Delwath: Wait. Remind me the initiative, who goes?
Unknown: 33.
DM: It's Tilly, Milo, then the dragon
Unknown: Okay
Seeker: Uh, so that's 33.
DM: Okay
Seeker: And it takes half of that.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: No, it failed.
Seeker: No, but the-
DM: Oh, it takes half of that. Yeah. The shadowing
Unknown: Yeah. The shadowing. Yeah
Seeker: 'Cause of the shadowing.
Seeker: So 16.
DM: So 16
Seeker: Um, and then I will be, because of the earth elemental charge on the glove, immune to-
DM: That still puts it under 100 hit points.
Unknown: Um-
Seeker: Just barely
Seeker: ... is the necrotic or the acid worse?
Seeker: Oh, definitely-
Wellby: Acid. There's a breath weapon spell
Seeker: ... do the acid. Yeah.
DM: Oh, yeah
Wellby: Breath weapon
Unknown: And then-
DM: Oh, and you still take damage from the athach globule
Seeker: ... before that, which is 14
DM: Yeah. 14
Seeker: Um, okay. So now it is
Seeker: ladder, which will just make its attack
Seeker: It fails.
Seeker: And then the stone construct makes its four attacks
DM: Four attacks, yep.
Kenzo: Hell yeah.
Unknown: Um...
Unknown: I mean, it still has res- its resistance doesn't go away
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Not till it's started its turn.
Unknown: Um... [dice rolling]
Kenzo: Hell yeah. They all hit.
Unknown: I think put this...
Unknown: Plus 10, right?
DM: They all hit.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: It has 20 AC [clapping] so they all hit.
DM: Good job, Stone Giant.
Unknown: Let's go. Let's go.
DM: Stone Golem.
Kenzo: So that's, um...
Kenzo: Stone Golem breaking our, our...
Seeker: Each of those is a D8 plus 12.
DM: Oh, that's a good plus.
DM: Plus 12? That's a lot.
DM: Oh, 'cause you cast it at eighth level.
Unknown: I did, yeah. [laughs]
DM: [laughs] Seeker, Seeker wants to get in [dice rolling] this baby competition here.
DM: Oh, yeah.
Seeker: Oh, that's a good roll.
Seeker: That's, um, 16-
Seeker: 26 plus...
DM: 48
Seeker: ... 48. [laughs]
DM: Right, so it's 13 plus 24.
DM: It's getting done.
Seeker: But still that's... Yeah.
Kenzo: That's great.
Seeker: 37, yeah.
Unknown: That's great.
DM: All right.
Unknown: Good job-
Unknown: Tilly
Seeker: ... stone construct.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Tilly and then Milo.
DM: And then the dragon.
Delwath: Okay. Tilly is going to...
Kenzo: It's gonna breath weapon again.
Seeker: Oh, and I can move.
Delwath: It... Yeah. And it can-
Seeker: Should I just step back inside here maybe?
Kenzo: Yeah, you should step back. Yeah.
Delwath: Unfortunately it's gonna be able-
Unknown: Watch your
Delwath: ... it can move about and breath weapon.
Kenzo: It's gonna breath weapon me and you.
Delwath: Yeah. And I only have 40 hit points.
Kenzo: Do we get opportunity attacks on it? We do.
Delwath: If it moves.
DM: If it moves.
Delwath: It can't breath weapon both of us-
DM: Without moving
Delwath: ... without moving.
Kenzo: Yeah. Or it might just go for me.
Delwath: Tilly... I'm gonna tell Tilly I could really use healing.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: One, two, three, four...
Delwath: Oh, she has a 60-
DM: 60-foot fly speed
Delwath: ... five.
Unknown: One, two, three, four, five.
Delwath: Okay.
Delwath: So, uh, let's see.
Delwath: A 3rd level healing word.
Delwath: She has 21 damage.
Kenzo: I mean, it might just go all in on a breath weapon on me.
Delwath: That's a... I should be able to survive a breath weapon hopefully with that.
Delwath: Um, I still have my bardic in- I did not use my bardic inspiration yet, so.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: it... Did the temp hit points come before the saving game?
DM: N- no. If you're knocked unconscious by the, the save, the temp hit points can't help you.
Delwath: And then Tilly can still use her action
Delwath: to cast a cantrip I guess is the best thing she can do.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: She will cast, uh-
Kenzo: There's still like one minion over here randomly, by the way.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: Oh, I forgot about that minion.
DM: Let's just say he closed with...
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Yeah, why not?
Unknown: It's all good.
Unknown: Right? Uh...
Seeker: On average,
Seeker: [laughs] creatures in this battle are closing in death.
Delwath: Um, ray of frost against the chimera.
DM: To the dragon. To the dragon.
Delwath: Nah, ray of frost against the dragon.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: Everything on the dragon.
Unknown: Everything on the dragon. The dragon's almost-
Delwath: Plus nine. 11 or better.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Oh. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: That's actually a decent amount of damage.
Unknown: Yeah, 48.
Delwath: I mean, it still has resistance, but...
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: We're, we're...
Kenzo: We just need to survive this, this breath weapon
Delwath: ... 10, 16, 21.
Kenzo: That's another 10.
DM: So that's another 10.
DM: Yeah. It... Basically if you survive the breath weapon you should be able to kill it.
Unknown: All right.
Wellby: Milo's up?
DM: Milo's up.
Wellby: He's gonna move one, two...
Wellby: And telling action, move-
DM: Okay
Wellby: ... two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
Wellby: And then he's going to-
Unknown: He should shoot the dragon
Wellby: ... shoot the dragon.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Fuck yeah, let's go. [dice rolling]
Wellby: He... That is a...
Wellby: What is that?
DM: Pretty good roll.
Wellby: It's not good enough. Rolled a four.
DM: No, that's not good enough.
Unknown: That is-
Wellby: 14. But, uh-
DM: He's got bardic
Wellby: ... he's got heroic.
DM: He doesn't have, he doesn't have bardic.
Unknown: Oh, he doesn't have bardic.
Wellby: But he has heroic.
DM: He has heroic.
Wellby: He's gonna use his heroic.
Wellby: [dice rolling] And then
Wellby: he's gonna...
Unknown: That hits.
DM: Yes. [laughs]
Wellby: Yeah. All right. That is, uh,
Wellby: 66 plus something.
Wellby: All right, that's 27 plus 5 is 32, is 16 then.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, we're, we're, we're light.
Kenzo: We're... The dragon is very fucked up.
Seeker: We're money.
Kenzo: Yeah, when the dragon is very fucked up.
DM: Okay.
DM: The dragon,
DM: puffing up its chest,
DM: is going to
DM: first of all kick this drift globe with its free object interaction, rolling down to there.
DM: So the
DM: light goes out from the-
Delwath: But Kenzo's still holding it
DM: ... Kenzo is still holding some.
Delwath: There's 40 foot light from me and s- 120 foot light from Kenzo.
DM: Yes. But it's just Kenzo as a glowing beacon now in the darkness.
DM: [laughs] And it's g-
Delwath: And Delwath
DM: ... And Delwath is a glowing beacon in the darkness.
DM: And it's gonna fly.
Unknown: Can we... Are we both-
Kenzo: We're both gonna get opportunity attacks
DM: ... still both get opportunities.
Unknown: But if I, if I upright-
Wellby: Stone Golem, is it incorporeal still or no?
DM: It, uh, nope. Start of his turn it's not incorporeal.
DM: But if you use your reaction-
Delwath: I know, I know, I know, I know
Seeker: ... Oh, it, [laughs] it has to make a wisdom save again.
DM: Oh.
Unknown: It's an easy one for it. It is DC 18.
DM: Yeah, it's definitely gonna use a leg-
DM: I wonder if it-
DM: It needs its... It's definitely using a...
DM: Ooh.
DM: What is the to- what is it?
Seeker: 18.
DM: Oh, no, it succeeds.
Unknown: Okay. [laughs]
DM: It would've used a legendary resistance on that though.
Seeker: That's the stony lethargy.
DM: So you guys decide-
Delwath: Well, can Kenzo... Can I see if Kenzo does a ton of damage before I decide?
DM: Yeah. Kenzo can go first.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So it flies straight up.
Kenzo: Hold on, hold on. But if I, if I, I, if I use my opportunity attack then does that impact-
Unknown: You can't use your reaction
DM: ... No, no. You can't use your reaction so you can't-
Unknown: Use evasion?
DM: No, no. You can't use your deflect attacks, but it hasn't actually attacked you with attacks yet.
Unknown: Can I-
DM: It's breath weapon
Unknown: ... oh, yeah. D- d-
DM: But if you...
DM: But you get your reaction back on your turn, but if you opportunity attack and then it decides to hit you with a claw or something, you can't deflect it.
Unknown: I see.
DM: It's both your primary reactions.
Kenzo: I see. I see.
Kenzo: I think it's better for me to do that 'cause it's still got three attacks, right?
Kenzo: It's g- it's gonna do-
DM: Well, if it breath weapons it doesn't get its...
Kenzo: Oh, it doesn't have any attacks.
Delwath: It could lege- it might have a legendary.
DM: It might have a legendary attack.
Wellby: I think we wanna pour as much damage as quickly as possible.
Kenzo: Yeah, I'll fucking attack it. Let's go.
Kenzo: I'll attack it. I'll attack it
Delwath: I mean, you still have huge... You don't have to worry about his breath weapon, because you only take half no matter what.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: I'll be fine. [dice rolling] That hits.
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: And that does another [dice rolling] 10 plus one.
Kenzo: Another 16 damage.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: And that's real 16 damage.
DM: That's real 16 damage, yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um, it is going to-
Kenzo: Wait, does the, the golem get an opportunity attack?
DM: Uh, well, the golem's not leaving its, its-
Unknown: No.
DM: No.
Unknown: Okay, yeah.
DM: Because it has to be within its reach.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: But-
Delwath: I'm gonna save my reaction
DM: ... it's gonna try and flip over and dump the golem onto the
DM: tower,
DM: which I think is a strength...
DM: Just make a strength check for the golem.
DM: What is its strength stat?
Kenzo: Oh, uh, probably very strong.
DM: It's probably pretty strong.
Unknown: 18.
DM: Okay, so roll a D20 plus-
Unknown: Four
DM: ... four.
DM: [dice rolling] It was a 15, and it stays on.
Seeker: 17.
DM: Okay, so it holds on.
DM: The golem's holding on upside down, its arm wrapped around the wings of the dragon as it turns upside down in the air, tries to dump it off, but then flies up
DM: like this. The ladder can also get an opportunity attack.
DM: The ladder's right there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: And where you're like in...
DM: You're there. Okay.
Seeker: Ladder's opportunity [dice rolling] attack is a 25.
Unknown: That hits.
DM: Okay, that hits.
Seeker: So that's [dice rolling]... Let's see, D10 plus five.
Kenzo: Yeah, you're so close to killing it.
Unknown: [dice rolling] Is the ladder gonna kill it?
Seeker: That's a nine.
DM: No.
DM: Nine damage?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: All right.
DM: And breath weapon is gonna hit Kenzo, Delwath, and the ladder.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Ladder.
DM: Make your dex save.
Unknown: Seeker-
Unknown: Do I-
Delwath: ... do you take damage? [laughs]
Seeker: Why, why would I? [laughs] I'm currently covered with a shiny chest to protect me.
Kenzo: [dice rolling] 27.
Delwath: Oh, I'm gonna use Heroic Inspiration.
Kenzo: Yeah, you do.
DM: Okay. You haven't already used it?
Unknown: No.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Oh. [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Fuck yeah.
Unknown: So wait.
Unknown: Oh.
Seeker: So the... And the ladder needs to roll a save as well?
Unknown: Uh, is a 22 good enough?
DM: Uh, 22 is the DC.
Unknown: What, what-
Delwath: I mean, I still have Heroic Inspiration.
Delwath: I bardic, too.
Seeker: Sorry, what's the save?
DM: It's a 22 dex save.
Seeker: A dex save.
Unknown: And the ladder-
Delwath: 22. [laughs] I can only beat it by rolling a 20.
DM: The ladder has plus two.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: You got it.
Seeker: The ladder, same, only has plus two, so it needs a 20.
Seeker: [dice rolling] No.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Okay, so that's, um-
Unknown: Ladder's going down
DM: ... 42-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... plus 37.
Unknown: Yeah, the ladder's down.
DM: Okay, the-
Unknown: Wow
DM: ... 79 total damage, um, half on the success.
DM: Um-
Delwath: Which one's the acid?
DM: 37 acid.
Wellby: And zero.
DM: Zero for Kenzo.
Delwath: So wait, hold on. How much total damage was it?
Wellby: Crazy.
DM: 79 total.
Unknown: So 40?
DM: So 40, half.
DM: You would save yourself eight damage with
DM: your reaction.
Delwath: Ah. I should have attacked it.
Delwath: Oh, well. Uh, I'm gonna save myself eight damage.
DM: Okay. And it's moving back, so it, it moves, it moves up,
DM: like, it... Just, like,
DM: a tiny bit so it can get past you, and then it's moving back so that it's gonna end.
DM: Uh, it shoots its breath weapon, and then it's gonna keep moving.
DM: It shoots its breath weapon from here.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: And then it's gonna keep moving a total of one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, 80 feet.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Is it running away?
Delwath: Wait, Kenzo, how much damage was it total?
Delwath: You said it was 40, but I would save eight.
Unknown: Total.
Delwath: So 32 total?
DM: 32 total.
Kenzo: Is it running away?
DM: Uh, it doesn't look like it's running away.
DM: It looks like it's, like, repositioning.
Wellby: How many feet away from you is it?
Wellby: It's still in the glow of you, right?
DM: It's trying to get out of the light is what it looks like.
Wellby: But currently it is still in the glow of-
Delwath: No, it's only 40 from me.
Unknown: Why would you think it's in the glow of you?
DM: It's in the darkness now.
Delwath: But if I drop the drift globe into the thing.
Delwath: No, it's not. It's in dim light.
DM: Oh, it's in dim light from the-
Delwath: Dim light from the drift globe
DM: ... um, but...
DM: Ah, except there's a line.
DM: Through the dim light of the drift globe, there's a line of darkness.
DM: Where does the dr- It's...
Unknown: Sorry, it's 60 feet each?
Delwath: 60 foot, yeah.
DM: 45, 60. Okay, so basically right here
DM: is dark.
DM: Pure black darkness.
Delwath: Is the dragon inside that? Okay.
DM: The dragon is inside that.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: The dragon is completely contained within a line of darkness?
DM: Completely contained within a line of pure darkness.
DM: Turns dim light into darkness.
Seeker: So it does... Okay, yeah.
Unknown: Well.
Wellby: Where are you in the initiative order?
DM: And that ends its turn.
Kenzo: Uh, second after you.
DM: Wellby is next.
Wellby: And I'm gonna hold my action until you reactivate the drift globe in the, in the this guy, on the theory that that's gonna dispel the darkness, and then I'm taking steady aim at the dragon from
Wellby: where I am.
Unknown: Perfect. Perfect.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: You don't get both haste attacks, though.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: But.
DM: You can't u- you can't do two o- two held actions.
Wellby: That's okay. That's worth it.
DM: But you can-
Delwath: Why don't you attack the chimera?
DM: You can still attack the chimera and hold your action for the dragon.
Wellby: Oh, I can do that.
Wellby: I will
Wellby: do that then, but I don't get advantage on the chimera,
Wellby: right?
DM: Uh, no, you... Yeah, you won't get sneak attack on the chimera.
Unknown: Dude cuts.
DM: Uh, what did you hit last time?
Unknown: He is ready.
DM: You didn't hit that, did you?
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Finish him.
Wellby: Uh, wait. Uh-
DM: Yeah, no, you did hit it last time.
DM: You get vexing.
Wellby: Awesome. I'm vexing, and then I'll steady aim on the dragon.
Wellby: [dice rolling] So here comes the first vex attack.
Wellby: It's a 27.
DM: That hits.
Delwath: Wait, so it goes Wellby, Kenzo, chimera.
DM: Wellby, Kenzo-
DM: I'm gonna kill the chimera
DM: ... chimera, Delwath, Seeker, Tilly, Milo.
Wellby: That's-
Unknown: I'm gonna kill the dragon
Wellby: ... 40 on the chimera.
Kenzo: Unless it does something crazy, like heal up to capacity.
DM: Okay. Chimera is, um,
DM: past bloodied now.
Wellby: But reactivate the light, and I'll hit it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Okay. Um, at the end of Wellby's turn-
Unknown: Oh, fuck
Unknown: Um, surrender
DM: Like a surrender.
Kenzo: [laughs] Wait, just, uh, tell that, tell him that we said that [laughs]
DM: What did he say?
Unknown: No, just s- s- Surrender Well- well- well- Surrender or be destroyed [laughs] Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: That's his, that's his favorite thing to say.
DM: Okay. You're, you're there. How high up are you guys flying?
Delwath: We're, like, at equal to the top of the t- we were like- Yeah ...
Delwath: parallel to the top of the tower.
Unknown: Yeah, it's about-
DM: Okay. So like-
Seeker: 50 feet something like that ... we could offer it an, an entry level position on Vindristjarna, you know.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: the dragon? Start, start fresh, you know?
Kenzo: Dude, totally start fresh. Like, why?
Kenzo: Why- why go through all of this, you know?
Unknown: Mm-mm.
Wellby: Yeah, he's gotta go. Gotta rethink his life choices.
Delwath: Oh, the golem's still on it.
DM: Yeah [laughs].
Unknown: The golem is still on it.
Kenzo: Does it influence its move, having a giant fucking golem falling on it?
DM: It's actually pretty small compared to-
Delwath: It keeps making the save Ah, okay.
Unknown: It keeps making the save for the-
DM: And the golem's small compared to the dragon
Kenzo: Relative to the dragon. Yeah, yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: I don't like him with all this, this, these, these...
Unknown: what is all this?
DM: Um-
Unknown: Counting
DM: ... it is going to use its-
Unknown: I know
DM: ... legendary action to create
DM: two pools of black acid.
DM: One
DM: right on the roof here,
DM: one right here.
Unknown: Huh. Fair enough.
DM: There's, like, grasping tendrils claw- crawling out of them.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um-
Delwath: Does anything happen of-
DM: Nothing happens unless you start your turn or move within 30 feet of them.
Kenzo: Oh, great. Perfect.
Delwath: I'm within 30 feet of them.
DM: No-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... you're 50 feet up.
Delwath: Oh, 50 feet up. Okay, got it.
DM: But if you fly to the dragon, that one's on the roof.
Seeker: Yeah. I can't get out of that building.
DM: But Seeker is within 30 feet of that.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: [coughs]
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So that ends the d- dragon's action.
DM: Kenzo is up.
Kenzo: I have 160 move, so I'm gonna grace- artfully get around all of this fucking shit.
Unknown: You're lighting... are you not lighting the way? First I'm lighting...
Kenzo: I, I... okay. First, first Kenzo flies over and even though he's never seen American basketball- [laughs] Um, he s- dunk, does like a reverse dunk.
DM: Okay, that-
Unknown: Drops like, drops smoke
DM: ... reactivates 300 feet of light and dispels the darkness.
Wellby: Okay. So- Does that trigger
Wellby: the held action?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Should.
DM: Do you have advan- oh, 'cause you're steady aiming on it.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Yeah, yeah. Um-
Unknown: Do it
DM: ... steady aim's a bonus action.
DM: You can't hold a bonus action.
DM: Oh, I guess we've been letting you do that the whole time, right?
Unknown: You know, it's about yeah.
DM: So that's fine then.
Unknown: You know, it's about-
Unknown: You're really not supposed to have advantage.
Wellby: That's a 30.
DM: Okay, so it doesn't matter.
DM: You hit.
Delwath: It matched for... oh, no, it doesn't matter for sneak attack 'cause he has an ally.
Unknown: That doesn't... it doesn't matter for sneak attack.
Delwath: Oh. 'Cause the golem-
DM: Golem
Delwath: ... is there. You're right, you're right. The golem's, like, distracting it so you can get its-
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: That's 39 damage.
Unknown: Does it kill it?
DM: Nope.
Wellby: Ah, I was trying to snipe it out from under you.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Man. All right.
Delwath: Yeah, Kenzo deserves the kill. That one's got the last hit.
Kenzo: Kenzo, Kenzo fucking, you know, artfully, like-
DM: Okay. Make a strength saving throw.
Unknown: Who?
DM: You.
Kenzo: Why me? I'm fly- I have 160 move.
Kenzo: I'm flying well over, around it.
DM: Oh, you're flying around it. Okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You're still-
Kenzo: Up and over it. I'm fucking...
Kenzo: I can do the, a whole big ass move.
DM: Yeah. You've got a crazy amount of move.
Kenzo: And I will get over within 15 feet and I'm gonna fuck this guy up.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: [grunts] All right.
Unknown: Uh,
Delwath: okay, here we go. [grunts] [die rolling] 17.
Unknown: 17 misses.
DM: That misses.
Kenzo: Do you still have your- I'm, I'm gonna use my bardic inspiration ...
Delwath: I was gonna say, I think you still have your bardic.
Kenzo: Why not? I do. Uh, it's D12.
Unknown: Here.
Unknown: [die rolling] That hits.
Unknown: 21.
DM: Yep, yep.
Delwath: And you do extra damage, right? You do four extra damage.
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: Okay. [die rolling] So this one is 12, uh, 14, 19, 23.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: First punch, first attack.
DM: Still standing.
Kenzo: Second attack. [die rolling] That definitely hits.
Unknown: [die rolling] And-
Delwath: I like this enlarged Langus claw Kenzo
Kenzo: ... dude, with, with fucking blessings-
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: ... it's pretty, pretty nasty. Oh, this one is quite good.
Kenzo: This is, uh- 20, right? 20.
Unknown: It's gotta be-
DM: Still standing
Delwath: ... almost dead though. It's gotta be, like, next one should kill it ...
Kenzo: that's second attack. I got three more attacks.
Kenzo: Come on, let's go. [die rolling] Right on the nose.
Unknown: Oh man, 14.
DM: That misses. That misses.
Kenzo: Ah, heroic inspiration.
Delwath: Did you already use it? No.
Kenzo: No, what? Oh, you used bardic.
Kenzo: I just used bardic. I just used my bardic.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: And you can only roll, roll one die.
Delwath: Okay.
Delwath: So it's the one from the other one plus.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Yeah. So one plus 10.
Unknown: [die rolling] Damn.
Kenzo: Oh. All right. All right, fourth attack.
Kenzo: [die rolling] That hits.
DM: Big job.
Kenzo: Come on.
DM: This can kill it.
Kenzo: Fucking die. Fucking die. Fucking die.
Unknown: Come on. Fucking die.
Unknown: [die rolling]
DM: That's a lot of damage.
Unknown: That's-
DM: That's gonna kill it, right?
Unknown: Yeah. This is, uh...
Kenzo: what is that? 13, 16, 21.
DM: Yep.
Unknown: Ah.
Unknown: Kenzo flies in.
Unknown: Boo, boo, boo.
Unknown: Fourth attack.
DM: [laughs] You hit it and this scar along its side-
Unknown: Oh, I should have punched its scar.
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... cracks open and it's, like, begins to peel out and suddenly
DM: the sun rises and there's, like,
DM: an entire sunset in a 360 degree circle around you
DM: as the dragon falls, crashes through the roof of the tower,
DM: and lands in the middle of the temple of the Night Queen,
DM: dead.
Kenzo: We forgot to shoot the, uh, shoot the sun spot.
Unknown: The, the spell. We did.
DM: It turned out okay.
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah. You can do the thing.
DM: You, you kind of did for the last one.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. For the last one.
Unknown: Uh- Does Chimera run away? Huh?
DM: Chimera runs away.
Wellby: Uh, well, opportunity attack it.
DM: [laughs] Okay.
Kenzo: Kenzo immediately starts looking around for dragonets.
Unknown: All... where, where is Gresh?
Kenzo: Where is, like, where-
DM: Um-
Wellby: 'Cause all those motherfuckers will start- And then I'm, I'm gonna kill it as it's flying away.
Wellby: Like, there's no way that I don't kill it as it's flying away.
DM: Yeah. It, you kill it as it's flying away.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um, there are, um, you can see what looks like an ongoing battle about three miles away.
Unknown: No way. Okay.
DM: There's about 40 dragonets- That are, seem like they've, like, nearly won,
DM: um,
DM: about against a n- slightly smaller force, maybe 25 dragonets.
DM: Um, and you can't recognize anybody from this distance.
Unknown: Right.
DM: You don't know who's won.
Kenzo: [laughs] Oh, this is gonna be chaos.
Wellby: [laughs] Dimitaur, can you use your booming voice to tell them the dragon's dead?
Kenzo: Or then Dimitaur, can you help figure out, 'cause we're gonna have to do this, you know, he know, Dimitaur knows.
Kenzo: Dimitaur, Dimitaur's gonna be the arbiter of who gets stuff.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: That, that's gonna be the, his, his-
DM: Yes. Dimitaur, there's a, there's a huge booming voice that rings out from the light and it echoes, like, for miles-
Unknown: Oh, fuck yeah, Dimitaur
DM: ... from the-
Unknown: Thank you.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: The dragon is dead.
DM: Meet
DM: at the villa for your rewards
DM: at sunset, which you can see, a sunrise, which you can see is now.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh, Dimitaur. Dimitaur has some, some work to do on being a truly benevolent leader.
Unknown: [laughs] He's like-
Unknown: Yes
Wellby: ... which is now, so, so I'll, I'll see you there.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: As soon as I can get there.
DM: No one go in the lair before us.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: There's probably still traps.
Seeker: Let's make Dimitaur the new emperor of Hkar, I guess.
DM: I mean, he might claim the throne because-
Kenzo: Oh, Dimitaur is gonna be the new-
DM: ... he definitely made The Wizard of the Oz his own
Unknown: ... yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Oh my God.
Kenzo: Dimitaur is for sure the new emperor of the Circular Island.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Which is now only dragonets.
Wellby: The last emperor of Hkar.
Kenzo: He is the last emperor of Hkar.
Unknown: Holy fuck.
Unknown: [laughs] Congratulations.
Kenzo: And he's, and he's gonna take away part of his title.
Kenzo: He can be the freer of the, uh, forever sunset.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: What's else his title?
DM: So
DM: you make your way over the course-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... of the next couple of hours
DM: down
DM: to
DM: the lair.
DM: You manage to deal with all the acid traps that-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... it was pointless to point out 'cause it'd be anti-climactic.
Kenzo: Yeah. Thank you.
DM: Um.
Seeker: That, that was a big fight.
Unknown: That was.
Kenzo: That was crazy.
Kenzo: That was good.
Kenzo: That was really fucking good.
Kenzo: Uh, hey guys, Kenzo did not take any damage that whole fight.
Unknown: Seriously, [laughs] took zero damage that entire fight.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Wait, that's ridiculous.
Kenzo: Kenzo, Kenzo is like a fucking dragon, like, just like fucks up dragon-
Unknown: Dragon slayer
Unknown: ... that, that, that is, that is the shit.
Seeker: Wait, how did you... You were in the path of the breath weapon.
Delwath: Yeah, I, I have a vision.
DM: He saves. He's on the save. He just-
Kenzo: My saves are fucking crazy.
Kenzo: The, the bless was so awesome.
Kenzo: Like, fucking extra D4 on every D20, that was massively helpful.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I mean, wide positioning really helps you a lot against a dragon-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... because, like, it, it can only, it can't get everybody.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Its best move was the surprise when it took out the servants.
Kenzo: Oh, that was very... Yeah, yeah. That's very good.
Kenzo: That was it though, man.
Unknown: That was well fought.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: That was very calm.
DM: So you-
Delwath: How many... You took, like, 50?
Wellby: I... No, I'm 10 points below.
Wellby: I took 25 total.
Unknown: Ah, man.
Wellby: And I have 15 extra hit points.
Seeker: Well, I got the acid blob on me, which, um...
Seeker: Actually it's still there. [laughs] So it kind of hurts, so.
DM: You could kind of clear it off.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: But again, like, the zombies absorbed a ton of damage.
Unknown: Well, Delwath also took 140 points of damage.
DM: Delwath absorbed a lot of damage.
Unknown: How much, how much hit points do you have?
Delwath: Well, I got a heal. I got a 35 point-
Unknown: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... healing word boost.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Wow.
Delwath: Well, now let's see.
Delwath: 30, yeah, like I have 30 hit points left and I got, I had 160...
Delwath: Yeah, I took 130 points of damage.
Seeker: And the stone, initial stone construct got one shotted-
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: By the first breath weapon and the ladder went down.
Unknown: But the-
Wellby: Oh, another ladder for the Hall of Records
DM: ... another ladder dies fighting a dragon.
Unknown: It's tragic.
Unknown: Wow. Wow.
Seeker: That's right.
DM: The ladders don't really-
Wellby: We'll have to recover the little ladder.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: They don't really survive dragons.
Unknown: The next time the ladder's gonna be like, "No."
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: It'll refuse to stay up.
Unknown: "I didn't do that." [laughs]
Unknown: Not a dragon. [laughs]
DM: Anything else-
Unknown: I heard about all these other ladders
DM: ... not a dragon.
Seeker: But the second stone construct didn't get a scratch on it, so.
DM: Well, positioning on the back of the dragon.
DM: I mean, that was probably the right move to begin with is to summon it on its back.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: We forgot to use scatter. We never used scatter.
Unknown: We didn't have to.
Unknown: Well, we didn't have to.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: We didn't have... I was, I thought about it on the turn
Delwath: that the dragon w- had resistance to all damage.
Delwath: I was thinking I could scatter all of the
Unknown: k-
Kenzo: All the minions away
Delwath: ... minions away and I could try and scatter the dragon to move it away from the thing so it couldn't knock out the light.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: But it didn't seem-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... worth it.
Wellby: Repairing the lighthouse was instrumental.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Absolutely.
Unknown: Like-
Unknown: That was, that was massive
Kenzo: ... it would've been a very different fight.
Kenzo: That was massive.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, it would've been very difficult not, without the light.
Kenzo: It turns out this was the precise exact place to fight the dragon.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Like, the best spot on the entire fucking island to fight the dragon.
Seeker: Yes. We had... And Dimitaur's fireball.
Delwath: Dimitaur's fireball helped.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Everybody played a role.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So you make your way through the lair.
Unknown: Dragon treasure. I can't wait.
DM: There's, like, a giant eight lake of acid.
Unknown: Dragon treasure.
Wellby: We'll leave, we'll leave that.
DM: That you just fly over.
Unknown: Dragon treasure.
DM: There's, like, shadowy tendrils and things.
DM: You come to the lair itself with massive acid geysers which have stopped erupting.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: And from the lair you can see into the main, like, the room of the main horde,
DM: and you have never seen anything like this before.
DM: There must be
DM: well over a million coins here.
DM: There's thousands upon thousands of, um, items of jewelry that are all...
DM: It's all laid out like a museum.
DM: It's like-
Unknown: Wow
DM: ... there's, like, one wall that has, like, 400 earrings just hanging on the wall.
Delwath: Holy shit.
DM: There's a, um, there's, like, a, a rock that's been carved into, like, a wavy serpentine circle and there's about
DM: 200 rings just kind of laid out- S- like, c- by color, right?
DM: From like the fancy-
Seeker: It's a very organized hoard.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: It's not just a pile of stuff.
DM: Oh, yeah. She spent like hours and hours every day.
Unknown: She... Years and years.
DM: Years-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... just organizing the hoard. There's necklaces, there's broaches, there's, um, there's a whole wall of holy symbols.
DM: There's...
Unknown: Rubies?
Unknown: Um, well, you'll have to search around a little bit.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Um, there's, uh, about 1,000 lockets of various kinds that are laid out like on the bottom panel of a wall.
DM: Um, and then there's a, a waterf- an waterfall of acid that separates this room from another room.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Uh, Dimension Door?
Wellby: Is there anything magic in this room?
DM: There's nothing magic in this room.
Unknown: Dimension Door?
Unknown: I, I guess we could, uh, we could short rest.
Delwath: I, I guess probably we short-
DM: You would have short-
Delwath: Or I could Prayer of Healing at least.
Kenzo: No, we would have short rested before we decided to come to this part of the dungeon.
Wellby: Dispel Magic on the waterfall?
Unknown: Is that a...
Unknown: Is it a magical effect? It must be an acid.
Kenzo: There's no like natural acid waterfall here.
DM: There's probably no natural acid waterfall here.
Kenzo: Dispel Magic.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: So I'll try Dispel.
DM: Okay. What level?
Seeker: I'd have to look at my-
Unknown: High
Seeker: ... what I've got left here.
Delwath: But I could also just Dimension Door.
Unknown: It's fine.
Delwath: But Seek would have to Dimension Door as well.
Seeker: And, and just turn the switch off on the other side.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: so we leave Dimitaur in charge of the treasure hoard.
Kenzo: I mean, we can't take, obviously, we can't take this with us which is a shame.
Wellby: We can take a lot of it with us though.
Seeker: I could do it at fourth.
DM: Well, the portable hole is pretty full.
DM: You've got the Cloudspinner in there.
Unknown: Yeah, but we-
DM: I mean, you can dump a bunch of coins around her.
Wellby: Right. We can do like all the-
Wellby: And gems
Wellby: ... gems and jewelry and like...
Kenzo: Yeah, the most valuable stuff.
Wellby: Yeah. We can leave the coins.
Seeker: All right, I cast Dispel Magic at fourth level.
DM: Okay. Um,
DM: uh, I'll just say it. Make a, make...
DM: Well, no, that just dispels it.
DM: There's no point. Um,
DM: past the acid waterfall you see this looks like a, the like special room.
DM: Um, wait, where did I, where did I have this written down?
Delwath: We gotta get Ghesh and-
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... Luxune to come in here and like offer-
Kenzo: Yeah, no, we're gonna, we're gonna role play that scene.
Unknown: We're gonna role play-
Wellby: Give them like a coin and they'd be like, "Oh, this is amazing."
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah, we can pick one thing.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Any, any one thing we want.
DM: Um, there are 18
DM: what seem to be particularly valuable or fine items arrayed in a row.
DM: Like sort of... There's like, so there's actually a total of, um...
DM: Oh, I, I lied actually. There are actually a large number of magic things in the other room.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: A large number of magic things.
DM: But they're all common items.
DM: They're like
DM: rings of cleaning.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Or like necklaces of healing.
Kenzo: Ring of cleaning, we could use that on the Vindristjarna.
Wellby: We've got the cleaning stone already.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah. Um,
DM: there are...
DM: 18, 19, 20.
DM: There are 30
DM: pedestals arranged at different heights, um, in the...
DM: I mean, it's all dark, but you know, she could see in the dark.
DM: Arranged at different heights sort of outlining 30 of what seem like her favorite items.
DM: There's, of which 12 are magical.
DM: There's a gold encrusted ceremonial cup.
DM: There's a sapphire and diamond necklace.
DM: There's a small, um, intricately carved marble-
Unknown: Wait, the gold...
Delwath: Okay. Uh, what was the next one?
DM: A small intricately carved-
Delwath: No, after the cup
DM: ... a sapphire and diamond necklace.
DM: There's an intricately carved marble statuette of a dragonette with this incredible detail and tiny little emerald eyes.
Delwath: Which ones are magical?
DM: None of these are magical yet.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: There's a dagger, um, set in a, with a hilt of rubies.
Kenzo: Is there like an Adventian, um, dagger just lying here?
DM: Nope.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um, there's a-
Unknown: 'Cause we know what that is
DM: ... intricately designed silver plate, um, clearly very old, um, with scenes of pastoral human life.
Unknown: There's a elaborately designed-
Unknown: Hkar?
DM: ... scepter made from gold and adorned with sapphires.
Kenzo: Hkar artifact? I mean, this is a, the treasure hoard of a-
DM: Yeah, maybe that's from Hkar.
Kenzo: Yeah, a Hkarian artifact.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: Um.
Kenzo: That would be extremely rare.
Wellby: We should look for like Hkarian coinage too while we're here.
Kenzo: There's just, there's a, there's gotta be a Hkarian somewhere in here.
DM: Um, there is an ornate shield crafted from, um,
DM: steel and featuring, um, vivid colors and a elaborate design that shows like a army of Stoneborn fighting against a demon.
Delwath: You know what we need is we need some magic items to give to the Philosopher's Guild.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Oh, yeah. There's
DM: a fine gold necklace.
Kenzo: I mean, [laughs] we've got plenty of stuff now.
DM: That has, um,
DM: it's made of a, of a gold chain, um, that has three, um,
DM: uh, like teardrops, um, each, uh, set with a diamond.
Kenzo: There needs to be some kind of a communication technology in here so we can stay in touch with Dimitaur at all times 'cause we need to like check in.
Kenzo: 'Cause he's, he's our, he's our, our master of coin, you know?
Kenzo: He's our, uh,
Kenzo: AKA the last emperor of Hkar.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: But also our master of coin.
DM: Um, there is another gold medallion with a, um,
DM: intricate relief, um, depicting a strange city.
Unknown: A strange city.
DM: Um.
Unknown: Strange how?
DM: What's particularly strange about it is it's depicting a city with a bunch of dragonettes flying around.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: It's Hkar.
Unknown: Wow.
Kenzo: Or is it like of the future and it's a picture of them?
DM: Um, there's an imperial signet ring.
Wellby: Of what emperor?
DM: Um, one of the emperor of Imridal, one of the Drankorian empires just before the civil war.
DM: There's a gold ring that's shown that is very intricately designed with two dragonets sort of flying, um,
DM: next to each other, um, with, uh, eyes
DM: of rubies.
DM: There's a gemstone brooch, brooch.
DM: Another... There's two more rings, one with silver and diamonds, one, um, a platinum ring set with an emerald.
DM: There's a coronation crown, an imperial coronation crown.
Kenzo: Ooh, we gotta save that for Dimitar.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Um, there's an enameled, um,
DM: serving platter set with, um, again, uh, depicting a scene of ships sailing, like away from a coast.
Unknown: These are all from Hkar.
DM: Um-
Wellby: If we have time, we should show some to the mirror.
Delwath: Yeah. That's gonna have to be like-
DM: Well, in your six month-
Unknown: In our six month downtime
DM: ... Seeker is making the
DM: fancy magic items.
Delwath: Hey, they can all be here. Even if we don't take them, we can borrow them to show them.
DM: Right. Um, there's a beautiful sword, um, with a, um, hilt inlaid with precious stones.
DM: Um, and there's o- like a flagon.
DM: Like, not like a drinking flagon, but like a, I don't know what the word for it.
DM: It's like a punchbowl. There's some medieval word for it.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Um, engraved with gemstones,
DM: and then the magic items.
Seeker: Oh, those are all just the non-magic items.
DM: None of those are magical.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: there, uh, so
DM: there are
DM: two potions.
DM: Um,
DM: there is a...
DM: Hold on. Sorry. [coughs] I need, I have 12 items.
DM: Um, there is a necklace-
Unknown: Of fireballs
DM: ... um, with seven small rubies on it.
Delwath: Of fireballs.
Unknown: I like it. I like it.
Delwath: We get to re- rectify our mistakes.
DM: Um,
DM: there is, um, there, there are, there's like a, a silk pouch that's been carefully opened, and inside the silk pouch there are five
DM: gems, each of which...
DM: Five like small, like small diamonds, each of which have been painted with an eye on it, like etched and engraved in the stone.
DM: Um,
DM: there are, um,
DM: um, there is a great sword,
DM: um, with a etched design of mountains along the bottom.
DM: [clears throat] There is
DM: a short bow.
Unknown: Um, it's made of, it's, it's made of wood, but it's
DM: quite a strange wood.
DM: It seems to almost be vibrating and humming with some inner energy.
DM: [clears throat] It does not have a bow string.
DM: Um, there is a-
Delwath: Didn't you just get a short bow from...
Delwath: But maybe a better one
DM: ... there is a belt, um, with a buckle that's decorated in dwarven runes like a, like a, um, probably like dragon hide or something like that.
DM: Uh-
Unknown: One, two, three, four, five, six.
DM: That's seven. Okay.
Unknown: I've got a few more on here.
DM: Um,
DM: uh, there is a,
DM: a small
DM: figurine of a s- of a, it's like an emerald figurine of a strange animal that Kenzo recognizes.
DM: Um,
DM: it's a triceratops.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Oh my God.
Wellby: A small figurine of a triceratops?
DM: Yep.
Wellby: Holy fuck. That's gonna be friends with the fly too.
Kenzo: No. Triceratops. I gotta give that back to the fucking, um,
Kenzo: the, the jungle. I fucking like hung out with dinosaurs and trained with them and shit
Kenzo: during my solo.
DM: Um, there is a,
DM: uh...
DM: Where are my notes? I have note- I have more notes.
DM: That's... Um, there is a, um,
DM: what looks like a fine, um,
DM: spri- like a, it looks like diamond dust.
DM: Um, a powder collected like diamond dust.
DM: [sneezes] Um, that's in a very fancy wooden box.
DM: Um-
Unknown: You said there was 12 of them. Should be three more.
DM: Um, and then there's three more items.
DM: That's all I wrote down.
Delwath: Three more cool things.
Delwath: We can each make one up.
DM: Okay.
DM: Um, I can send you the details later.
DM: The only one that you have to know about is the painted eyes.
DM: So you can, you can place an eye anywhere you want,
DM: and it fades invisibly into the wall,
DM: and anytime you want, you can use an action to see out of the eye.
Wellby: Perfect.
Wellby: That's so cool.
Delwath: Asa can put one in-
Unknown: Right here.
Delwath: Yeah. Here?
Delwath: No, in Dimitar's...
Delwath: Not in the lair.
Kenzo: Why not in the lair? Don't we wanna keep track of our shit?
DM: Nobody's gonna wanna live in the ass lair.
Unknown: That's too tricky and yucky.
Kenzo: Yeah, but then the people, people wanna come and...
Kenzo: Oh, just, but can we comm- like what we need is a communication method Dimitaur
Delwath: Yeah, we need a two-way.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Well, he can write messages to you.
Unknown: How?
DM: You can see out of the eye.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: We can't like commune with him, but,
Unknown: um,
Delwath: so let's, let's, um-
DM: Oh, actually let's say
DM: there's another one of the items
Wellby: Sunny stones?
DM: A, a paired bag of mouths.
Kenzo: Paired bag of what?
Wellby: Uh, mouths to go with the eyes.
Unknown: Oh, so we can talk to each other.
Wellby: And ears.
Kenzo: Thank God. Thank you.
DM: No, you don't need to be able to listen.
DM: You can always write.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Well, okay, let's say the... let's say the eyes can also hear.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: So we don't want to show the dragonets this place.
Delwath: We made a deal. Let's just... Let, let Ghesh and-
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah, but um-
Unknown: Let them in.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: No. Everybody except Ghesh and...
Delwath: I keep forgetting her name.
DM: Miragen.
Delwath: Miragen. Ghesh and Miragen get to come-
DM: Inside
Delwath: ... get a tour, right? We're gonna go find them.
Delwath: We're gonna thank them for their help.
DM: I mean, you go out and there's like 200 dragonets.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay. Hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
DM: Dimitaur's like, "Okay.
DM: One at a time."
Kenzo: Wait, hold on. Hold on. Hold on. [laughs] Dimitaur's gonna give a-
DM: They just said it was safe.
Kenzo: [laughs] Hold on. Di- Dimitaur, Dimitaur has to announce himself first.
Unknown: Hold on.
Kenzo: I w- I wrote a whole thing for Dimitaur.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Okay. Can you, can you still do booming voice here?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: As a cantrip.
Kenzo: Does he have a... Does he have like a, you know...
Kenzo: I- is he like the, the son of anything in or is he like the, you know...
Kenzo: What's this like-
DM: I mean, he'd be happy to make up a genealogy.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: Yeah, so he, he's, he's the son of what?
Kenzo: Like, what's some like, like legendary dragonet that like they would know?
DM: Um.
Kenzo: Or would just be like, "Oh my God," like, you know.
Seeker: Son of the legendary father of Dimitaur.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Okay, that's good. [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Okay. Let's go with that.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: Okay. So for... So Dimitaur, Dimitaur announces him- himself.
Kenzo: He fly- and he flies up.
Unknown: "Behold."
Kenzo: [laughs] "It is I, son of the legendary father of Dimitaur.
Kenzo: I am the light giver and the first fire, the devourer of Ra'ghemdros, the last emperor of Hkar, known as the eternal radiance and liberator of the secret sunset, His Highness
Kenzo: Dimitaur."
Kenzo: And he, and he, and he just kinda stands there and waits.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Pauses for applause.
Kenzo: Pauses for applause.
DM: Everybody is slow, but then-
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: ... they start clapping.
Unknown: Slow clapping.
DM: And then like the voice comes out, "Where's our treasure?"
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: "You promised us gold."
Unknown: Okay.
DM: "Bring it out."
Kenzo: All right. Well, now, now we, we can, we can take to Dimitaur and then, uh, we, we get Gresh and, uh-
Delwath: So Dimitaur, Ghesh, and Magin- M- Maged-
DM: Miragen
Delwath: We're gonna... Those three only can come in first.
Unknown: Yeah. Those three can.
DM: Dimitaur is like, "I will check it out for you."
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: "Just be patient." There's like more flying in
DM: like every minute.
Unknown: Flying into the thing?
DM: No, no. Flying to gather around him.
Unknown: Oh, to ga- yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: There's gonna be like 500 dragonets here by the time you come out.
Unknown: Great.
Delwath: Yeah, that's like almost the whole population.
DM: That's almost the whole population.
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: Fine.
Delwath: We have to come up with a little quiz, like-
Kenzo: Hmm? Oh, if, if, if they bought, if they bought our-
Delwath: Like a little quiz, right? Like, like
Delwath: what happened at the battle?
Unknown: I mean, you don't actually know what happened at the battle.
Unknown: No. We'll ask Ghesh.
Kenzo: Yeah. Ghesh, what, what happened?
DM: Uh, we won. You didn't see?
Kenzo: No. Did you, did you see what we were doing?
Kenzo: We were killing the dragon.
DM: It was... I mean, I saw the glowing light.
Kenzo: Yeah, you could see our whole battle.
Delwath: It was all bright and lit up.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It was awesome.
Kenzo: Yeah. You saw me punching the thing?
DM: Well, I was a little far away.
Kenzo: Ah, you missed it. It was great.
Wellby: I saw you punch the thing. Good job.
Unknown: I mean, it was great.
Unknown: So
Kenzo: you guys wanna see the treasure?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: We, uh, we f- we, uh, you know, kind of slowly get the...
Kenzo: Uh, I guess how do we... Do we turn off the acid water first?
Delwath: Yeah, we just thought might-
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: We turned it off.
Seeker: It's gone, yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, we, uh, we, we bring them into the room, and then, you know, what's, what's their, what's their reaction?
Kenzo: What's Dimitaur into? [laughs]
DM: Dimitaur's like-
Wellby: Money signs
DM: ... "I'll take the throne."
DM: And then he's like, "I am the king.
DM: Wait, no, that's not right. Let's try."
DM: He goes and he walks around a little bit.
DM: Um, "I am the throne of Hka- no.
DM: What should we be? Emperor?
DM: That sounds a little, you know..."
Unknown: Protector.
DM: "I am the protector of Hkar."
DM: I like that one. "This throne,
DM: the voice of the th- man, the gods.
DM: There's something about the gods.
DM: I'll, I'll figure it out."
Unknown: I say just work on it. Keep working, keep working on it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Keep working on it. You'll, you'll get it.
Unknown: You'll get it.
DM: I need something to sit on the throne.
DM: What about your, uh...
DM: What about your golem? Can you leave that behind?
Seeker: Oh, it's, it's gonna fade away pretty soon unfortunately.
DM: Oh, that's too bad.
Kenzo: You can sit on it. Why can't you sit on it?
DM: [sighs]
Wellby: It's a little statue of you.
DM: Hmm?
Wellby: It's just a little statue of you.
Unknown: We, we could... No?
DM: Like little or like-
Wellby: No, it's the... How big was the thing?
Wellby: Oh, yeah, no, that's too small, never mind.
Unknown: We could make you a-
Delwath: I mean, take a look around. There's like...
Delwath: Can you find a... Is there anything here that would be good for sitting on a throne?
Seeker: We could make you a booster seat so you could s- be a little higher up on the throne.
Seeker: It's too big for you, but we c- you know.
DM: Maybe.
Wellby: A cushion.
Unknown: A cushion. [laughs]
DM: A nice pillow.
DM: A nice pillow. I could take a nice pillow.
Kenzo: Oh, there's a lot of fancy pillows in here.
Unknown: You can find, find a-
Wellby: There's a whole pillow wing.
DM: No, there's no pillows-
Unknown: There's not
DM: ... 'cause they don't go through acid very well.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: There's no cloth, books, except for magic items.
DM: There's nothing that's-
Unknown: Ah.
DM: Everything's metal or stone.
Kenzo: Except for a magic pillow.
Wellby: Stone.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Maybe-
DM: We'll figure it out
Delwath: ... maybe, um, maybe you could ask one of the trees to, to
Delwath: make a little seat for Dimitaur.
Kenzo: Yeah, we can do that. I can carve you a seat.
Kenzo: We can, we can, we can, uh, they can make an elven seat for you.
DM: Oh, yeah. That's good.
Kenzo: Elven wood seat.
DM: I like that.
Delwath: Like a little throne inside a throne.
Kenzo: [laughs] It's like a, it's like a little baby seat.
DM: Yes. Could we get three thrones?
Kenzo: Three?
DM: Well, for the little statuette
Unknown: And what's the third one?
DM: I have a little stone carved wood and stone to sit on the arm of the throne for the statuette that Wellby just told me about to sit next to me.
Delwath: The big throne.
DM: The big throne.
Unknown: Ah, yeah.
Unknown: The little throne.
DM: The little throne.
Delwath: The little, little throne.
DM: The wooden throne.
Kenzo: All right. All right. I mean, is this...
Kenzo: Are we like... Is this like the start of some, like, kind of fascist empire that we're, like, gonna end up, like, you know?
Kenzo: Anyways, okay. Yeah, we can make that happen.
Kenzo: We can do that.
DM: Okay.
DM: That's good.
Delwath: I- is that the treasure you'd like, the, the little statuette?
Unknown: Come see.
DM: Oh, I'm sure I'll get a few other things.
Kenzo: What about Dimitaur, right?
Unknown: Yeah, take whatever you want.
Kenzo: Well, D- you're, you're, you're... I mean, I mean, I think we gotta go do stuff, but we're...
Kenzo: We got a little... I mean, you're, you're gonna help us here, right?
Kenzo: This is, this is... You gotta keep an eye out on this stuff for us.
DM: Oh, yeah. I mean, keep an eye on it?
DM: What's the point? If there's rot and hassle, just, you know, scatter it around, put it back where it belongs.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I mean, take what you want first.
Unknown: All right.
Wellby: We can, we can fill all the remaining volume of the portable hole.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: I, I think we look for diamonds and rubies.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Or anything precious.
Delwath: No, no, no. Diamonds and rubies.
Unknown: Resurrection.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Some rockrum.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Magic items.
DM: And magic items.
Delwath: We'll take the 12 magic items.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: But none of the common ones.
Unknown: I mean, we can take a couple common ones.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: There's gotta be a few, like, fun rings and stuff.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Interesting common ones to be named later.
Delwath: I think we spend, like, a little while.
Delwath: Like, what, what are, what are the...
Delwath: What do Ghesh and what do they want?
DM: I mean, they poke around a bit.
DM: They find some stuff. Milo and Tilly are kind of-
Unknown: They can take something.
Unknown: Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Looking around.
Wellby: Yeah, help yourselves.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs] Help yourselves.
DM: Seriously.
DM: I mean-
Unknown: Can
DM: ... do you want this bow?
Wellby: Maybe. But if I do, I'll give you mine.
DM: It's a deal.
Delwath: Uh, does Tilly want anything? [laughs]
DM: I mean, Tilly wants one of the cool things that's hasn't been made up yet.
Delwath: Yeah, that's fine.
Delwath: They deserve it.
Wellby: We should take, like, some art objects from Hkar also.
Kenzo: Oh, definitely.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Any Hakarian like stuff.
DM: They, they just want some coin.
DM: Th- um, and Milo says, "What we actually want..."
Wellby: Do you want us to review your boat for you again?
DM: I want your boat.
Wellby: The folding boat?
Unknown: Well,
Seeker: I mean, they did s- significantly repair it, didn't they?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I mean...
Wellby: We don't really need a boat.
Wellby: This is like the second time we've ever used it.
Seeker: I think it's a f-
DM: I mean-
Seeker: Considering the service they did, they did for us
Delwath: ... yeah, I think we should be investing in this
Unknown: ... I think it's a fair trade.
Unknown: Fair trade.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: What'd they do for us?
Delwath: Sailed us here.
Wellby: Oh, yeah. No, that's important.
Delwath: And helped us kill the dragon.
Wellby: Also important.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Although
Delwath: they did... I mean, actually Tilly kept Delwath from dying.
Delwath: That was useful.
Unknown: Also important.
Unknown: They helped us.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. It was-
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Kinda helped.
DM: I mean, we gotta sail out of here, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But we were talking, I think we might take some of this coin
DM: heads south.
Unknown: You know what?
Delwath: Take one of the eyes.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: So that way we can-
Delwath: We can see what they see.
DM: How many have we got of them?
Unknown: Two eyes.
Delwath: We got five. Yeah, take an eye and a mouth.
Delwath: I think you should just... I think actually the mouths seem weird.
Delwath: I would just make the-
DM: Yeah, make the eyes
Delwath: ... I mean, if you want, just make 11 items instead of 12.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: But make the eyes be able to just communicate.
Unknown: That's better.
DM: Yeah, the mouths are weird. But yes, they should be able to communicate.
DM: It's a, it's a little bit annoying if they can't.
DM: But just they can... Yeah, they can hear and see.
DM: No, they can speak and see.
DM: While you're looking through the eye, you can speak from the eye.
Kenzo: But so are they like sending stones but you can see?
DM: Um.
Seeker: They're smart sending stones.
DM: They're kind of like smart sending stones.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But they don't... You have to put them in a...
DM: They don't-
Delwath: They're permanent.
DM: They're-
Delwath: You install them
DM: ... you can uninstall them.
Unknown: Right
DM: So you can move them around.
Delwath: Is there like a-
Wellby: Minimum size of thing that can swallow it?
Delwath: No. Is there like a
Delwath: visualizing? Is there another piece that we have to use or-
DM: No, no. You, you use your action.
Delwath: But who uses their action?
DM: Whoever installed it.
Delwath: As only one of us can use it?
DM: Whoever installs it can use their action to see through it.
Wellby: So like you would install it on the boat and potentially s- one of us would.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: And then it would just be there.
DM: I mean, your best bet is to have Seeker use it so that he can teleport to all sorts of strange places.
Seeker: Oh, yeah. Of course.
Unknown: What?
Delwath: 'Cause if he sees it, he can teleport.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Right, to, to weird places.
Unknown: Yeah. Holy fuck.
Unknown: Actually, yeah.
Kenzo: So we can put these eyes all over the place-
Unknown: Put... Actually, like-
Unknown: ... and then see all kinds of weird shit
Unknown: ...
Delwath: I, I don't know if this is worth it, but we could, in theory, use two on Milo's boat.
Delwath: Put one on the prow-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
Delwath: ... and one, like, in his cabin or something like that.
Unknown: Nah, nah, nah, nah, nah.
Unknown: Is that not what we want?
Seeker: We just, we just need the one on the mast or whatever.
Unknown: Yeah, I guess I'll put it on the mast.
Unknown: On the mast. Yeah, yeah. Put it on the prow.
DM: It can see out and it can see him.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Wow. Anything that they see we can teleport to.
Unknown: Yeah. That's-
DM: Well, not with scene one, so there's a chance you fail.
Unknown: Yeah. Right. Okay, fine.
Unknown: But still.
DM: Still.
Seeker: But it's possible.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah, actually this is a good trade.
Delwath: Milo, take the boat, sail to strange places.
Unknown: Maybe we'll drop by sometime.
Unknown: Use the eyes. [laughs]
Kenzo: Yeah. Show, show us... Go, go, go look at as much cool stuff as you can.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Um.
Kenzo: Show the mast of the boat as much cool stuff as you can.
DM: So the only thing, how do you remove them once you install them?
Kenzo: Are you... Is that the DM side?
DM: Milo, Milo's asking Seeker.
DM: I mean, Seek... You can take them out and move them, but then it would be a new person.
DM: Because we're not gonna keep this boat forever.
DM: It's a little small.
Seeker: I see
Wellby: I mean, can you just put it,
Wellby: put it on like a little-
Unknown: No, no, no
Wellby: ... little piece of wood?
Delwath: Isn't the mast that the tree built for you something you wanna take onto a new boat?
DM: Oh, yeah.
DM: We'd definitely keep that.
Unknown: Perfect.
DM: Put it on the mast.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: We made the mast.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Easy enough.
Unknown: Plus, this boat-
DM: That's what I wanted to know. If you take the thing off, does it break?
Kenzo: You can. We're, we're, we're, item-
Seeker: Well, it'll be, it'll become-
DM: No, if you move the item, it's installed to...
DM: No, it won't break.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: But there's a minimum size. You can't just put it in a little stone.
DM: It has to be like a, a wall or a solid stru- I mean, you could put one on Vindristjarna so you could always keep track of what's going on.
Kenzo: Right.
Kenzo: That's great.
Delwath: Also, don't forget the boat does fold up.
Kenzo: There, it's literally a nest camera.
Unknown: So you should bring it with you.
Wellby: It's literally a nest camera.
DM: Yeah, but I think we gotta find an artificer.
DM: I don't think it's gonna fold with this new mast.
Unknown: Ah, yes.
Seeker: Oh, fair point.
Unknown: Well, um...
DM: But that's our quest.
Seeker: So maybe it's an unfolding boat now, yeah.
DM: No, no, it's gonna be...
Unknown: Oh.
DM: They're gonna sail off. They're like...
DM: They probably level up.
DM: They just killed a, kill a dragon.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: They'll sail off. They'll find somebody who can fix the boat, and you'll, you'll have a little eye on the mast-
DM: Perfect
DM: ... of the halfling ship exploring the Southern Ocean.
Wellby: Oh my gosh.
Wellby: Pretty cool.
DM: So the dragonets are eager to
DM: decorate their homes and return all the treasure that they found on Hkar and gave to...
Unknown: Right
DM: ... found on the Circular Island and gave to Ra'ghemdros.
Delwath: So I think we take like an hour or two and, like...
Delwath: I mean, this is pretty well organized, right?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, we don't even have... We don't have to put stuff in the portal hole.
Delwath: Like, take a backpack and fill it with gems.
DM: That's... There's not a ton of gems.
DM: It's mostly jewelry, coin-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... and coins.
DM: Um.
Wellby: But we should take as much value in coins as we can because, like the-
Unknown: It's just always useful
Wellby: ... outfitting costs-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Wellby: ... that we got quoted for, like, building up the ship are insane.
Kenzo: I mean, this was everything but.
DM: No.
Wellby: It's-
Kenzo: Just like airship owning, you know what I mean?
Unknown: It's just like-
DM: It's like maintenance costs
Kenzo: ... the insurance.
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: You know, all of it. It's just-
Wellby: It's a money pit.
Kenzo: I mean, it's just, you know, once you start going in there, you know.
DM: We should take, take what we can in coin.
Kenzo: Every contractor, and they're like double, triple quoting us.
Unknown: I mean, it's a-
Wellby: 'Cause they see how nice your airship is.
Kenzo: It's just, I mean, it just...
Kenzo: The whole thing is just a racket.
DM: [coughs] I mean, you can take a fair bit of coin.
DM: The more... You know, it's just a trade-off between fancy art.
DM: Like, take all the, like, selected items from the collection-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... that are, like, the ancient Dracorian artifacts.
Delwath: I just wanna look around for, like, ge- diamonds and rubies.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Well, I mean, so diamonds and rubies were precious for magic back in the Dracorian days too.
Unknown: Right.
DM: So they're not typically used in common jewelry.
DM: There's some. Not gonna be a huge amount.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Um.
Delwath: I mean, a- anything that looks super old that...
Unknown: I mean, that-
DM: Well, she curated the oldest stuff.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Your sense is that everything in that
DM: room was, like, carefully curated either 'cause it was connected to the Dracorian imperial line or 'cause it predated Dracoria.
Delwath: So who-
Seeker: But, but nothing relating to Shammut?
DM: No.
Unknown: Huh.
Unknown: Where's Shammut's stuff?
DM: I mean, Shammut probably kept his own stuff.
DM: She hasn't left the island the way-
Kenzo: Where's, where... But where is Shammut's stuff?
Wellby: Somewhere out there in the world, right?
Delwath: Shammut's hoard.
Kenzo: Ooh, that's another good side quest.
DM: Well, it's probably in Limbo.
Kenzo: That's a great side quest, though.
DM: It's probably on another plane.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Could go to Limbo once you get Vindrist...
DM: That's a good 20-level one shot.
Kenzo: Ooh, that's a great, that's a great-
Unknown: Ah, yeah
Kenzo: ... that's a great one shot. Go find Shammut's hoard.
Wellby: I wonder if there are other-
DM: I mean, it's definitely not on this plane.
DM: Shammut's hoard is for sure not somewhere on Tal'dorei.
Seeker: Are there any other siblings?
DM: There could be.
Seeker: Right. Was this an only child?
Kenzo: Wait, so who's the... If Shammut's the...
Kenzo: Is there a mom? It's like who the hell are the fucking dragons?
Kenzo: Do we need to figure that out?
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: You, you have the impression that they, that they reproduce magically.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Like, they turn a stone into an egg or something like that by magic.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: Right? 'Cause there were seven dragons that were born from the-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
DM: ... dead body of Shammut by some weird magical process.
Unknown: Right.
DM: And Grimmuskull was one of them.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: So over the next couple of hours, you sort out the, like, most valuable stuff.
DM: You manage to get, like, a, a small collection of rubies and diamonds.
DM: Um, you know, enough for at least a few castings of Smackum.
DM: Um,
DM: take what seems the most valuable of the art objects and then just, like, pour coins until it fills the space.
Delwath: Once we, um, once we free...
Delwath: Once we liberate Chardin, we should have, like, a big auction in Chardin of all of our...
Delwath: 'Cause coin is a lot more useful than all this jewelry.
Kenzo: Anyway.
DM: Um, and then close up the portable hole.
DM: Say goodbye to Dimitar.
DM: Install an eye on his throne.
DM: Like, where do you want to put the eye?
Kenzo: Uh, where does he think is gonna be the most, uh...
Unknown: Like, where's he, where does he hang out?
Delwath: Where is he putting the throne?
Wellby: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: How's he getting the throne out?
Wellby: We'll, we'll animal shape and put the throne somewhere for him.
Delwath: He does have an 8th-level spell.
DM: Well, he's got, he's got-
Unknown: That's true
DM: ... 400 dragonets with ropes.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: Yeah. He can solve this problem.
Unknown: It's like, look.
Kenzo: Well, where are you, where are you putting the throne, Barry?
DM: I'm not sure yet.
DM: I'm kind of curious if this heals.
Kenzo: What heals?
DM: He points to the, like, spongy acid moss.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Seeker: Oh, yeah. Probably.
DM: 'Cause, like, the villa's got a pretty nice view.
Kenzo: Stay right in this area. Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, we could just put the eye at the, like, top of the throne.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Right?
Wellby: That's a good idea.
Seeker: Dim- Dimitar has a tough task.
Seeker: They've just had such a massive influx of treasure.
Seeker: It's, like, unprecedented.
Unknown: Everything's changed.
DM: But there's nothing for the-
Seeker: Shiny infla- shininess inflation.
DM: Well, yeah, but also-
Seeker: So he needs to reinvent the entire-
Wellby: You can't buy anything with it
Seeker: ... dragonet economy because they've nothing to do
DM: ... but there is no economy because you just go fly to an arcane circle anytime you need food or water.
Seeker: So what he... So basically he has to provide entertainment
DM: It's enter- entertainment and real estate, but there's only 500 of them.
DM: There's plenty of real estate and not-
Unknown: Hmm. We've also opened up-
Wellby: Dimitaur's cornered the market on entertainment
Seeker: ... we've also opened up the Half Island by-
Delwath: Now that all got plugged because of, because the plague
Seeker: ... the west side.
DM: Somebody, one day somebody might come back and clear the plague cursed areas.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: The next time we come back there's gonna be like 30,000 dragonets.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: And there's gonna be like elaborate like fucking-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... crazy games and shit.
Unknown: Bubble condos everywhere.
Unknown: Yeah, like just-
Unknown: Space age cities
Unknown: ... yeah, just...
DM: Maybe they'll figure out how to get the island to move again.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: What's Dimitaur's [laughs] vision for his...
Kenzo: He's, he's the last dwarven empire.
DM: Well, he has... I mean, he probably doesn't have that much longer to live.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: He's like super old.
Seeker: So he'll find a successor.
DM: He's like, "Yeah, I gotta see who's the
DM: most interesting or..."
Kenzo: Okay. Before, before we go also, Kenzo gives Gresh a look like,
Unknown: like
Unknown: you, you-
DM: Come back and visit.
Kenzo: Yeah, but just you... It's like...
Seeker: We'll keep an eye on you.
Kenzo: Yeah, but just he's... You know.
Kenzo: Remember that first dice game. Let, let you have those couple but, you know, worked out in the end for you.
DM: Oh, I won fair and square.
Kenzo: You did. You did, but it worked out well for you in the end, right?
DM: Oh, no question.
Kenzo: You chose the right team, right? There you go.
Unknown: There you go.
DM: So you sail back through the storm.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: Why don't we just... I thought we were just gonna Rainbow Bridge.
Wellby: Sail the Rainbow Bridge?
Delwath: Uh, I guess we should save it.
DM: I mean, Milo and Tilly have to sail through the storm one way or the other.
Delwath: That's true. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Seeker: So they can give us a ride in their boat.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah. You're right.
DM: Um, the boat now equipped with a magic elven,
DM: uh, mast, handles much better and you manage to make it through without too much damage
DM: and see Vindristjarna.
Seeker: Ah. Finally.
Kenzo: Nice to be back.
Unknown: So good to be home.
DM: Return
DM: to, I think, I need to check with Kate, Rizwin and the oppressive eye of Apollyon watching your every move.
Unknown: What?
Seeker: How do we know that's happening?
DM: 'Cause of just meta game.
Unknown: Ah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Kate's on Vindristjarna right now?
DM: Rizw- I, I'm pretty sure Rizwin was planning on coming back for the last
DM: fight against Apollyon.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: 'Cause she's off dealing with the like Rizwin doppelganger.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: Yeah. So Apollyon is going to be watching our every move.
Delwath: That's fun.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Yeah. So what? What the fuck is he doing?
Kenzo: It's like I just... I'm not that scared of Apollyon.
Delwath: He's just like whatever.
Delwath: [laughs] I mean, guess our private sanctum comes in handy.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: But we can only use it once, right?
Unknown: We have a scroll of private sanctum.
DM: Yeah, a scroll of private sanctum.
Delwath: How does that, that, uh... Does that...